<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

    <channel>
        <title></title>
        <link></link>
        <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 11:12:33 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        
        <item>
            <title>A tool for thinking</title>
            <link>
                /2021/thinking
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Yesterday as I was sat on my sofa watching the Sunday morning church service on YouTube I had my MacBook Pro open on my lap to make notes in Obsidian. After the service had finished I spent a few minutes to tidy up some formatting and make sure the correct bible verses were being referenced, I realised how much I am enjoying using the app. It got me thinking about why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/thinking
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Yom HaShoah</title>
            <link>
                /2021/yom-hashoah
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Today is Yom HaShoah, or Holocaust Remembrance Day, in Israel. Racism has been in the news a lot of the last year or so, and yet we hear very little of the fact that anti-semitism is on the rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have visited Israel twice. It’s a place that quickly won my heart with it’s beauty and history. Last time I was there was in 2014 and I was able to visit &lt;a href=&quot...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/yom-hashoah
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The notes app quest continues</title>
            <link>
                /2021/notes-app-quest
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve been continuing to seek out a notes app that works for me as well as I would like it too. A couple of weeks ago I posted about &lt;a href=&quot;https://philbowell.com/2021/searching-for-the-perfect-notes-app/&quot;&gt;what I’m looking for&lt;/a&gt; and since then I’ve been giving a couple of the contenders a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I wrote that post I had been using Craft fo...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/notes-app-quest
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Write sentences, what I’m thinking, because I want too</title>
            <link>
                /2021/write-sentences
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Tonight I came across two blog posts in Reeder as I was lying in bed catching up on my feeds and watching the Formula One. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://audacious.blog/2021/write/&quot;&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; was all about writing. The author coined a phrase that is very reminiscent of Michael Pollan’s approach to food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Write sentences, not too many, ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/write-sentences
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Searching for the perfect notes app</title>
            <link>
                /2021/searching-for-notes-app
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;For the last 6 months or so I have been using Roam Research as my notes app. The daily note turned into my home from home allowing me to capture things throughout the day. Thoughts, feelings, meeting notes, tasks, articles I read, videos I watched, everything got noted down in the daily note. Using the service has encouraged me to read more wisely, making notes from articles that are u...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/searching-for-notes-app
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Tweaking my morning routine</title>
            <link>
                /2021/Tweaking-my-morning-routine
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;There’s nothing quite like writing down the routine you’ve found yourself falling into to make you realise there’s somethings you’d like to change. When I &lt;a href=&quot;https://philbowell.com/2021/routines/&quot; title=&quot;Routines&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about my routine the other week it made me more conscious of what I’ve been doing in the morning so I started to pay more att...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/Tweaking-my-morning-routine
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Routines</title>
            <link>
                /2021/routines
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;On my lunch break today as I sat reading some RSS feeds, I came across a [Daily Blogging Challenge] that started on the first of March. As I clicked through to the organising site to find out more I discovered that each day they are sharing a prompt word that everyone taking part should use to kickstart their post for the day. I’m not going to commit to taking part everyday, but I like...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/routines
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Micro blogging again</title>
            <link>
                /2021/micro-blogging-again
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve recently made some changes to the hosting for my blog and other websites as part of the consolidation of my many websites in to one. I had been aiming to have one website to rule them all integrating my portfolio and my blog into one site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m in the process of creating a new theme to help accomplish that, but I realised that for a long time I’ve not wanted to ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/micro-blogging-again
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Lockdown 3</title>
            <link>
                /2021/lockdown-3
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;We have been in Lockdown 3 for a few weeks now as Covid-19 continues to spread through the population. The government issued stay at home notices again, but this time people don’t seem to be following things quite as closely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s both frustrating and annoying seeing so many people still meeting up with friends, even travelling across cities to meet in the park for ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/lockdown-3
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My book of the year 2020</title>
            <link>
                /2020/book-of-the-year
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve always enjoyed reading and for as long as I can remember I’ve read fiction. Several years ago I got surprised with a Kindle for Christmas from my parents. It caused me to increase dramatically the number of books I was reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year is a different story. Reading has been a difficult task something that is very unusual. Reading has always been a point of co...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/book-of-the-year
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Domain conundrums</title>
            <link>
                /2020/domain-conundrum
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve amassed a number of domains for various websites I’ve wanted to create. A few of those are related to my former freelance business, and two relates to blogs. This week I got a notification that 3 of them are up for renewal in January, it’s left me questioning if should renew them all or if it’s time to let some go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the domain for this blog...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/domain-conundrum
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Grey day</title>
            <link>
                /2020/grey-day
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Today has been a grey and foggy day, it’s felt like a real reflection of the mood of the last month. As I’ve driven around Cheltenham today doing some bits and bobs, I’ve seen more and more people starting to put up Christmas trees and lights. It’s been nice to see them emerging out of the gloom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today marks the start of Advent, with the first candle being lit in ch...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/grey-day
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thanksgiving</title>
            <link>
                /2020/thanksgiving
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Today is Thanksgiving in America, and despite being a Brit I thought it would be good to try and post something I’m thankful for this year. I started to write this post at lunchtime, and struggled, I couldn’t zero in on something. This evening after my counselling session I realised what it is I’m thankful for this year. I’m thankful for all the people who have helped my family navigat...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/thanksgiving
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Roaming around</title>
            <link>
                /2020/roaming-around
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Since the end of August I’ve been using Roam Research as my notes application. Having tried and played around with Notion but finding it to be too much work to manage anything, I decided to give Roam and it’s freeform notes a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found it to be one of the most intuitive note taking apps I’ve ever come across and have since begun using it for more and more thin...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/roaming-around
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>An acknowledgement</title>
            <link>
                /2020/an-acknowledgement
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve had this blog in one form or another since I was 21, earlier posts have been lost in the many transitions it has made but it’s always been there. A hobby that taught me how to design and build websites that has since become my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment I think I am in one of the longest streaks of not posting to the site that I’ve ever been on. For the last few wee...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/an-acknowledgement
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Two States of Perfection</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Two-States-of-Perfection
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember I’ve had a sketchbook on the go. I think I established the habit when I started senior school, but I remember having them back in junior school as well. They’ve been a companion beside me all that time, whether I’ve been drawing, writing, brainstorming, planning, or something else, they’ve helped me to be creative in some form or another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Two-States-of-Perfection
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Blogging Habit</title>
            <link>
                /2018/The-Blogging-Habit
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;When I first started writing a blog I was 20. It was my first year of university, and I’d somehow stumbled across a couple of random blogs, I’m not entirely sure how, but I know one thing. As soon as I saw them, I wanted one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dabbled with a free blogger account, and then in my second year at university I bought my first domain and installed WordPress. That was the...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/The-Blogging-Habit
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Bulletin Board</title>
            <link>
                /2018/The-Bulletin-Board
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve been reading Austin Kleon’s blog since January, I find the way that he speaks about his notebooks and how he uses them very inspiring. Today’s post is about his &lt;a href=&quot;https://austinkleon.com/2018/05/01/the-bulletin-board/&quot;&gt;bulletin board&lt;/a&gt; and how he pins images, clippings, index cards, and various other bits to it for inspiration while he is writing a b...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/The-Bulletin-Board
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Establishing New Habits Without Apps</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Establishing-Habits-Without-Apps
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to establish some new habits lately so &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjchilvers.com/blog/establishing-new-habits-without-apps&quot;&gt;this was a timely post&lt;/a&gt; from CJ Chilvers. I’ve been using the app Streaks like he mentions to keep focused on some of my habits, but there is a certain lack of accountability that goes with it. When a big streak gets broken it’s...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Establishing-Habits-Without-Apps
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My Secret Battle – a Grief Shared</title>
            <link>
                /2018/My-Secret-Battle-a-Grief-Shared
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;This week I can across the blog is Simon Thomas. He’s a Sky Sports presenter and a Christian, known by many in the U.K. He lost his wife to cancer in September last year and has been blogging about his grief. This week he shared a post about &lt;a href=&quot;https://agriefshared.com/2018/02/09/my-secret-battle/&quot;&gt;his Secret Battle&lt;/a&gt; with depression and anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/My-Secret-Battle-a-Grief-Shared
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Quantity not quality</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Quantity-not-quality
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;There’s an odd pressure when you’re trying to exercise the muscle of discipline, it’s tempting to want everything you do as a part of that to be the best that it can be. Sometimes you need to just push through and exercise that muscle. When you’re starting out, quantity is often more important than quality. You need to get used to doing something regularly before you can focus on doing...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Quantity-not-quality
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Book Budget</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Book-Budget
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I just added a new category in my YNAB Budget under Quality of Life Goals, it’s name? Books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I started using Goodreads in 2013 I’ve read 104 books. That’s an average of just under 21 books a year with a low of 17 in 2013 and a high of 34 books in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly I like to read, so it made sense to actually budget for these books financially s...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Book-Budget
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Write More</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Write-More
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Cameron Moll &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cameronmoll/status/958849192113225728&quot;&gt;posted a thread on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; urging  people to write. Here &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cameronmoll/status/958849192113225728&quot;&gt;are&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cameronmoll/status/958849193224781825&quot;&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twi...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Write-More
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thoughts On Just Turning Up</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Thoughts-Turning-Up
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a little more about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://philbowell.com/2018/thoughts-as-nest-eggs&quot;&gt;link I posted&lt;/a&gt; to Austin Kleon’s blog the other day. I finished it with the line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Instead there should just be turning up to write down a thought and seeing where it takes you.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It’s a sentiment that ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Thoughts-Turning-Up
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thoughts as Nest Eggs</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Thoughts-as-Nest-Eggs
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today when you say “nest egg” many think of money saved and put away, but a literal “nest egg” is a real or fake egg that you put in a nest to encourage a bird or a hen to lay more eggs there. So what Thoreau is saying is that by simply writing down a thought, you encourage more thoughts to come. When you have enough thoughts pushed together in the same space — a c...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Thoughts-as-Nest-Eggs
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A Home Screen Update</title>
            <link>
                /2017/A-Homescreen-Update
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I used to post a monthly series that looked at the Home Screens of my iPhone and iPad. Over time though I realised it didn’t change as much as I expected and so I lost interest in the process. Things have changed a lot recently so I thought it was time to post another look at my iPhone.
A few of weeks ago I put in to the practise the ideas in a post I &lt;a href=&quot;http://philbowell...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/A-Homescreen-Update
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A mid-year review</title>
            <link>
                /2017/A-mid-year-review
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Last week I was away at the CMJ Conference, I had the pleasure of joining them to take photos of the event, post to social media throughout it on their accounts, and to hear some excellent bible teaching in the process. It lasted from Friday afternoon to late Sunday afternoon, and by the time I got home I was absolutely exhausted. I spent most of the week recovering whilst trying to wo...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/A-mid-year-review
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Workloads and Creativity</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Workloads-and-Creativity
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed over the last few weeks a distinct correlation between my ability to spend time on side projects and the amount of design work I have going on. Juggling a part time job in the Coffee House alongside running my design business makes for a distinct lack of energy to keep my side/personal projects going when things get busy. I find my motivation drops as my energy gets used u...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Workloads-and-Creativity
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Haptic Architects Teach the Benefits of the Scandinavian Work Life Balance</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Scandinavian-Work-Life-Blance
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Work/Life balance is a thing many of us struggle with. I know when I was 100% self-employed it was the thing I struggled with most, there was always something I felt I should be doing. Whilst many people claim that doing what you love means you have a perfect work/life balance that seems far to idealistic to me. Work is work, whether we love what we do or not and we need a good balance...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Scandinavian-Work-Life-Blance
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Walking</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Walking
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Back in January 2015 when I realised I was ill, and consequently started a course of antidepressants, many people encouraged me to exercise. I had been a keen cyclist and they encouraged me to keep at it and get out on my bike as much as I could. I was told, and in fact read many times, that exercise was a great way of countering some of the symptoms of depression. My issue was that th...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Walking
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Employment vs. Self-Employment</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Employment-vs-Self-Employment
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Occasionally I’ll come across an article on the internet that I find myself reading more than once. Usually it’s because the piece resonates deeply with me, but sometimes it’s because it’s something I want to be able to write myself. In this instance it’s just that, a piece I would like to be able to write in a years time, but with my own perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a piece abo...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Employment-vs-Self-Employment
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Seth Godin Blog Daily</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Seth-Godin-Blog-Daily
            </link>
            <description>
                
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;title: Seth Godin Explains Why You Should Blog Daily
—
With the arrival of Micro.blog my interest in my blog has picked up considerably. It’s always been there bubbling at the back of my mind, but actively posting micro posts to it has me once again looking to post other content more regularly. CJ Chilvers linked to an article by Seth Godin that &lt;a href=&quot;https://w...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Seth-Godin-Blog-Daily
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Deep Prayer &gt; Deep Work</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Deep-Prayer-Deep-Work
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of talk on the internet circles I follow about focus and deep work. They’re thought provoking and often resonate with me, but there’s one thing I’ve been struggling to reconcile in it all. The focus of all these discussions is usually aimed at putting your individual desires first, which doesn’t really jive with my Christian beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris Bowler,...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Deep-Prayer-Deep-Work
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Dedication Olympics</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Dedication-Olympics
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;As I sit writing this the BBC are showing their roundup video of the Rio Olympics. Normally when it comes to the Olympics I’m pretty glued to it for the few weeks that it runs. This year, maybe due to the time difference, it took a week or so for me to get in to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only when the track cycling came on and Team GB started to win medals that I started to watch....
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Dedication-Olympics
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Finding Your Bliss Station</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Finding-Your-Bliss-Station
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;There’s so much stuff on the internet that it seems like an impossibility that you would read something at exactly the time you need to read it. Austin Kleon’s recent article about &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@austinkleon/finding-your-bliss-station-436290c4da03&quot;&gt;finding your bliss station&lt;/a&gt; has managed to achieve just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around a year ago ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Finding-Your-Bliss-Station
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Depression Days</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Depression-Days
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Sometimes a day hits you when things that are normally easy to do become the hardest things. I mean simple things like getting out of bed, going downstairs and making a coffee. That’s the nature of depression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it happens you have to find ways of getting through because giving in to it can be crippling. Giving in can be the start of a downward spiral, a spiral y...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Depression-Days
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Desire to Tinker</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Tinker
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;The desire to tinker is strong in this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have this problem when it comes to my blog. The more I start to post to it, the more I want to tinker. The more active I am on the site, the more I notice little things I don’t like and want to fix. The more I post to it, the more I want all my internet posting to originate on it. It’s like an illness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&g...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Tinker
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My Blogroll in 2016</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Blogroll
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Back when I first started writing on the internet – ok it’s called blogging, ugh – I discovered a lot of blogs through the sidebars of those I was reading. The trend at the time, way back in 2006, was for each blog to feature a Blogroll. A collection of links to the blogs of other people that the author of each site either knew personally or who simply enjoyed those other sites. It was...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Blogroll
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Permission</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Permission
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;At the start of last week I set myself the challenge to blog everyday between then and the end of the year. Yesterday I didn’t manage to post to this site, in some people’s eyes I’ve failed the challenge already. Maybe I have, but it’s not going to stop me carrying on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These types of challenges are great to do, they add an extra bit of impetus to get going on someth...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Permission
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Kill Your To Do List</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Kill-Your-To-do-List
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Here’s what’s always bothered me about task management systems: it’s not what Presidents use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never thought of &lt;a href=&quot;http://cjchilvers.com/blog/kill-your-to-do-list&quot; title=&quot;Kill Your To Do List&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; before. It’s never even crossed my mind about the methods of working for people in ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Kill-Your-To-do-List
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>You’re Not Meant To Do What You Love. You’re Meant To Do What You’re Good At.</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Do-What-Youre-Good-At
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do what you love&lt;/em&gt; has been a bit of a mantra of late on the internet, at least on the blogs I seem to have been reading over the last couple of years. It’s something that I love the sentiment of, but at the same time something that has never quite sat properly with me. So when I saw the phrase &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/personal-growth/youre-not-meant-to-do...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Do-What-Youre-Good-At
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>What Do You Write About?</title>
            <link>
                /2016/What-Do-You-Write-About
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I know what you’re thinking. It’s only the second day of the challenge I set myself, to post to my blog everyday from now until the end of the year, and already I’m asking the question of what do I write about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would imagine it’s a familiar story to anyone who’s decided to undertake such a challenge. Going from barely writing or posting to your blog to posting eve...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/What-Do-You-Write-About
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The 2016 Blogging Challenge</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Blogging-Challenge
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve written 442 posts on this site. The first one was written on 17th January 2011, that’s five and half years ago. It equates to around 80 posts per year and about 1.5 posts per week. It’s not bad going, but it could be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During those times there’s been many spells of inactivity and many spells of multiple posts per day, this is what I would like to change m...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Blogging-Challenge
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>One Twelfth</title>
            <link>
                /2016/One-Twelfth
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;We’ve done it. All of us. Good job everyone. We’ve made it through January and we’re into February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always find January a bit of an odd month, it’s full of the initial hopes and dreams of the year ahead, yet it’s a hard slog. We spend the first week getting back into the swing of things, the second week doing our utmost to get new patterns of behaviour, thinking a...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/One-Twelfth
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Holocaust Rememberence Day</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Holocaust-Rememberence-Day
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Today marks the 71st anniversary of the liberation of Auschwitz-Birkenau, a place which is known world wide for the atrocities that our Jewish brothers and sisters faced during the Second World War. Atrocities that I didn’t know the depth of fully until I visited Yad Vashem in Jerusalem on my first visit to Israel a few years ago. Reading through the account of the holocaust in that pl...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Holocaust-Rememberence-Day
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Just Hit Command-N</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Just-Hit-Command-N
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Just hit Command-N. Those are the words I just read in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.manton.org/2016/01/tim-cook-swift-and-the-return-of-blogs.html&quot; title=&quot;Tim Coo, Swift and the Return of Blogs&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; from Manton Reece, and so that’s what I’m doing. I may not be a developer or someone who’s had much of an audience in my life on the Internet. However, for the...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Just-Hit-Command-N
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Let me make a note of that</title>
            <link>
                /2015/Let-me-make-a-note-of-that
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Ever since I got my first iOS device, a 2nd generation iPod Touch, I’ve been on a quest to work out the best way to take notes. I’ve tried a shed load of different apps, Simplenote, Evernote, Notesy, the built in notes app, NVAlt… in fact if you can name it I’ve probably tried it. I’ve always read with interest articles on note taking setups, how people use them, how their go to app on...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2015/Let-me-make-a-note-of-that
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Archives</title>
            <link>
                /2015/Archives
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Back in October of 2014 I wiped this blog and started all over again in an attempt at a fresh start and the beginning of more regular posting. The lack of baggage was supposed to be the catalyst to help me post, to a degree it has worked and I’ve been posting here much more regularly since the turn of the year. The Week in Links has helped, and is approaching it’s six month anniversary...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2015/Archives
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Be Yourself</title>
            <link>
                /2015/Be-Yourself
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I can’’‘t remember how I came across the article &lt;a href=&quot;http://ift.tt/1E152hD&quot;&gt;Be Yourself&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Nahumck but I instanty saved it. I’’‘ve read twice since then. It resonated with me, in fact the tweets by Aaron Mahnke which triggered this article resonated with me. But most of all, this quote is what I connected with the most. Never have I been more aware of...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2015/Be-Yourself
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Bored</title>
            <link>
                /2015/Bored
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I wonder how often the phrase &lt;em&gt;I’m bored…&lt;/em&gt; came out of your mouth as a child? I know it crossed my lips a fair few times, during my years at primary school. As I grew older the phrase appeared less and less, in fact I can’t remember the last time that phrase crossed my lips and I don’t recall it ever crossing them in my years since university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tha...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2015/Bored
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Building</title>
            <link>
                /2015/Building
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’m great at making statements and promises about things that I want to do. It’s easy. I think of something I wish to do, decide there and then a means by which to do it, then post to my blog declaring it in the public domain.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
In principle it’s a good tactic. The public declaration should be enough of a motivation to make sure I stick to something, but the reality is ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2015/Building
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Barriers</title>
            <link>
                /2015/Barriers
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Barriers are a strange thing. In the real world they exist to form a separation, a physical division between two things. They can be permanent or temporary, but they exist for a specific reason. Their purpose though, is always the same, to prevent you from going somewhere you shouldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mental world things are slightly different. Barriers exist of course, but...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2015/Barriers
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Rediscovering the Personal Site</title>
            <link>
                /2015/Rediscovering-the-Personal-Site
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;It’s been an interesting start to the year to say the least, but one positive from it has been the renewal of my interest in both my own blog and the blogs of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been reading blogs, or personal sites would probably be a more accurate term in 2015, since I came across them in my second year at university in 2006. Back then I loved the idea of people publish...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2015/Rediscovering-the-Personal-Site
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thirty Things I've Learned in Thirty Years</title>
            <link>
                /2014/Thirty-Things-I've-learned-in-thirty-years
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;When the year turned 2014 I began to reflect on my life, who I am, where I am and what I’m doing. Why should a simple year change cause such a mood to dawn on me? At the end of September I turned 30, it also happened to mark the 10 year anniversary since I left home and moved to university here in Cheltenham. These are two significant events in my life that mark the beginning and end o...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2014/Thirty-Things-I've-learned-in-thirty-years
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Fresh Start</title>
            <link>
                /2014/Fresh-Start
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;It dawned on me today that I’ve been writing a blog, in one form or another, for the last 8 years. Initially, I was full of the youthful enthusiasm of someone who had just discovered the medium, I could easily sit down at my Mac and within half an hour have published a new post. Within a few months I had found a number of other bloggers who wrote with a little more quality than I did a...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2014/Fresh-Start
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Resolutions and Intentions</title>
            <link>
                /2013/Resolutions-and-Intentions
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;At the start of every year, I, along with millions of others around the world, make resolutions. We decide, often quite flippantly, to do certain things. It could be to change a habit, lose weight, or to get fitter and just “be healthier”. But 99% of the time they are lofty goals that last only a couple of weeks, a month or maybe six weeks if you really try hard, but they rarely last.&...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2013/Resolutions-and-Intentions
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Do you like to shave?</title>
            <link>
                /2012/Do-you-like-to-shave
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I like to shave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask most men my age, their late twenties, that question and its usually met with a snort. An upturned lip. A look that says “are you serious?” without words passing their lips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact if you asked me that question a few years ago I would’ve responded in much the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what changed I hear you say? My ap...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2012/Do-you-like-to-shave
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The One Where I Announce I'm Now Self Employed</title>
            <link>
                /2012/The-One-Where-I-Announce-I'm-Now-Self-Employed
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;There are some posts you dream about writing, posts you’d love to write but never think you actually will. This is one of those posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I wrote a post about change. Changing the way I approached something has lead to exciting guidance and a big change in my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started with a conversation with two very good friends of mine. ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2012/The-One-Where-I-Announce-I'm-Now-Self-Employed
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Change</title>
            <link>
                /2012/Change
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;For the last few years I’ve been praying about something. I’m sure many of you have as well, but this particular &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; has occupied my prayers for several years. I’ve been praying about it in the same way for pretty much the entire time, asking for guidance and direction in relation to the &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt;. During that time the urge to do that &lt;em&gt;t...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2012/Change
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>I Miss My Cave</title>
            <link>
                /2012/I-Miss-My-Cave
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;man cave&lt;/em&gt; 
  noun Informal .
  a room or other area in a home that is primarily a male sanctuary, designed and furnished to accommodate the man&#39;s recreational activities, hobbies, etc.
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/browse/man+cave&quot;&gt;Dictionery.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my latter years at school whi...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2012/I-Miss-My-Cave
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Reading Stories, Food for the Imagination</title>
            <link>
                /2012/Reading-Stories-Food-for-the-Imagination
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I work as a graphic designer. Like many other folks in my profession I find it hard to turn off. I may not be thinking about projects from work all the time, but I’m always thinking about projects I’d like to do or reviewing the things I see all around me. I see every piece of design and mentally critic it, 99% of the time I’m not even aware I’m doing it, but it’s there, almost like a ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2012/Reading-Stories-Food-for-the-Imagination
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Wecloming 2012 and Setting a Few Targets</title>
            <link>
                /2012/Wecloming-2012-and-Setting-a-Few-Targets
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;It’s that time once again when many people are posting reviews of the year just passed. I always enjoy reading these posts, seeing the people I follow who have achieved all that or more than they hoped to whilst hoping those who didn’t are able to in the coming year. I’m always drawn to writing something myself, and whilst my last year contains many highlights – my trip to Israel, a su...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2012/Wecloming-2012-and-Setting-a-Few-Targets
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>In Search Of Flow</title>
            <link>
                /2011/In-Search-Of-Flow
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Like most of the world, the arrival of an iPad in my life has meant a lot of my established routines and behaviours have changed. I’m no longer setting up camp on my sofa with my MacBook Pro to spend some time reading RSS feeds and going where the links take me, instead this time is being spent using my iPad. I find I’m using my MacBook Pro a lot less than I used too, that’s not necess...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2011/In-Search-Of-Flow
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My First Conference (Part Two)</title>
            <link>
                /2011/My-First-Conference-(Part-Two)
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to work a seemingly random collection of thoughts into a follow up post about New Adventures conference. It’s not really happened so I’ve chosen to just throw them out there to anyone who is interested.
Overall I enjoyed the day, it was fun, informative and pushed me out of my comfort zone, teaching me things about design and myself that are valuable and I am processin...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2011/My-First-Conference-(Part-Two)
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My First Conference (Part One)</title>
            <link>
                /2011/My-First-Conference-(Part-One)
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;This week I’m heading to my first design conference in the form of &lt;a href=&quot;http://newadventuresconf.com/&quot;&gt;New Adventures&lt;/a&gt; in my home town ((Well 25 minutes outside of the city is technically my home town, but I was born in Nottingham so close enough.)). In the past I’ve always looked in on conferences from the outside, so when I heard about &lt;a href=&quot;ht...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2011/My-First-Conference-(Part-One)
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Leaving Tumblr</title>
            <link>
                /2011/Leaving-Tumblr
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;It’s been just under a year since I began trialling &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; as the basis of my blog. At the time I was writing from &lt;a href=&quot;http://phil.electricweekend.com/&quot;&gt;Electric Weekend&lt;/a&gt; but had been struggling thanks to several events that happened at the end of 2009. In an attempt to get back in to the swing of ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2011/Leaving-Tumblr
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Introducing PBcom</title>
            <link>
                /2010/Introducing-PBcom
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;The last few months have been very quiet here at Electric Weekend, there’s been lots going on behind the scenes which have made it hard to write here. I covered some of those in the last post, but now I’m beginning to feel the desire to write again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I also feel as a person I’ve begun to out grow Electric Weekend, particularly as I look to present mysel...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2010/Introducing-PBcom
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Summer 2009</title>
            <link>
                /2009/Summer-2009
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Well, it’s been a while. In fact it’s been the longest gap between posts there’s ever been on Electric Weekend. I’m not going to apologise, the simple fact is that in the last 2/3 months a lot of stuff has happened, a mixture of ends of chapters, beginnings of new ones and a good bye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest end to a chapter has meant I’m now living in a flat on my tod instead ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2009/Summer-2009
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Experiencing A Fever</title>
            <link>
                /2009/Experiencing-A-Fever
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve done something tonight I’ve not done for a a while. I’ve sat at my desk with a glass of wine and read. I’ve read feeds. Some of which contained posts that stretched back a few weeks, others posts written today and I’ve come out the other side feeling like I’ve enjoyed a relaxed evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world where we get busier and busier, where more and more things are g...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2009/Experiencing-A-Fever
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Motivation</title>
            <link>
                /2009/Motivation
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;These days, I’m sure like many, my primary source of reading material is via the internet, or more specifically my feed reader. There’s a lot of great content out on the web and filtering out the cruft to get to it can be a bit of a mission. We are bombarded with information clamouring for our attention the moment we open our web browser, so finding a way of weeding out the crap to rev...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2009/Motivation
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Talent Crutch</title>
            <link>
                /2009/The-Talent-Crutch
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Micaheal Mistretta has been at it again. Another excellent post this time about &lt;a href=&quot;http://michaelmistretta.com/2009/the-myth-of-talent/&quot;&gt;The Myth of Talent&lt;/a&gt; which brought to mind a lesson I learned back when I was 16 doing my GCSE’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a talent, you have a talent, everyone has a talent. A lot of people don’t believe they have one,...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2009/The-Talent-Crutch
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Two Mac Nightmare - Email & Contacts</title>
            <link>
                /2009/Two-Mac-Nightmare-Email-Contacts
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;If you’ve only just found this series of posts exploring how I keep my two Macs in sync you might want to look at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://phil.electricweekend.com/2008/12/mac-sync-series/&quot;&gt;introduction&lt;/a&gt; of the series to help set the scene. In this post I want to explore the issue of keeping emails and contacts in sync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m sure the majority ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2009/Two-Mac-Nightmare-Email-Contacts
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Two Mac Nightmare – Calendars</title>
            <link>
                /2008/The-Two-Mac-Nightmare-Calendars
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;When I &lt;a href=&quot;http://phil.electricweekend.com/2008/12/mac-sync-series/&quot;&gt;introduced&lt;/a&gt; this series of posts, I highlighted the main areas I wanted to keep in sync between my Macs and a web interface for use at work. This post aims to introduce you to the method I use to keep my calendar in sync across the three areas.
On both my Macs I use iCal to keep things or...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2008/The-Two-Mac-Nightmare-Calendars
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Two Mac Nightmare – Synchronisation</title>
            <link>
                /2008/The-Two-Mac-Nightmare-Synchronisation
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;For the last couple of years I’ve been wrestling with the age old problem of having two Macs, a desktop and a laptop. Whilst it’s nice to have the luxury of two Macs it’s always presented an issue that I’m only now beginning to find a solution for. The age old problem of keeping the two machines in sync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many people I’ve gone down the route of pursuing that &lt...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2008/The-Two-Mac-Nightmare-Synchronisation
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Faceless</title>
            <link>
                /2008/Faceless
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Yesterday I encountered something at the bank which made me really think about the way some services are provided. More specifically it’s made me think about how technology is being introduced and taking the place of humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’m sure many of you know, I like technology. It fascinates me and I believe used correctly it can help us do many tasks. In fact I’d say pr...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2008/Faceless
            </guid>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
	</rss>