<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

    <channel>
        <title></title>
        <link></link>
        <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 19:42:11 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        
        <item>
            <title>A tool for thinking</title>
            <link>
                /2021/thinking
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Yesterday as I was sat on my sofa watching the Sunday morning church service on YouTube I had my MacBook Pro open on my lap to make notes in Obsidian. After the service had finished I spent a few minutes to tidy up some formatting and make sure the correct bible verses were being referenced, I realised how much I am enjoying using the app. It got me thinking about why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/thinking
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Yom HaShoah</title>
            <link>
                /2021/yom-hashoah
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Today is Yom HaShoah, or Holocaust Remembrance Day, in Israel. Racism has been in the news a lot of the last year or so, and yet we hear very little of the fact that anti-semitism is on the rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have visited Israel twice. It’s a place that quickly won my heart with it’s beauty and history. Last time I was there was in 2014 and I was able to visit &lt;a href=&quot...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/yom-hashoah
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The notes app quest continues</title>
            <link>
                /2021/notes-app-quest
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve been continuing to seek out a notes app that works for me as well as I would like it too. A couple of weeks ago I posted about &lt;a href=&quot;https://philbowell.com/2021/searching-for-the-perfect-notes-app/&quot;&gt;what I’m looking for&lt;/a&gt; and since then I’ve been giving a couple of the contenders a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I wrote that post I had been using Craft fo...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/notes-app-quest
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Write sentences, what I’m thinking, because I want too</title>
            <link>
                /2021/write-sentences
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Tonight I came across two blog posts in Reeder as I was lying in bed catching up on my feeds and watching the Formula One.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://audacious.blog/2021/write/&quot;&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; was all about writing. The author coined a phrase that is very reminiscent of Michael Pollan’s approach to food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Write sente...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/write-sentences
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Searching for the perfect notes app</title>
            <link>
                /2021/searching-for-notes-app
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;For the last 6 months or so I have been using Roam Research as my notes app. The daily note turned into my home from home allowing me to capture things throughout the day. Thoughts, feelings, meeting notes, tasks, articles I read, videos I watched, everything got noted down in the daily note. Using the service has encouraged me to read more wisely, making notes from articles that are u...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/searching-for-notes-app
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Tweaking my morning routine</title>
            <link>
                /2021/Tweaking-my-morning-routine
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;There’s nothing quite like writing down the routine you’ve found yourself falling into to make you realise there’s somethings you’d like to change. When I &lt;a href=&quot;https://philbowell.com/2021/routines/&quot; title=&quot;Routines&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about my routine the other week it made me more conscious of what I’ve been doing in the morning so I started to pay more att...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/Tweaking-my-morning-routine
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Routines</title>
            <link>
                /2021/routines
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;On my lunch break today as I sat reading some RSS feeds, I came across a [Daily Blogging Challenge] that started on the first of March. As I clicked through to the organising site to find out more I discovered that each day they are sharing a prompt word that everyone taking part should use to kickstart their post for the day. I’m not going to commit to taking part everyday, but I like...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/routines
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Micro blogging again</title>
            <link>
                /2021/micro-blogging-again
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve recently made some changes to the hosting for my blog and other websites as part of the consolidation of my many websites in to one. I had been aiming to have one website to rule them all integrating my portfolio and my blog into one site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m in the process of creating a new theme to help accomplish that, but I realised that for a long time I’ve not wanted to ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/micro-blogging-again
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Lockdown 3</title>
            <link>
                /2021/lockdown-3
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;We have been in Lockdown 3 for a few weeks now as Covid-19 continues to spread through the population. The government issued stay at home notices again, but this time people don’t seem to be following things quite as closely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s both frustrating and annoying seeing so many people still meeting up with friends, even travelling across cities to meet in the park for ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/lockdown-3
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My book of the year 2020</title>
            <link>
                /2020/book-of-the-year
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve always enjoyed reading and for as long as I can remember I’ve read fiction. Several years ago I got surprised with a Kindle for Christmas from my parents. It caused me to increase dramatically the number of books I was reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year is a different story. Reading has been a difficult task something that is very unusual. Reading has always been a point of co...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/book-of-the-year
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Domain conundrums</title>
            <link>
                /2020/domain-conundrum
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve amassed a number of domains for various websites I’ve wanted to create. A few of those are related to my former freelance business, and two relates to blogs. This week I got a notification that 3 of them are up for renewal in January, it’s left me questioning if should renew them all or if it’s time to let some go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the domain for this blog...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/domain-conundrum
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Grey day</title>
            <link>
                /2020/grey-day
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Today has been a grey and foggy day, it’s felt like a real reflection of the mood of the last month. As I’ve driven around Cheltenham today doing some bits and bobs, I’ve seen more and more people starting to put up Christmas trees and lights. It’s been nice to see them emerging out of the gloom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today marks the start of Advent, with the first candle being lit in ch...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/grey-day
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thanksgiving</title>
            <link>
                /2020/thanksgiving
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Today is Thanksgiving in America, and despite being a Brit I thought it would be good to try and post something I’m thankful for this year. I started to write this post at lunchtime, and struggled, I couldn’t zero in on something. This evening after my counselling session I realised what it is I’m thankful for this year. I’m thankful for all the people who have helped my family navigat...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/thanksgiving
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Roaming around</title>
            <link>
                /2020/roaming-around
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Since the end of August I’ve been using Roam Research as my notes application. Having tried and played around with Notion but finding it to be too much work to manage anything, I decided to give Roam and it’s freeform notes a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found it to be one of the most intuitive note taking apps I’ve ever come across and have since begun using it for more and more thin...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/roaming-around
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>An acknowledgement</title>
            <link>
                /2020/an-acknowledgement
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve had this blog in one form or another since I was 21, earlier posts have been lost in the many transitions it has made but it’s always been there. A hobby that taught me how to design and build websites that has since become my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment I think I am in one of the longest streaks of not posting to the site that I’ve ever been on. For the last few wee...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/an-acknowledgement
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My Year in Books 2018</title>
            <link>
                /2018/My-Year-in-Books-2018
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;For the past few years I’ve taken part in the Goodreads Reading Challenge setting myself the target of reading at least 25 books over the course of the year. This year I haven’t quite hit my goal, but I’ve still enjoyed a good year of reading. The books have mostly been fiction this year, with a couple of non-fiction books finding their way in. This is the first year I’ve managed to ma...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/My-Year-in-Books-2018
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Two States of Perfection</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Two-States-of-Perfection
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember I’ve had a sketchbook on the go. I think I established the habit when I started senior school, but I remember having them back in junior school as well. They’ve been a companion beside me all that time, whether I’ve been drawing, writing, brainstorming, planning, or something else, they’ve helped me to be creative in some form or another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Two-States-of-Perfection
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Blogging Habit</title>
            <link>
                /2018/The-Blogging-Habit
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;When I first started writing a blog I was 20. It was my first year of university, and I’d somehow stumbled across a couple of random blogs, I’m not entirely sure how, but I know one thing. As soon as I saw them, I wanted one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dabbled with a free blogger account, and then in my second year at university I bought my first domain and installed WordPress. That was the...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/The-Blogging-Habit
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Bulletin Board</title>
            <link>
                /2018/The-Bulletin-Board
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve been reading Austin Kleon’s blog since January, I find the way that he speaks about his notebooks and how he uses them very inspiring. Today’s post is about his &amp;lt;a href=”https://austinkleon.com/2018/05/01/the-bulletin-board/”&amp;gt;bulletin board&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; and how he pins images, clippings, index cards, and various other bits to it for inspiration while he is writi...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/The-Bulletin-Board
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Establishing New Habits Without Apps</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Establishing-Habits-Without-Apps
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to establish some new habits lately so &amp;lt;a href=”https://www.cjchilvers.com/blog/establishing-new-habits-without-apps”&amp;gt;this was a timely post&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; from CJ Chilvers. I’ve been using the app Streaks like he mentions to keep focused on some of my habits, but there is a certain lack of accountability that goes with it. When a big streak gets broke...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Establishing-Habits-Without-Apps
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My Secret Battle – a Grief Shared</title>
            <link>
                /2018/My-Secret-Battle-a-Grief-Shared
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;This week I can across the blog is Simon Thomas. He’s a Sky Sports presenter and a Christian, known by many in the U.K. He lost his wife to cancer in September last year and has been blogging about his grief. This week he shared a post about &amp;lt;a href=”https://agriefshared.com/2018/02/09/my-secret-battle/”&amp;gt;his Secret Battle&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; with depression and anxiety.&lt;...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/My-Secret-Battle-a-Grief-Shared
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Quantity not quality</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Quantity-not-quality
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;There’s an odd pressure when you’re trying to exercise the muscle of discipline, it’s tempting to want everything you do as a part of that to be the best that it can be. Sometimes you need to just push through and exercise that muscle. When you’re starting out, quantity is often more important than quality. You need to get used to doing something regularly before you can focus on doing...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Quantity-not-quality
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Book Budget</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Book-Budget
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I just added a new category in my YNAB Budget under Quality of Life Goals, it’s name? Books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I started using Goodreads in 2013 I’ve read 104 books. That’s an average of just under 21 books a year with a low of 17 in 2013 and a high of 34 books in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly I like to read, so it made sense to actually budget for these books financially s...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Book-Budget
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Write More</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Write-More
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Cameron Moll &amp;lt;a href=”https://twitter.com/cameronmoll/status/958849192113225728”&amp;gt;posted a thread on Twitter&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; urging  people to write. Here &amp;lt;a href=”https://twitter.com/cameronmoll/status/958849192113225728”&amp;gt;are&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=”https://twitter.com/cameronmoll/status/958849193224781825”&amp;gt;the&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Write-More
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thoughts On Just Turning Up</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Thoughts-Turning-Up
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a little more about the &amp;lt;a href=”http://philbowell.com/2018/thoughts-as-nest-eggs/”&amp;gt;link I posted&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; to Austin Kleon’s blog the other day. I finished it with the line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;
Instead there should just be turning up to write down a thought and seeing where it takes you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a sent...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Thoughts-Turning-Up
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thoughts as Nest Eggs</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Thoughts-as-Nest-Eggs
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;
Today when you say “nest egg” many think of money saved and put away, but a literal “nest egg” is a real or fake egg that you put in a nest to encourage a bird or a hen to lay more eggs there. So what Thoreau is saying is that by simply writing down a thought, you encourage more thoughts to come. When you have enough thoughts pushed together in the same space...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Thoughts-as-Nest-Eggs
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A Home Screen Update</title>
            <link>
                /2017/A-Homescreen-Update
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I used to post a monthly series that looked at the Home Screens of my iPhone and iPad. Over time though I realised it didn’t change as much as I expected and so I lost interest in the process. Things have changed a lot recently so I thought it was time to post another look at my iPhone.
A few of weeks ago I put in to the practise the ideas in a post I &amp;lt;a href=”http://philbowell....
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/A-Homescreen-Update
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A mid-year review</title>
            <link>
                /2017/A-mid-year-review
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Last week I was away at the CMJ Conference, I had the pleasure of joining them to take photos of the event, post to social media throughout it on their accounts, and to hear some excellent bible teaching in the process. It lasted from Friday afternoon to late Sunday afternoon, and by the time I got home I was absolutely exhausted. I spent most of the week recovering whilst trying to wo...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/A-mid-year-review
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Workloads and Creativity</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Workloads-and-Creativity
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed over the last few weeks a distinct correlation between my ability to spend time on side projects and the amount of design work I have going on. Juggling a part time job in the Coffee House alongside running my design business makes for a distinct lack of energy to keep my side/personal projects going when things get busy. I find my motivation drops as my energy gets used u...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Workloads-and-Creativity
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Haptic Architects Teach the Benefits of the Scandinavian Work Life Balance</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Scandinavian-Work-Life-Blance
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Work/Life balance is a thing many of us struggle with. I know when I was 100% self-employed it was the thing I struggled with most, there was always something I felt I should be doing. Whilst many people claim that doing what you love means you have a perfect work/life balance that seems far to idealistic to me. Work is work, whether we love what we do or not and we need a good balance...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Scandinavian-Work-Life-Blance
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Walking</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Walking
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Back in January 2015 when I realised I was ill, and consequently started a course of antidepressants, many people encouraged me to exercise. I had been a keen cyclist and they encouraged me to keep at it and get out on my bike as much as I could. I was told, and in fact read many times, that exercise was a great way of countering some of the symptoms of depression. My issue was that th...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Walking
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Employment vs. Self-Employment</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Employment-vs-Self-Employment
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Occasionally I’ll come across an article on the internet that I find myself reading more than once. Usually it’s because the piece resonates deeply with me, but sometimes it’s because it’s something I want to be able to write myself. In this instance it’s just that, a piece I would like to be able to write in a years time, but with my own perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a piece abo...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Employment-vs-Self-Employment
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Seth Godin Blog Daily</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Seth-Godin-Blog-Daily
            </link>
            <description>
                
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;title: Seth Godin Explains Why You Should Blog Daily
—
With the arrival of Micro.blog my interest in my blog has picked up considerably. It’s always been there bubbling at the back of my mind, but actively posting micro posts to it has me once again looking to post other content more regularly. CJChilvers linked to an article by Seth Godin that &amp;lt;a href=”https://www...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Seth-Godin-Blog-Daily
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Deep Prayer &gt; Deep Work</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Deep-Prayer-Deep-Work
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of talk on the internet circles I follow about focus and deep work. They’re thought provoking and often resonate with me, but there’s one thing I’ve been struggling to reconcile in it all. The focus of all these discussions is usually aimed at putting your individual desires first, which doesn’t really jive with my Christian beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris Bowler,...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Deep-Prayer-Deep-Work
            </guid>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
	</rss>