<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

    <channel>
        <title></title>
        <link></link>
        <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 13:36:11 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        
        <item>
            <title>Work, Family, Scene - Pick two</title>
            <link>
                /2022/Work-Family-Scene
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Life is about tradeoffs. When we know what to say no to, and we know why, we can say yes with comfort and confidence to the things that matter. To the things that last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conversation with one of my favourite authors Austin Kleon, Ryan Holiday finished a post with this quote. They were discussing the choices between work, family, and scene, but I the sentence above can be applied to a lot of things.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2022/Work-Family-Scene
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Any day can be Blue Monday</title>
            <link>
                /2022/any-day-can-be-blue-monday
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Today, the third Monday of January, is commonly referred to as Blue Monday. It’s considered to be the most depressing day of the year. By this time people are feeling down because they have broken all their New Year’s resolutions and there’s still another week until pay day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day’s like this that receive a lot of coverage in the press can be both damaging and helpful to mental health awareness. They can harm mental health awareness by giving the impression that depression or other illnesses only happen on particular days, but they can be helpful by bringing conversations up with people. They can be helpful to highlight that every day can be a &lt;em&gt;Blue Monday&lt;/em&gt;, it is not confined to a single Monday in January. Instead it can strike on any day, at any time. My &lt;em&gt;Blue Monday&lt;/em&gt;’s have been on a Friday in December, a Monday in August, and a Tuesday in January. Each on years or months apart. What’s important to know is that they are all survivable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are struggling with your own &lt;em&gt;Blue Monday&lt;/em&gt; you’re not alone. People are there to help you, be they family, friends, or healthcare professionals. They all care about you. Don’t suffer in silence.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2022/any-day-can-be-blue-monday
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Keep it simple…</title>
            <link>
                /2022/keep-it-simple
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Part of my approach to the new year involved rediscovering one of my habits. I’ve been trying to &lt;a href=&quot;https://philbowell.com/2022/i-want-my-hobby-back&quot;&gt;write a blog post more often&lt;/a&gt;. I initially intended to use my Micro.blog and to post all my content there, but given the chance to reflect I realised I wanted my longer posts to live here. I’m not committing to a set number of posts per week, but I am committing to posting here more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All week I’ve been thinking about what to write about. Everytime I opened my iPad and sat down to write something I couldn’t think of anything to write. It started to become a problem. I wanted to write a post, but I didn’t know what to write. I wanted to write a post but I began to feel like I didn’t have anything to say. I wanted to write but I began to believe I didn’t have anything to say or write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is evening as I sat here recovering from my counselling session I was bumbling around on the internet. Something made me google a photographer whose blog I used to follow years ago. I even have one of his photos. To my delight I found his website and realised he was still blogging regularly. As I scrolled through his posts I came across one titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jorgeq.com/blog/stop-hiding-behind-complexity&quot;&gt;Stop hiding behind complexity&lt;/a&gt;. The first line struck me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Whether we like to admit it or not, we sometimes enjoy making the simplest task more difficult because it’s easier to blame the many loops it would have taken to finish it if we don’t succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realised perhaps this is what I’m doing with my blog. I want to write a post but I think that I need to write something significant. Instead of sitting down to write something, be it about something I’ve read or done this week, I’m making the simple task complicated. The likelihood is that it’s easier to not post something and hide behind the thought that I have nothing to say than it is to open Obsidian and write until I’ve put something together worth posting. If I want to write for my blog more often, it should be as simple as writing a post and publishing it. No second guessing myself and no worrying about whether I have something to say. Just writing.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2022/keep-it-simple
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My time for work playlist</title>
            <link>
                /2022/Time-for-work-playlist
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve developed a few strategies to help get me in to the right frame of mind to work. One of the best ones is my time for work playlist, I put it on when I need to focus and it never fails to get me into the right state to focus on a project. I’ve worked out that the best albums for me to work to are film soundtracks. The nature of films means that they often build to a finale towards the end of the film, and the soundtracks have a big part to play in that. I find that as the urgency in the music builds my focus deepens and by the end of the soundtrack I’m immersed in my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally I’ll come across a new album that has a similar effect to the play list and I add it on the end. This week when I came across a new album I realised that it might be time to review the albums that I have in there. When I opened it up I had amassed over 6 hours worth of music. I realised it was time to review what albums I had saved, along with the fact that I rarely even got to the soundtracks at towards the end of the playlist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time when I used this playlist it was to settle down to a block of work, generally in the afternoons when I have fewer meetings at work. That means a block of work a can last between 1 and 3 hours, so I really had no need for the amount of music that was in there. On a Wednesday afternoon work has implemented a no meetings policy, it means we have a consistent free block of time we can set aside for deep work, and my playlist gets used a lot on those afternoons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I assessed the albums that I had in there, I decided it was time to limit the length to about 3.5 hours of music. I picked my top 2 soundtracks and added in the new one to hit the magic length of time. I structured the playlist with the longest first moving to the shortest last. We travel through Dune, Tron Legacy, and The Dark Knight, which nicely breaks my work period into three chunks should I need to pause for a few minutes and move my legs. I’ve been using it this week and it’s working very well. If you’re interested here’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://music.apple.com/gb/playlist/time-for-work/pl.u-9B3du5440G&quot;&gt;Apple Music version&lt;/a&gt; for you.&lt;/p&gt;


            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2022/Time-for-work-playlist
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>I want my hobby back</title>
            <link>
                /2022/I-want-my-hobby-back
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;One thing I want to do more of this year it to write. Back when I started blogging in 2005 or 2006 I used to post everyday, often more than once. It might have been the novelty of being able to write something and have it appear on the internet for people to read that made it easier. It might also have been that the blogging community was in full force at the time, but one thing is for certain it was my hobby and I enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since those heady days of the my blog something has gone astray. It might have been that all the bloggers I followed at the time became “serious” about blogging. They made careers out of it, and it made me feel like I had to be “serious” as well. Twitter also had a large impact. A lot of people, myself included, became more focused on posting there than on their blogs. Sharing took place there, but it lacked the same feel. What I do know is that somewhere along the way the joy of blogging disappeared and I lost interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve tried to kick start the habit again but it’s never lasted more than a couple of weeks. This Christmas I’ve had some time to think and reflect over the events of the last couple of years. One thing that has become clear is that I lack a hobby, something for myself, and I want a hobby as much as I’ve realised I need one. I’ve decided that one of my intentions this year is to blog more, to find my hobby again and write for me. I try to journal most days in Obsidian which helps my mental health, but I want my blog to be more. So I’m starting off in January with a simple goal. To post something at lest once a day. Whether it’s a thought, or a link, or a longer piece is irrelevant, I want to make the act of posting a habit again. Most importantly I want to find the joy of sharing again.&lt;/p&gt;


            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2022/I-want-my-hobby-back
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>World Elephant Day Is Today</title>
            <link>
                /2021/World-Elephant-Day
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;This morning I found out that it’s world elephant day. It’s one of those facts which has stuck in my mind ever since for the simple fact that elephants are my favourite animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parents tell the story of when I was small and we went to zoo together for the first time. There was one animal I wanted to see, the elephants, but for little me they were terrifying. I had only ever seen pictures of elephants in books, where the scale of the images didn’t communicate to me how big the creatures are in reality. When you’re a small child and see a picture of an elephant on one page and a duck on the next, the two appear the same size. So when I saw the sheer size of the creatures, I burst into tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t remember the day, but it makes me want to go back and reassure my small self that it’s ok, elephants are still awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years I’ve struggled with my mental health. It’s the second serious bout of depression that I’ve had in the last 8 years. This time, I’ve found elephants oddly comforting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Mum and my Aunt have often sent me small videos of elephants in that time and never once have they failed to bring a smile to my face. Baby elephants are funny. They do daft things and they have fun little personalities. Who can’t help but laugh at the elephant that kicks it’s trainer in the bum while standing next to him? They are like naughty teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s another side to elephants which I’ve really come to appreciate in the last couple of years. The caring, nurturing side of the adults. I’m sure other animals exhibit these characteristics to their young, but something about the way the elephants express it is very comforting. Perhaps it’s their size, and the strength and power they display, that makes it more surprising when you see a mum curl her trunk around her baby and pick it up from the ground. There’s a gentleness from these animals that you wouldn’t expect. At a time when the world seems more broken than it ever has, there’s something oddly comforting in seeing a large creature display such gentle and caring behaviours towards others of it’s kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t really know where this post is going, or really what the point of it is, other than that I wanted to write something today. So here it is. Make of it what you will.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/World-Elephant-Day
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Welcome to version 8 of my blog</title>
            <link>
                /2021/Welcome-to-version-8
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;As the title says, welcome to the eighth official version of my blog. This one has been a while in the making. It started as a new theme on Wordpress over a year ago, included a short holiday on Ghost before ending up being powered by Jekyll. That makes this the first version of my blog not to be powered by Wordpress and in all honesty it’s a refreshing change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I’m using a new engine to power things, I’ve decided to take a bit of an iterative approach. What you see here is what I would call the Earliest Testable Product (ETP). It has all the basics I would like to include on my blog, a home page, an about page, an archive page, and the blog posts themselves. My intention is to gradually add features over the coming months, improve the design of some elements, and ultimately add a place to display some portfolio pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest decision about this new version of my blog was the move away from Wordpress. The CMS has powered this site since the very beginning, but recent versions have made me start to question how suitable it is for a site such as this. Wordpress has begun to feel quite heavy and complicated with lots of new features being added that I had no interest in. I began to crave a simpler way of doing things. Something flexible that didn’t require my Mac for me to work on so that I can do things from my iPad as well. It’s the ability to develop from my iPad is a big part of the decision. It has become my go to device away from work and the one which I do most of my writing on so being able to develop the blog from iPad became a big factor in picking the new engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next few weeks I plan to put together a roadmap to work through for both features and design improvements, at least until I get the key things implemented. In the mean time, if you see anything that seems out of place or broken, drop me &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:phil@philbowell.com&quot;&gt;an email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/Welcome-to-version-8
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A tool for thinking</title>
            <link>
                /2021/thinking
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Yesterday as I was sat on my sofa watching the Sunday morning church service on YouTube I had my MacBook Pro open on my lap to make notes in Obsidian. After the service had finished I spent a few minutes to tidy up some formatting and make sure the correct bible verses were being referenced, I realised how much I am enjoying using the app. It got me thinking about why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the day it slowly dawned on me what it is that I like about it. It doesn’t tick all the features I was hoping to &lt;a href=&quot;https://philbowell.com/2021/searching-for-the-perfect-notes-app/&quot;&gt;find in the my notes app&lt;/a&gt;, but it does tick one that I didn’t list before. It is a tool for thinking, and really that’s what I’ve been looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ephemeral notes still go into Obsidian through my daily notes, and where appropriate they are linked to project notes, but I’ve found that I’m creating notes about subjects that I am thinking about or trying to learn more about. Looking at my Obsidian graph I see some small clusters starting to form. There is one about note taking itself as I read around the subject of evergreen and atomic notes; there is one around habits and routines; and there is a larger one forming related to my work and current thinking about the concept of Minimal Viable Products (MVP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve been looking into these different applications and their feature sets, I’ve been exposed to some ideas about note taking that I had never really considered before. The concept that a “notes” app can be more than a scratchpad used throughout the day but a tool for thinking has connected with me. Really it is not a notes app but something much more useful and important. I guess this is why many people refer to these tools that I’ve been exploring as Personal Knowledge Management (PKM) or their second brain. I’m not sure either of those terms sit right with me, I think they are more than that. I am not purely gaining knowledge by using this tool and it’s not thinking for me like a second brain should, but I can use this tool to see connections between ideas. It forces me to distill concepts down to manageable chunks so that I can form my own ideas from them. This is why I’ve begun referring to it as a tool for thinking and why it’s starting to become a key part of my creative process. Time will tell if it lasts.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/thinking
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Yom HaShoah</title>
            <link>
                /2021/yom-hashoah
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Today is Yom HaShoah, or Holocaust Remembrance Day, in Israel. Racism has been in the news a lot of the last year or so, and yet we hear very little of the fact that anti-semitism is on the rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have visited Israel twice. It’s a place that quickly won my heart with it’s beauty and history. Last time I was there was in 2014 and I was able to visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yadvashem.org&quot;&gt;Yad Vashem&lt;/a&gt;, The World Holocaust Remembrance Center. To this day when I think about my visit the feelings come flooding back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The museum which tells of all the events that took place across Europe overwhelmed me to the point that I couldn’t take it anymore. I had to walk to the end and find a place to sit down. After a cup of tea our group then visited the memorial which names all the people who died. It was just as overwhelming. A friend who was part of our party was able to find the names of her family members in the memorial and so the Holocaust became even more of a reality to me. We learn all about the atrocities of World War 2 in our history lessons, but until there is a personal connection with the events it’s hard for it to feel like a reality. My Grandad once wrote me a letter about what he did when he fought in the War, it made the war a reality to me and not just something to learn about. Seeing my friend find her family members in the memorial had a similar effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not really sure where I’m going with this post, other than to say I will remember them. I hope you will too, and I hope that together we can all make sure that something like it is never repeated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are very few Jews left who survived the Holocaust, so we must find ways to make those connections with history a reality for the generations who cannot hear first hand what it was like. I think the stories of family members will play a crucial role in that. Let’s make sure it never happens again.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/yom-hashoah
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The notes app quest continues</title>
            <link>
                /2021/notes-app-quest
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve been continuing to seek out a notes app that works for me as well as I would like it too. A couple of weeks ago I posted about &lt;a href=&quot;https://philbowell.com/2021/searching-for-the-perfect-notes-app/&quot;&gt;what I’m looking for&lt;/a&gt; and since then I’ve been giving a couple of the contenders a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I wrote that post I had been using Craft for around a week or so. It’s a very good app, I like that it is native on all my devices, has good shortcuts support and is a pleasure to write in. It lacked a couple of the features on my list out of the box, but a quick shortcut was able to fix the lack of a daily note and I was happily on my way giving it a run through it’s paces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having been forced into a week off work thanks to some strong side effects from my Covid vaccine, last weekend I started to play with Obsidian to see how it worked. Initially put off by it I found a theme that makes it look and feel a lot more like a native macOS application. So last week I started giving it a run through it’s paces. It’s lacking a first party iOS and iPadOS app at the moment, but one is in beta and seems to be developing quickly and since there’s nowhere to go at the moment it’s not the end of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I intend to give Obsidian a similar amount of time to Craft and then I’ll try to make a decision. There are a few things about Craft which started to really annoy me before I decided to give Obsidian a try, and I’m sure there will be some things about Obsidian that annoy me as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far Craft feels better placed for meeting notes and capturing tasks along the way. It’s ability to easily send something to Things is great. In contrast Obsidian seems to handle referencing and embedding blocks more efficiently. Craft can do this but I ended up having some real difficulties finding blocks I wanted to reference and once I had figured out the syntax that Obsidian uses it made a lot more sense. Both apps have their strengths, I have a feeling it will be about refining how I take notes and which one will handle that.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/notes-app-quest
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Write sentences, what I’m thinking, because I want too</title>
            <link>
                /2021/write-sentences
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Tonight I came across two blog posts in Reeder as I was lying in bed catching up on my feeds and watching the Formula One. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://audacious.blog/2021/write/&quot;&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; was all about writing. The author coined a phrase that is very reminiscent of Michael Pollan’s approach to food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Write sentences, not too many, mostly active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It riffs nicely off&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Eat food, not too much, mostly plants&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something which I’m trying to stick too but not very good at. It might have connected with me because it’s familiar, but I think it goes a bit deeper than that. I’ve been trying to write more lately. I want to post a lot more regularly than I do, but often feel that I’m not contributing enough to warrant a post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://gabz.me/2021/03/25/just-blog.html&quot; title=&quot;Just blog&quot;&gt;second&lt;/a&gt; seemed to know what I am thinking and hit me between the eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just blog, if that’s all you want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend I &lt;a href=&quot;https://philbowell.micro.blog/2021/03/27/installed-ghost-locally.html&quot;&gt;downloaded and installed Ghost&lt;/a&gt; on my Mac. I’ve been looking at moving away from Wordpress for a while and finally took the time to look into one of the alternatives. But really it’s just a distraction. I have a fully functional blog here. I’d like to change the design of it, but I don’t need too. If I want to blog more, I should do it. So I’m going to try and write sentences about what I’m thinking, because I want too. That seems to be a good way of looking at things. I will still slowly work on a new design for this place, but I’m going to do my utmost to make sure that it doesn’t stop me from posting more.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/write-sentences
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Searching for the perfect notes app</title>
            <link>
                /2021/searching-for-notes-app
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;For the last 6 months or so I have been using Roam Research as my notes app. The daily note turned into my home from home allowing me to capture things throughout the day. Thoughts, feelings, meeting notes, tasks, articles I read, videos I watched, everything got noted down in the daily note. Using the service has encouraged me to read more wisely, making notes from articles that are useful and capturing highlights and thoughts as I read books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last month or so, I’ve noticed my usage start to drop off. Some of it is related to me having days off from work, so I’m not in front of my Mac all day, but that’s not the sole reason. I’m writing this on my iPad which has become my main personal computer. Mac for work, iPad for me. I started to realise that this is part of the reason I’ve been using Roam less even though I still wanted to capture notes and thoughts. I don’t find the experience of Roam on the iPad to be that pleasant. There are too many little quirks and bits that don’t quite work properly that mar the experience enough to to make me want to stop using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the last week I started to draw up a shortlist of apps to try in an attempt to replace Roam. In order to really understand if something can grow in to a replacement I need to understand how I’ve been using Roam and what I have come to find really useful about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-the-key-features-im-after&quot;&gt;What are the key features I’m after?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;daily-notes&quot;&gt;Daily Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve come to realise the joy and freedom in having a Daily Note open on my screen all day. It has become my main place to capture anything and everything. Articles I read, what’s on my mind, notes from meetings I’m in, tasks that come in. Each new item gets a time stamp and then I write down what I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;references-to-blocks-and-pages&quot;&gt;References to blocks and pages&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is new functionality to me but one that I’ve quickly understood the value of. Being able to reference something with a back link is really powerful. If I’m in my Daily Note and jot something down about a project, being able to quickly link to that project page and have what I wrote appear there is invaluable. It frees up thoughts for thinking instead of focusing on putting it in the right place in my system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;embedding-blocks&quot;&gt;Embedding blocks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are even more powerful and I think have become really important for me. On a Sunday as I watch church on YouTube (who knew that would be a thing?) I make notes on the sermon. I’ve taken to adding the bible passage broken down verse by verse in a separate note, then when I need to make a note about a verse I embed the block and write a note under it. Having the text visible is really useful and having the bible passages automatically reference all the notes I make over time will be really insightful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;capturing-tasks&quot;&gt;Capturing tasks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a simple one, but a quick way to capture tasks in a meeting without having to change app focus is great. Even better is the ability to send those tasks to my dedicated task manager where I can organise them after the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;journal&quot;&gt;Journal&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This final one is a little up in the air at the moment. I used the Daily Note of Roam to help me start journaling again and since beginning this quest to find a more native experience I’ve dusted off Day One and started to use that instead. As I reflected on how I had been Journaling in Roam, I realised that I didn’t intentionally use any of the connected thought features for it. Questioning why that was, I realised it’s because what I’ve been journaling about isn’t necessarily related to what I’ve been thinking about or working on, instead it’s more about processing how I feel and am handling situations. So for now I’m going to use Day One for this part of my writing, although it lacks the convenience of having one place to write I think the trade off is better for me.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/searching-for-notes-app
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Tweaking my morning routine</title>
            <link>
                /2021/Tweaking-my-morning-routine
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;There’s nothing quite like writing down the routine you’ve found yourself falling into to make you realise there’s somethings you’d like to change. When I &lt;a href=&quot;https://philbowell.com/2021/routines/&quot; title=&quot;Routines&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about my routine the other week it made me more conscious of what I’ve been doing in the morning so I started to pay more attention to what I was doing last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the course of the week I realised I was spending a bit too much time in bed bumbling on the internet at the start of the day and then rushing through some other things that are more valuable. Last week I decided to try something out. I left my phone alarm to go off as it always does, then I set my little alarm clock to go off at 07:15 in the hope that it’s blaring sound would be enough to pull me out of my snoozing habit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the alarm waking me more thoroughly I found I was naturally ready to get out of bed a bit earlier. The one problem was that I was still slipping into my habit of lying in bed for longer than I needed too. So this week I added a new part to my wake up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using my habit app of choice &lt;a href=&quot;https://streaksapp.com&quot;&gt;Streaks&lt;/a&gt; I added a new task with a timed alert for 07:30 to get out of bed at that time. So far it’s been working. I’ve been out of bed at that time everyday this week and showered, dressed, and in my chair by 08:00. It’s given me another 20 minutes of space in the morning to spend a bit longer on my quiet time and even start writing some blog posts like this one. The big test will be next week, it’s one thing to keep doing something the week you start it, it’s another picking it up and carrying on for a second or third week.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/Tweaking-my-morning-routine
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Routines</title>
            <link>
                /2021/routines
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;On my lunch break today as I sat reading some RSS feeds, I came across a [Daily Blogging Challenge] that started on the first of March. As I clicked through to the organising site to find out more I discovered that each day they are sharing a prompt word that everyone taking part should use to kickstart their post for the day. I’m not going to commit to taking part everyday, but I liked the prompt from 1st March, [routine].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Routines have always been a bit of a comfort to me, mostly they just happen and I realise that I’ve settled in to one without considering what I’m doing. My morning routine for example is one that I’ve realised I’ve settled in to without really considering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wake up with my alarm around 07:00 and spend the next 45 minutes or so waking up. That involves a bit of snoozing, a bit of morning messaging, and a bit of bumbling around on the internet. Then I get out of bed and head towards the shower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m usually dressed and ready to start my day by around 08:20. The next step is a glass of juice and my meds, followed by a sit down in my chair and a bit of time to have a quiet time with whatever reading plan I’m using in the Youversion app at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 08:40 I’ll turn on my Mac and head to the kitchen to make coffee and sort out some food for myself before I settle at my desk to contrive the days business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t realise this was a routine I’d fallen in to until I came across Pablo Picasso’s daily schedule and it started me on path looking in to the routines of other famous creators, something I’ll be looking into and sharing here.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/routines
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Micro blogging again</title>
            <link>
                /2021/micro-blogging-again
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve recently made some changes to the hosting for my blog and other websites as part of the consolidation of my many websites in to one. I had been aiming to have one website to rule them all integrating my portfolio and my blog into one site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m in the process of creating a new theme to help accomplish that, but I realised that for a long time I’ve not wanted to post the short status posts and images on to this site. I used to use Twitter for that, and whilst I’m still on the site I rarely use it. I’ve also been a member of [Micro.Blog] since the kickstarter days, but lately I’ve found myself just observing with only the occasional reply and not actually contributing. So I’ve decided to give something a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve setup a hosted Micro Blog, which will use one of my spare personal domains, and I’m going to try posting to there with the short status posts and images as I would’ve done on Twitter and Instagram. I’ll likely use it to share things links and things along the way. In contrast I plan to keep this blog as somewhere to post longer posts and in time to add my portfolio as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To simplify things, I’m thinking about using my Micro Blog and this blog as ways of generating some [Stock and Flow]. As Robin Sloan put it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Flow is the feed. It’s the posts and the tweets. It’s the stream of daily and sub-daily updates that reminds people you exist.
Stock is the durable stuff. It’s the content you produce that’s as interesting in two months (or two years) as it is today. It’s what people discover via search. It’s what spreads slowly but surely, building fans over time.
I’ve realised I’ve lost those concepts in my creative work. I no longer tweet and I don’t blog regularly, so if I can start to correct that I hope that the two blog formats can inform one another with more content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an extension of that I’ve also been thinking a lot about Austin Kleon’s book [Show Your Work], something which I’ve also not been doing much of lately. My hope is that I’ll be able to combine these two sites and ways of posting with showing some of my work. Be it personal or professional (when appropriate). We’ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/micro-blogging-again
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Lockdown 3</title>
            <link>
                /2021/lockdown-3
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;We have been in Lockdown 3 for a few weeks now as Covid-19 continues to spread through the population. The government issued stay at home notices again, but this time people don’t seem to be following things quite as closely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s both frustrating and annoying seeing so many people still meeting up with friends, even travelling across cities to meet in the park for birthdays. Everyone it seems is able to find a way of exempting themselves from the rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to approach this lockdown differently as well. Maybe because it’s also a new year, I’m not sure. I’m trying to eat more healthily, snack less, and exercise more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nations favourite–or maybe least favourite judging by some of social media–PE teacher Joe Wicks, has been doing his live workouts again. This has been my workout of choice so far, I’ve not been doing it live as it’s at an inconvenient time for work, but I’ve been doing the recorded versions at a later time. I’m 6 for 6 so far, and I’d never thought I’d say this about HIIT workouts, but I’m actually enjoying them. Although not the ache or stiffness in my legs after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also been taking more time to read this time. In the first lockdown I couldn’t concentrate on a book, I wasn’t able to focus for more than a couple of minutes and would find myself rereading sentences over and over. This time however has been different. I’m finding that familiar refuge in fiction again. Getting lost in another world that exists only in my imagination and one that doesn’t have the anxiety that comes with the world we live in right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also been watching the last season of Portrait Artist of the Year. It’s one of the few “reality” tv shows I enjoy. Previous series have always made me feel inspired, but this time around it seems to be more so. I’ve even sorted out all my old art materials with the aim of finding some time to pick up a brush. We will see what happens there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I finish writing this the sun is coming out. The covering of snow I woke up too this morning is still there, but I fear it may not last long. Time to dig out the wellies and go for a walk.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2021/lockdown-3
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My book of the year 2020</title>
            <link>
                /2020/book-of-the-year
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve always enjoyed reading and for as long as I can remember I’ve read fiction. Several years ago I got surprised with a Kindle for Christmas from my parents. It caused me to increase dramatically the number of books I was reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year is a different story. Reading has been a difficult task something that is very unusual. Reading has always been a point of comfort for me. When I was in junior school I had a series of books I would read when I was struggling with being bullied. When I was in my teens I would go back and read familiar books when I needed to find something calming. A few years ago when I was battling my first bout of depression I read Harry Potter books that were familiar and provided a way for my mind to imagine instead of spiral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when the world imploded this year, I thought once again I would be able to find refuge in books of fiction. But for several months I struggled to read. My mind could not focus, so it was a surprise to me when I looked at my reading stats in Book Track and Goodreads to discover that I had read more books this year than last. The thirteen books (so far) I’ve read this year is still low compared to my normal levels, but there is a definite uptick in the final half of the year that I’m pleased to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I set out to write this post it was going to be a top 5 books of the year, as I started writing I realised there’s only one book I want to highlight. I read it right at the start of the year, and it’s a book that has continually come to mind ever since. I was given a print of one of the pages in it for my birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Boy, the Mole, the Fox and the Horse&lt;/strong&gt; by Charlie Mackesy is a masterpiece. It has been so relatable over the course of this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quote that has been hanging in my living room is one which many people have reminded me of and one which will no doubt have me returning to time after time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Being kind to yourself is one of the greatest kindnesses,” said the mole. “&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a time when people often become quite introspective and look back at what they’ve done with the year, it’s easy to see all the people shouting about how they have utilised the lockdown to achieve so much and feel inadequate. It would be easy to begin beating ourselves up. So we should take notice of what the mole has to say, and be kind to ourselves, because actually getting through this year is pretty good going.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/book-of-the-year
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Domain conundrums</title>
            <link>
                /2020/domain-conundrum
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve amassed a number of domains for various websites I’ve wanted to create. A few of those are related to my former freelance business, and two relates to blogs. This week I got a notification that 3 of them are up for renewal in January, it’s left me questioning if should renew them all or if it’s time to let some go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the domain for this blog, philbowell.com, which I will definitely renew. I have philbowell.blog, which I used briefly for this site, and I have philbowell.design, which is what I used for the last couple of years of working for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I started working as part of an in-house UX team, I’ve been intending to consolidate my portfolio into my personal site. One domain for both places. What I hadn’t thought of was how to handle the domains. A redirect seems to make the most sense, but the cost of renewing them is much higher than I expected it to be. Letting go of domain names is something that I don’t like doing and I’m trying to work out the impact of doing that. It’s a tricky conundrum.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/domain-conundrum
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Grey day</title>
            <link>
                /2020/grey-day
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Today has been a grey and foggy day, it’s felt like a real reflection of the mood of the last month. As I’ve driven around Cheltenham today doing some bits and bobs, I’ve seen more and more people starting to put up Christmas trees and lights. It’s been nice to see them emerging out of the gloom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today marks the start of Advent, with the first candle being lit in churches across the country we are reminded of the hope that comes from Jesus. The arrival of the King.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of this year I started to go to a new church, given the pandemic if might not have been the best time, but the services I’ve been attending online have been ones of great comfort. They have shown great care, sensitivity, and compassion throughout the year, and I’m incredibly thankful that God guided me to this church. I’m looking forward to being able to go to a service again, I hope it is sooner rather than later. I’m sure it will be.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/grey-day
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thanksgiving</title>
            <link>
                /2020/thanksgiving
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Today is Thanksgiving in America, and despite being a Brit I thought it would be good to try and post something I’m thankful for this year. I started to write this post at lunchtime, and struggled, I couldn’t zero in on something. This evening after my counselling session I realised what it is I’m thankful for this year. I’m thankful for all the people who have helped my family navigate through the year. The members of their church, some old friends from previous churches, some new friends, some new colleagues who have become friends. Some people who were friends and I’ve discovered are now very good friends. For all of them I am thankful, we couldn’t have done it without you.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/thanksgiving
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Roaming around</title>
            <link>
                /2020/roaming-around
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Since the end of August I’ve been using Roam Research as my notes application. Having tried and played around with Notion but finding it to be too much work to manage anything, I decided to give Roam and it’s freeform notes a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found it to be one of the most intuitive note taking apps I’ve ever come across and have since begun using it for more and more things. It’s not just replaced the notes apps I was trying to use before, it’s become my journal and task manager as well. In fact it’s even starting to grow into my personal CRM as well and I believe it is behind the desire for me to start blogging more because I’m enjoying writing in it so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I like is that is seems to fit the way I think. Despite being a visual person I often find myself taking notes in the form of bullet points. When I’m thinking and working through something on paper I will often write a point and then riff off it with a series of bullet points below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two way linking has also been a revelation. One of the things I was trying to use Notion for was a one stop shop for my notes and tasks that related to various projects I’m working on. The databases that make Notion so powerful seemed like a good fit for this, but I found it to be a lot of extra work to maintain. In contrast Roam’s Daily Notes, which I use heavily, helps to give me both context in the form of when something happened as well as an easy way to automatically link to a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What has been surprising for me has been how I’ve found it to help me on a deeper level. The fact that I have a daily note open on my screen all day as I work means that when I find myself having to deal with some strong emotions I am able to write them down to help me process them. One thing I am having to learn is to not let my thought patterns spiral. I find it all too easy to get stuck in a particular thought pattern that turns itself over and over in my mind. Having something open all the time lets me process what I’m feeling when I become aware of it helps me to tackle that spiral in a way I’ve not been able to before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favourite books this year comes from an artist called Charlie Mackesy. I discovered it by accident when I was looking for a Christmas present last December. I bought it and gave that book as a gift for J and she loved it so much she bought me my own copy and I’ve since bought it for my Mum as well. For my birthday this year I got given a print of one the pages from the book. It contains a quote which is something both a couple of friends and my counsellor keep reminding me of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Being kind to yourself is one of the greatest kindnesses,” said the mole.
It struck me as I was writing this that having the space to process my feelings and let myself feel them is being kind to myself and that perhaps we all need to be a bit kinder to ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/roaming-around
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>An acknowledgement</title>
            <link>
                /2020/an-acknowledgement
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve had this blog in one form or another since I was 21, earlier posts have been lost in the many transitions it has made but it’s always been there. A hobby that taught me how to design and build websites that has since become my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment I think I am in one of the longest streaks of not posting to the site that I’ve ever been on. For the last few weeks I’ve wanted to start posting again, I’m seeking to revive a hobby that was once very enjoyable to me. The trouble is I don’t know where to start or what to write. So, I’m writing this post as an acknowledgement of some very difficult events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last two years have been two of the hardest of my life. This time two years ago I was working part-time in a speciality coffee shop, doing some freelance design work, and contracting in to a local studio. There was a promise that my contract position would become full time in the next six months. At the beginning of April last year, a conversation that I thought would be about going full time was a conversation about the studio changing their mind. A month later I was no longer working there. A month after that the final client for my freelance business, which I was winding down due to the aforementioned promise, understandably told me they had made other arrangements for their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the work situation I was dealing with some things in my personal life. The culmination of all these events, alongside an unsuccessful gruelling seven week interview process, resulted in a mental breakdown and the return of my depression in August last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One positive is that somehow, in the middle of that breakdown I managed to think clearly enough for an hour-long interview that resulted in the job I have now been in for over a year. I can only thank God for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then 2020 happened. A global pandemic has thrown the world into chaos as Covid-19 has swept across the world. Normal life has been taken away which for everyone has been a difficult adjustment. In the midst of this my Mum has been undergoing treatment for cancer and my Dad has had and recovered from a stroke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping that by writing this post it will help to remove the block I have been struggling with when it comes to posting to this site. Through counselling I have come to realise the importance of taking care of yourself properly. I have realised that I need hobbies in my life and I would like to start blogging here again as a first tentative step to building some healthy habits. I didn’t feel I could get that going again without acknowledging recent events, so here I am taking a scary step and daring to put into words some of the hardest experiences I have had to go through.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2020/an-acknowledgement
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Two States of Perfection</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Two-States-of-Perfection
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember I’ve had a sketchbook on the go. I think I established the habit when I started senior school, but I remember having them back in junior school as well. They’ve been a companion beside me all that time, whether I’ve been drawing, writing, brainstorming, planning, or something else, they’ve helped me to be creative in some form or another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a new sketchbook arrives, it always brings a moment of joy. The moment the wrappings come off is one of the two moments that a sketchbook is perfect. There are no creases on the spine, no scuffs on the cover, no page corners curling up or folded in, everything sits square and compact, full of potential. I always enjoy that moment. When a sketchbook is first opened it’s exciting, there’s potential on those pages, but with it comes a hesitancy, it’s something that I don’t want to ruin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the fear of the blank page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years when I’ve started a new sketchbook I’ve developed a habit. I open it to the first page, grab a pen and I write the same sentence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I give myself permission to mess this sketchbook up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From then on I use it how I want and it doesn’t matter what goes in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might seem a bit silly to write that sentence on the first page, but without it it would take a lot longer for my sketchbooks to get to their second point of perfection. The moment they are finished, either because they are completely full, or the year has ended. At that point it’s done it’s job and deserves it’s spot on my shelf alongside all it’s older siblings, it’s perfect because it’s been used and not wasted. It’s helped me think, helped me create, helped me process events that have passed, it’s potential has been met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without that first page sentence and my natural state of being a perfectionist, there’s a chance those sketchbooks would remain on the shelf in their first state of perfection. And in that state they would be a waste. What would be the point in owning them, if they remained forever in their first state of perfection and never made the journey to the second state of perfection?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not just a sketchbook that has these two states of perfection. A blog has them, a canvas has them, a book has them, a roll of film or an SD card in a camera has them. The unused perfection, and the finished, full, complete perfection of a job well done.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Two-States-of-Perfection
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Blogging Habit</title>
            <link>
                /2018/The-Blogging-Habit
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;When I first started writing a blog I was 20. It was my first year of university, and I’d somehow stumbled across a couple of random blogs, I’m not entirely sure how, but I know one thing. As soon as I saw them, I wanted one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dabbled with a free blogger account, and then in my second year at university I bought my first domain and installed WordPress. That was the beginning of having my own personal website, a place where I posted to almost every day, where I taught myself how to build websites. I looked at other peoples blogs, I copied what they were doing and began adding my own twist on to things. It was fun, a hobby, a thing I did to stretch my creative muscles, a thing to learn on. A thing to think on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the fourteen years since I first began to blog, I’ve posted to my site at least a few times a year, often several times a month, and in a few bursts everyday for a couple of weeks. This year has been one of my most active on years for a long time, but most of that activity has been short posts or photos. There has been very little in the way of full blog posts, everything has been verging on the micro end of the scale. Whilst that’s fine, and has coincided with me using Twitter and Instagram less, over the last few months I’ve been fighting an itch to try and start writing a longer blog post a day (in the working week at least) but for whatever reason I’ve resisted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend I spotted a tweet from Austin Kleon in my timeline. He was &lt;a href=&quot;https://austinkleon.com/2017/11/20/a-few-notes-on-daily-blogging/&quot;&gt;linking back to a post he wrote&lt;/a&gt; just over a year ago after he had kickstarted his daily blogging habit. A couple of sentences in that post jumped out at me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I had no idea how badly my writing muscles had atrophied. After a couple of weeks, I could feel the sentences coming easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It began to sink in, that rather than thinking about trying to write a post a day, I should just get on and do it. It doesn’t matter really how good they are, the thing is to just get on and do it. But, I still managed to put the thought to the back of mind. Then I read the final point of his post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Maybe I’m weird, but it just feels good. It feels good to reclaim my turf. It feels good to have a spot to think out loud in public where people aren’t spitting and shitting all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I identified with that. The whole reason I started a blog fourteen years ago was because I wanted to. I enjoyed it. It felt good to have a place on the Internet that was mine, it was fun to have a hobby. So here I am, posting again. In a slightly longer format than I have been doing for most of the year. We’ll see how long it lasts, but the main focus, is to have fun and develop my hobby again.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/The-Blogging-Habit
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Bulletin Board</title>
            <link>
                /2018/The-Bulletin-Board
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve been reading Austin Kleon’s blog since January, I find the way that he speaks about his notebooks and how he uses them very inspiring. Today’s post is about his &lt;a href=&quot;https://austinkleon.com/2018/05/01/the-bulletin-board/&quot;&gt;bulletin board&lt;/a&gt; and how he pins images, clippings, index cards, and various other bits to it for inspiration while he is writing a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analog nature of lots of things that Austin does has really caught my attention. I love technology, but as a designer I also love objects and paper. When I was a student I covered the wall of my room in halls with bits of graphics that I liked. The whole thing turned into one giant collage of inspiration. That’s something I would like to get back into my creative life, something tactile and away from a glowing rectangle.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/The-Bulletin-Board
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Establishing New Habits Without Apps</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Establishing-Habits-Without-Apps
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to establish some new habits lately so &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjchilvers.com/blog/establishing-new-habits-without-apps&quot;&gt;this was a timely post&lt;/a&gt; from CJ Chilvers. I’ve been using the app Streaks like he mentions to keep focused on some of my habits, but there is a certain lack of accountability that goes with it. When a big streak gets broken it’s very hard to find the energy to start again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I’ve found a bit easier to face when starting—or restarting—a project is to break it down to months. Define the goal, decide to begin it at the start of the next month, and then make sure you’re ready to go in the time in between. The space allows you to process what you’re aiming to accomplish, and allows you the time you need to make sure you’re ready to get going.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Establishing-Habits-Without-Apps
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My Secret Battle – a Grief Shared</title>
            <link>
                /2018/My-Secret-Battle-a-Grief-Shared
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;This week I can across the blog is Simon Thomas. He’s a Sky Sports presenter and a Christian, known by many in the U.K. He lost his wife to cancer in September last year and has been blogging about his grief. This week he shared a post about &lt;a href=&quot;https://agriefshared.com/2018/02/09/my-secret-battle/&quot;&gt;his Secret Battle&lt;/a&gt; with depression and anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a very honest and open account of the battle he has, and still is, facing. I have a great admiration for anyone who is able to post so publicly about their battle with mental health. I have attempted to write many times about my own struggle with depression, it is not an easy thing to do. I’m thankful that Simon has a strong faith in God that is helping him through this time. My own faith helped me in my darkest time, and I have witnessed the faith of others close to me help them. I am forever thankful for this.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/My-Secret-Battle-a-Grief-Shared
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Quantity not quality</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Quantity-not-quality
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;There’s an odd pressure when you’re trying to exercise the muscle of discipline, it’s tempting to want everything you do as a part of that to be the best that it can be. Sometimes you need to just push through and exercise that muscle. When you’re starting out, quantity is often more important than quality. You need to get used to doing something regularly before you can focus on doing it better, otherwise the fear of &lt;em&gt;not good enough&lt;/em&gt; can hold you back and prevent you from making the progress you want to make.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Quantity-not-quality
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Book Budget</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Book-Budget
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I just added a new category in my YNAB Budget under Quality of Life Goals, it’s name? Books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I started using Goodreads in 2013 I’ve read 104 books. That’s an average of just under 21 books a year with a low of 17 in 2013 and a high of 34 books in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly I like to read, so it made sense to actually budget for these books financially since I’m already making time in my life to read them. There’s something very different about sitting down and relaxing with a good book compared to a film or boxset that I enjoy a great deal. Most of these books are fiction, I find they provide me with a good way of shutting my mind off at the end of the day by forcing me to use my imagination. I have to let my mind create the images that go with the words, converting the writers descriptions into visuals in my mind. The words on the page acting as the brush and my mind as the paint to create the large landscapes and cityscapes as well as the detail of the characters faces and the expressions they pull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until a few years ago I had gone a few years without reading a lot, I always had a novel on the go but the number I would read in a year was much less. Gradually as I got older and remembered how much I like reading the number would increase, but the intensity at which I devoured books became greater after I became ill with depression a few years ago. Throughout my recovery, and when I find my mood dipping again, novels become a great source of escape. Usually I find concentration hard when I’m battling a low period, but a good novel (often a familiar one that I’ve read many times) is able to provide me with some escape. Reading the prose of a good fantasy or sci-fi book allows me to find freedom from the circular thoughts and spirals of whatever I find myself fixating on. As a visual thinker letting my imagination build the worlds centuries away from today (in either direction) is a great way of exercising my creative muscles and preventing those unhelpful thought patterns take hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I’ve spoken to friends who have been struggling with similar mental health issues, I always recommend they read. It takes a bit of effort to start, but I’ve found it much more helpful than watching a film. The act of watching images develop on a screen is far less distracting than having to engage your mind with the words and story of a book. Reading, I find, is a form of active rest. I can let my body rest and recharge, while using my mind in a way that’s different from the work of my two jobs, and in so doing letting it refresh and recharge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s to books, to my new book budget, and to the many more hours of rest that they will provide.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Book-Budget
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Write More</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Write-More
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Cameron Moll &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cameronmoll/status/958849192113225728&quot;&gt;posted a thread on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; urging  people to write. Here &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cameronmoll/status/958849192113225728&quot;&gt;are&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cameronmoll/status/958849193224781825&quot;&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cameronmoll/status/958849194466275328&quot;&gt;four&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cameronmoll/status/958849195682639872&quot;&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt; quoted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve found it incredibly difficult to make time for long-form writing the past few years. When I have, the catalyst has been reminding myself of the tremendous ROI as a designer, manager, business owner, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you want to be a better designer, write more. If you want to be a better manager, write more. If you want to be a better biz owner, write more. You can also substitute “speak more” for each of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The act of synthesising what’s in your head for an audience of critics leads to increased analytical thinking, self-awareness, clarity, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Last but not least, you inspire others to write—or at the very least ‘write’ by joining the conversation you’ve started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s something I’ve been thinking about lots the last couple of weeks. I’ve been wanting to post to my blog more because I think it will be beneficial for me in many ways, one of which to help me build &lt;a href=&quot;http://philbowell.com/2018/thoughts-on-just-turning-up/&quot;&gt;discipline&lt;/a&gt; and self-control in other areas of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that really strikes me about this Twitter thread, the whole thing would make a good blog post. It probably would’ve been easier to post to a blog as well, likely have a longer life span, and consequently have more of an impact. Not all writing on a blog has to be long to have an impact, if it’s worth stringing four tweets together in a thread to make a point, it’s worthy of a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Write-More
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thoughts On Just Turning Up</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Thoughts-Turning-Up
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a little more about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://philbowell.com/2018/thoughts-as-nest-eggs&quot;&gt;link I posted&lt;/a&gt; to Austin Kleon’s blog the other day. I finished it with the line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Instead there should just be turning up to write down a thought and seeing where it takes you.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It’s a sentiment that you hear quite regularly around the Internet these days. Just keep turning up every day and do the thing—whatever your thing is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phrase turning up is just a less intimidating way of saying be disciplined. Turning up to write a blog post everyday is a discipline, just as reading your bible every day is or getting up without pressing the snooze button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I get older I’m understanding more and more that learning to be disciplined is one of the most important things you can do. It can effect every area of your life and it’s easy to assume that discipline is something that you have or you don’t. That you’re either able to be disciplined or you’re not, but that’s not the case. Discipline, I’m learning, is something you can develop. It’s like a muscle, the more you work it the stronger it gets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hard part, I believe, is not getting started but maintaining and developing. Everyone can start something, doing it for a couple of days before they get distracted or it begins to feel like work, and then stopping because it requires effort to continue. But that’s where you need to begin exercising that muscle of discipline, when things feel too hard keep going regardless, over time how hard it feels will disappear and instead it will become something you do each and every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So join me in learning to be disciplined. Starting tomorrow morning decide what time you’re going to get up, set your alarm and then get up when it goes off. No snoozing, no rolling over, just turn off that alarm and get up. Then do it the next day, and the next, until it becomes something you just do.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Thoughts-Turning-Up
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thoughts as Nest Eggs</title>
            <link>
                /2018/Thoughts-as-Nest-Eggs
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today when you say “nest egg” many think of money saved and put away, but a literal “nest egg” is a real or fake egg that you put in a nest to encourage a bird or a hen to lay more eggs there. So what Thoreau is saying is that by simply writing down a thought, you encourage more thoughts to come. When you have enough thoughts pushed together in the same space — a collage of thoughts, juxtaposed — they often lead to something totally new.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is the magic of writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Austin Kleon &lt;a href=&quot;https://austinkleon.com/2018/01/22/Thoughts-as-Nest-Eggs/&quot;&gt;wrapped up a recent post&lt;/a&gt; with the quote above. The post on one level is about journaling and writing in general, but do you know what else that quote describes? A blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blog is nothing more than a series of thoughts written down over a period of time. When you think about it that way it’s incredibly freeing.  There should be no pressure. Instead there should just be turning up to write down a thought and seeing where it takes you.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2018/Thoughts-as-Nest-Eggs
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A Home Screen Update</title>
            <link>
                /2017/A-Homescreen-Update
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I used to post a monthly series that looked at the Home Screens of my iPhone and iPad. Over time though I realised it didn’t change as much as I expected and so I lost interest in the process. Things have changed a lot recently so I thought it was time to post another look at my iPhone.
A few of weeks ago I put in to the practise the ideas in a post I &lt;a href=&quot;http://philbowell.com/2017/beautility-my-ultimate-iphone-setup/&quot;&gt;linked&lt;/a&gt; to about setting up an iPhone home screen. I dropped all my apps into one folder and popped it in the dock. Then I pulled Tweetbot, Messages and Mail out alongside it in to the dock. My intention was to try and use my iPhone less, and when I do use it, to use it productively for communicating with my friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks later I found myself with five apps sitting on a second page of my home screen. I kept the first screen blank because I wanted to keep as close to the idea as possible, but I wanted these apps available without having to search for them. They all fell into one category. Entertainment, or more specifically video services (iPlayer, YouTube, etc) to stream content to my Chomecast or Apple TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve now made another change and introduced 8 apps which I use so regularly it’s worth bringing them back to the my home screen to make accessing them more convenient. My iPhone still feels much calmer and focused than it did, but it’s not quite as a peaceful as a blank home screen used to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;left-bleed&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/homescreen-2017.png&quot; alt=&quot;My homescreen - 2017&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption-right&quot;&gt;Going minimal with my homescreens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the difference, I’ve gone from three screens with lots of app and folders on each, to two screens each with a clear use case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-dock&quot;&gt;The Dock&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve made a change to the three apps that sit in my dock. &lt;strong&gt;Tweetbot&lt;/strong&gt; remains, although I actually do all my posting to the service through this site, I still interact on the service a lot and find some great content to save and read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Messages&lt;/strong&gt; is fairly self explanatory, thankfully most of my friends and both my parents are iPhone users so I do a lot of communication through iMessage. It’s been a mainstay of my iPhone dock since the day I got my iPhone 3G years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third app is &lt;strong&gt;Things&lt;/strong&gt;. I’ve used a lot of to do apps over the years, for a long time I was a Things user, but it’s lack of OTA sync was a deal breaker and I moved to OmniFocus for many years. In the last year I’ve returned to Things via a stint with Todoist. In fact I was very happy with Todoist until the launch of Things 3. It’s just a pleasure to use and over the last few weeks I’ve found myself using it a lot more than I realised. Mostly to add things to my Inbox, but also when out shopping and running errands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;page-1&quot;&gt;Page 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fitbit&lt;/strong&gt;
Another fairly self-explanatory one, I wear a Fitbit pretty much everyday and it’s companion app keeps things in sync and helps me to keep an eye on how well I sleep and how much I’m moving. One day I hope to replace this with the Health app and an Apple Watch, but that’s a ways off yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YNAB&lt;/strong&gt;
Being wise with my money is something I am trying to be better at. I’m on a tight budget so making sure I’m saving and keeping money for various bills etc is really important. Since I started using YNAB I’ve found it to be really helpful and need it to check and add transactions too while I’m out and about. It’s the first budget app that’s stuck for me since Cha-Ching many years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overcast &amp;amp; Apple Music&lt;/strong&gt;
I listen to quite a few podcasts on varioius different subjects both while out and about and at home. When I moved some apps back to my home screen it made a lot of sense to include it in the eight. Apple Music follows similar logic, I like listening to music both out and about as well as at home. Usually it starts from my iPhone whether listening on headphones or over AirPlay to my living room speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instagram&lt;/strong&gt;
My photo sharing app of choice. Interestingly as I type this I’m considering moving it back in to the apps folder and replacing it with something else. It still sucks me in when I’m just futzing about with no real intention which is what I’m trying to stop myself doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Micro.blog&lt;/strong&gt;
Micro.blog is a fairly new service, I backed the kickstarter and have been using it since the launch of the beta. Over the last couple of weeks I’ve found myself using it more and more, to the extent that I’m considering whether it’s worth replacing Tweetbot with it in my dock. I don’t think it’s got quite enough activity on it for that just yet, but maybe in the near future as more people are able to join the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safari&lt;/strong&gt;
Again self explanatory, I search the web a lot. Far more than I realised and despite using Spotlight to start most searches it became more annoying than just opening the app and starting a search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mail&lt;/strong&gt;
It’s email, I get too much of it, I need to be able to at least keep an eye on it for communication. I don’t want to be sucked in to it too much so it doesn’t live in my dock anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;page-2&quot;&gt;Page 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This second page is purely for the apps I use regularly to watch content on my TV. In the case of these apps my iPhone becomes my TV remote. Triggering a cast from here turns my TV on and gets me straight in to the show or sporting event I want to watch. These apps are useful to be available without having to search, and keeping them on a focused second screen means they stay out of way for my general use during the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BBC iPlayer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now TV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Netflix&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BT Sport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall this has been a really interesting exercise that has helped me to really focus and consider how I use my iPhone. I hope to continue with it like this for a while. There’s just one thing I wish I could do, especially as I have small hands, and that is to be able to pin those eight apps to the two rows above the dock rather than at the top of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/A-Homescreen-Update
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A mid-year review</title>
            <link>
                /2017/A-mid-year-review
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Last week I was away at the CMJ Conference, I had the pleasure of joining them to take photos of the event, post to social media throughout it on their accounts, and to hear some excellent bible teaching in the process. It lasted from Friday afternoon to late Sunday afternoon, and by the time I got home I was absolutely exhausted. I spent most of the week recovering whilst trying to work and, thankfully, have spent most of this weekend doing some serious introverting at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday afternoon while I was sat on the sofa reading and watching Le Tour, it struck me that we are nearly at the end of July. We’re over halfway through the year and it seemed like a good time to review some of the goals I set out with at the start of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don’t know, I laid them out in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://philbowell.com/now/&quot; title=&quot;My now page&quot;&gt;now page&lt;/a&gt; at the start of the year, which saw an update in April. Whilst I didn’t make a post here about those updates, a mid year review of those aims seems like a good thing to make note of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Health &amp;amp; Personal&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my aims at the start of the year was to take better care of myself than I’ve done in previous years. I bought a Fitbit and set out to hit the 10,000 steps per day goal. That aim is going reasonably well. I’m hitting an average of 9,219 steps per day, which isn’t quite the 10,000 I’m aiming for. However when you consider that I’ve spent a total of 2 weeks taken out by illness (thanks former housemates for sharing your bugs) or my wisdom tooth operation when I barely hit 1000 steps a day, I’ll take it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of exercise, I was playing football most weeks until it stopped for the summer, although I wasn’t enjoying it quite as much as I had done. The couch to 5K plan hasn’t really happened either, running is something I do not enjoy, I find it frustrating and boring so easily become demotivated to do it. I have however been doing a Fitstar work out most weeks since May, although I confess that June/July has not been great on this front I’ve started that up again this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Faith&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to say that I am still working through the 5 Day Reading Plan. I’ve gotten behind a few times but never more than a week, and what’s more, I don’t find myself reading out of obligation but out of desire to keep reading The Word of The Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My use of the Prayer Mate app has also continued although much more spottily. I go through phases of using it everyday and then phases of only using it here and there. That’s ok though, it’s a tool after all and not an obligation or the only way to pray. The times I’ve used it well it’s been beneficial, but so have the times when I have not used it as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the memorisation of scripture, I’ve not been quite so good. The Verses app is still on my iPhone, but I haven’t used it as much as I hoped. I plan to be more intentional over the second half of the year to make use of this app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Freelancing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still continuing to do this, and in fact the last couple of months have been busy and very enjoyable. Please do recommend me or get in touch if you know anyone who might need some design work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;This Site&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am posting to this site more regularly, although the majority of the posts are small status type posts I have been able to post a few more considered posts. One thing I’ve noticed it that I am posting less links which means that more of the content here is original and not pointing to somewhere else. One thing I have decided to do is put less pressure on myself to post, it’s my site after all and so why should there be a pressure to put something here if I’m not feeling creative in that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also started another &lt;a href=&quot;http://phil.coffee&quot; title=&quot;Flat white &amp;amp; AeroPress&quot;&gt;side project&lt;/a&gt;, and I can’t decide whether to dual post here as well as there. In the mean time it will remain where it is and on Medium as a publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Reading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Goodreads Reading Challenge is on track. Of the 25 books I pledged to read I’ve read 13 so far and am a good chunk through 2 more. Once again the number of fiction books are outweighing the non-fiction ones, which is understandable as I read at the end of each day to help me relax, it is something I would like to be more even over the next half of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On reflection it’s been a pretty good first half of the year, both in terms of the goals I set out to accomplish and in some of the things that happen in life. My prayer is that the second will continue in this vein, perhaps with a bit more progress on the healthier living side of things than I’ve had so far.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/A-mid-year-review
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Workloads and Creativity</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Workloads-and-Creativity
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed over the last few weeks a distinct correlation between my ability to spend time on side projects and the amount of design work I have going on. Juggling a part time job in the Coffee House alongside running my design business makes for a distinct lack of energy to keep my side/personal projects going when things get busy. I find my motivation drops as my energy gets used up juggling the two, and it’s a source of disappointment since I know the importance of doing my own creative things on the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to be a matter of margin or focus, I’m yet to work out which, but my gut (which is usually right) tells my it’s about focus. When I become invested in a project it dominates my mind. It becomes what I think about when I’m not really thinking and I’ve certainly become aware that this is what has been happening of late. It’s the reason I’ve started &lt;a href=&quot;http://phil.coffee&quot; title=&quot;Flat white &amp;amp; AeroPress&quot;&gt;yet another side project&lt;/a&gt; that will operate on a schedule and is on a topic completely unrelated to any of my other side projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst having a project sit at the top of my mind is helpful for work, it’s not always helpful for me mentally. I need to be able to create things just for the sake of creating them. It brings me a joy and satisfaction that creating for a client doesn’t always bring. Eric Liddell once said&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
I believe God made me for a purpose, but he also made me fast! And when I run I feel his pleasure.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never thought about it in that way but I can certainly relate to it. Like Liddell I believe God made me for a purpose, but I know He also gave me a gift of creativity and a passion for design. When I use my gift, especially just for the sake of it and not just for my work, I feel His pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God created the world because he wanted to, because it gave him satisfaction and joy to do it (Genesis 1 v 31). He enjoyed walking in his creation and meeting with the people he created, which we learn from Genesis 3 v 9 when God goes looking for Adam &amp;amp; Eve. When I create something because I want to, I feel God’s pleasure because in some way I am mirroring Him and that is an incredible thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My God is the God of creation and He has given me the gift of creativity. When I use that gift to create I feel His pleasure and that’s why I need to firm my resolve to create for the sake of creating something because I want to create it.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Workloads-and-Creativity
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Haptic Architects Teach the Benefits of the Scandinavian Work Life Balance</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Scandinavian-Work-Life-Blance
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Work/Life balance is a thing many of us struggle with. I know when I was 100% self-employed it was the thing I struggled with most, there was always something I felt I should be doing. Whilst many people claim that doing what you love means you have a perfect work/life balance that seems far to idealistic to me. Work is work, whether we love what we do or not and we need a good balance between it and the rest of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems Haptic Architects have that same awareness, and so I was interested to read about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.designweek.co.uk/issues/22-28-may-2017/haptic-architects-teach-us-benefits-scandinavian-work-life-balance/&quot;&gt;the Benefits of the Scandinavian Work/Life Balance&lt;/a&gt; that they have implemented in their design studios. It seems a healthy approach to work and demonstrates a real awareness and care towards their employees.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Scandinavian-Work-Life-Blance
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Walking</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Walking
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Back in January 2015 when I realised I was ill, and consequently started a course of antidepressants, many people encouraged me to exercise. I had been a keen cyclist and they encouraged me to keep at it and get out on my bike as much as I could. I was told, and in fact read many times, that exercise was a great way of countering some of the symptoms of depression. My issue was that the thought of going out on my bike caused me anxiety and stress, both things which I was trying to avoid and so I dismissed the notion as not for me. Nearly two and a half years later I’m starting to understand a little of what the mysterious &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; were talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a month ago I moved into a new flat, one which I’m living in on my own, it’s great to have my own space again. As a consequence of that move I’ve been doing a lot more walking. It’s located in such a place that I can walk to pretty much everywhere I need to go on a regular basis. I can walk to my shifts at the coffee house, my church, a couple of supermarkets, as well as the centre of town, and I’ve been doing that as much as is practically possible. It’s become a time that I enjoy, an opportunity to pop my headphones in and listen to some music or catch up on a few podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of weeks I’ve begun to notice something, when I don’t get my daily walks in my mood suffers. The realisation has come home to roost this bank holiday weekend. On Saturday and Monday I didn’t really go out. I stayed home in my flat tinkering on my websites, making a few adjustments, watching some TV shows, what most people call relaxing. And it has been just that, but today I noticed the heaviness creeping in, it made me realise what effect going out for a walk has on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not just the small amount of exercise that a brisk walk provides that I’ve missed today, it’s the intentionality of going for a walk. Instead of the day just passing by, the act of walking to work is intentional and provides an element of structure to my day. I need to schedule in the time for my walk to work otherwise I won’t get there on time letting people down. It helps that my walk to work is a pleasant one down an old railway line, that’s what’s in the photo at the top of this post, for a moment I can be lost in the wonder of looking at the trees and greenery as I walk. It provides a chance to look at God’s creation and see how the same place changes from day to day. It’s a chance to walk and listen to some new music or the latest podcasts, in my own little world that’s outside in the wider world. It’s a chance to pop the headphones out and walk listening to the birds and rustling of the trees. When the sun’s out it’s especially enjoyable, but even on a rainy day I look forward to my walk to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost by accident I’ve discovered that the act of walking to work provides me with a moment of calm. In that walk there is nothing I can do for my design business, nothing I need to do for my coffee house shift, no tweets or Instagram photos to catch up on (unless I want to walk into my fellow walkers or be run over by the many cyclists), I can just enjoy the simple act of walking.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Walking
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Employment vs. Self-Employment</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Employment-vs-Self-Employment
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Occasionally I’ll come across an article on the internet that I find myself reading more than once. Usually it’s because the piece resonates deeply with me, but sometimes it’s because it’s something I want to be able to write myself. In this instance it’s just that, a piece I would like to be able to write in a years time, but with my own perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a piece about &lt;a href=&quot;https://garrettdimon.com/2017/employment-vs-self-employment/&quot;&gt;Employment vs. Self-Employment&lt;/a&gt; Garret Dimon wrote this paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Being self-employed is great. And it’s not so great. Like anything, there are tradeoffs. For you, the tradeoffs may be worth it. Or, they might not. Or, they may not be the right tradeoffs at this point in your life. Just don’t put self-employment on a pedestal. There are plenty of other options that are darn near self-employment without the burdens.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been on both ends of Employment and Self-Employment. For the last 5 years I’ve been running my own design business, and during the last year and a half of that I’ve been running it alongside another job in a coffee house. I’ve loved every minute of it, but it’s also been the most stressful time of my life. So stressful that it made me ill. The last couple of months I’ve been thinking about and making steps to begin looking for a full time design job working for someone. Through it all I have to keep reminding myself that self-employment is not the be all and end all, there is &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of important work being done by many different people and companies that it will be a privilege to be a part of.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Employment-vs-Self-Employment
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Seth Godin Blog Daily</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Seth-Godin-Blog-Daily
            </link>
            <description>
                
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;title: Seth Godin Explains Why You Should Blog Daily
—
With the arrival of Micro.blog my interest in my blog has picked up considerably. It’s always been there bubbling at the back of my mind, but actively posting micro posts to it has me once again looking to post other content more regularly. CJ Chilvers linked to an article by Seth Godin that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjchilvers.com/blog/seth-godin-explains-why-you-should-blog-daily&quot;&gt;Explains Why You Should Blog Daily&lt;/a&gt; resonated deeply with me and the growing desire to post to this site more regularly. It’s both a creative outlet both and a mental outlet that I know will be good for me. I intend to mix the content I post between links, quotes and original articles/thoughts alongside the afore mentioned &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.blog/philbowell&quot; title=&quot;My Micro.blog&quot;&gt;micro posts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Seth-Godin-Blog-Daily
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Deep Prayer &gt; Deep Work</title>
            <link>
                /2017/Deep-Prayer-Deep-Work
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of talk on the internet circles I follow about focus and deep work. They’re thought provoking and often resonate with me, but there’s one thing I’ve been struggling to reconcile in it all. The focus of all these discussions is usually aimed at putting your individual desires first, which doesn’t really jive with my Christian beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris Bowler, in his excellently considered article &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisbowler.com/journal/deep-prayer&quot;&gt;Deep Prayer &amp;#62; Deep Work&lt;/a&gt;, seems to demonstrate I’m not alone. In doing so he seems to capture exactly how this kind of thinking should be influencing my approach to my faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
But over and over, I come back to the fact that while Newport’s concept of increasing our ability to focus is crucial to a successful career, it’s even more crucial to a successful Christian life. One that is lived attuned to the Spirit. One that is carefully watching to see where God is working, then ready and willing to join him in it.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2017/Deep-Prayer-Deep-Work
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Dedication Olympics</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Dedication-Olympics
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;As I sit writing this the BBC are showing their roundup video of the Rio Olympics. Normally when it comes to the Olympics I’m pretty glued to it for the few weeks that it runs. This year, maybe due to the time difference, it took a week or so for me to get in to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only when the track cycling came on and Team GB started to win medals that I started to watch. The success of the British team on this field is mind-blowing, every four years the team hits form perfectly and brings home gold medal after gold medal. Similarly, the success of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alistair_Brownlee&quot; title=&quot;Alistair Brownlee&quot;&gt;Brownlee&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jonny_Brownlee&quot; title=&quot;Jonny Brownlee&quot;&gt;brothers&lt;/a&gt; in the Triathlon, so consistent year after year resulting this year in the first triathlete to retain the gold medal. Then there’s Andy Murray, only weeks after winning Wimbledon, retaining his gold medal. Not to mention the many other athletes who’ve won medals for Team GB, helping us as a nation to finish second in the medal table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most years by the end of the games I’m inspired. I want to try a new sport, or return to an old one I used to play. This year is a bit different. I’ve not been inspired to go and do sport, but instead by the dedication that unites these athletes. Each and every one of them has a level of dedication that blows me away. They are able to apply themselves for every single day between olympic cycles. For four years they are able to focus their energy on one thing so that they can give themselves the best possible shot to win that gold medal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During one of the events one of the commentators picked up on this. I don’t think it was what he meant, but the way it came across as he spoke of it was that these athletes seem to have a gift none of the rest of the world does. Not in terms of their sporting prowess, but in their ability to apply themselves and dedicate themselves to their chosen discipline. It’s an easy mindset to fall into, but it’s also a dangerous one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discipline or dedication is not a thing that we just have, it’s something we can learn. Each and everyone of us can learn discipline and self control in order to focus on something. In order to grow and develop into a great writer it takes dedication and discipline to turn up and write each day. For the artist it takes hours of painting, the musician hours of playing their instrument. Dedication is something we can grow in and get better at. The more we dedicate ourselves to do something, the more likely we are to do it. For the olympic athlete, turning up to training on a wet Monday morning in November makes them more likely to turn up for training on a wet November Tuesday, Wednesday and Thursday. Likewise, writing a post for this blog on a Sunday makes me more likely to want to write one for tomorrow. I don’t want to break the chain or waste the time I spent the day before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many people are want to say on the internet at the moment, the key to everything is &lt;em&gt;showing up&lt;/em&gt; everyday. The key to winning a gold medal is showing up everyday with an unrelenting dedication to your sport. The key to growing in dedication to our chosen discipline is the same.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Dedication-Olympics
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Finding Your Bliss Station</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Finding-Your-Bliss-Station
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;There’s so much stuff on the internet that it seems like an impossibility that you would read something at exactly the time you need to read it. Austin Kleon’s recent article about &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@austinkleon/finding-your-bliss-station-436290c4da03&quot;&gt;finding your bliss station&lt;/a&gt; has managed to achieve just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around a year ago I was just finishing up a course of counselling aimed at helping me understand the depression I was diagnosed with in January 2015. One of the things I learnt about myself was my need to do creative things for myself and how over the year prior to my diagnosis I had stopped doing that. This evening as I read Austin’s article it hit home a little further, I might’ve lost my cave a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week has been a tough one, the first tough week for a while which is something I know happens to everyone now and again. A giveaway sign, which I’ve realised as I write this, is the recurrence of the word introvert in a lot of my snippets/tweets. I’ve been craving time on my own, and that usually happens when I’m starting to feel a bit unbalanced in life. It’s a little clue that I might’ve lost my bliss station, or cave as I’ve referred to it in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What’s clear is that it’s healthiest if we make a daily appointment to disconnect from the world so that we can connect with ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In counsellor speak this is called &lt;em&gt;self care&lt;/em&gt;. We need to take time out to take care of ourselves, to stop ourselves being bombarded by the world around us. To find a place that frees us from the stresses of work, from running a business and working for someone else at the same time. From being around people all day, to having a few moments to our ourselves each and everyday. To take a little bit of time to do something we want to do just because we enjoy it and it helps us feel free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Sunday evening I plan to have reclaimed my cave from the dumping ground it’s become, and in the spirit of making better use of my calendar I plan to schedule in a time everyday for me to be in it just because I want to create some stuff for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Finding-Your-Bliss-Station
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Depression Days</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Depression-Days
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Sometimes a day hits you when things that are normally easy to do become the hardest things. I mean simple things like getting out of bed, going downstairs and making a coffee. That’s the nature of depression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it happens you have to find ways of getting through because giving in to it can be crippling. Giving in can be the start of a downward spiral, a spiral you don’t want to be in and that can take a long time to get out of. That’s a place you don’t want to go. Instead you have to find a way to push through, to stop the down from taking over. What that looks like is the tricky part, but for everyone there is way of doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Depression-Days
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Desire to Tinker</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Tinker
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;The desire to tinker is strong in this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have this problem when it comes to my blog. The more I start to post to it, the more I want to tinker. The more active I am on the site, the more I notice little things I don’t like and want to fix. The more I post to it, the more I want all my internet posting to originate on it. It’s like an illness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s something I’ve always struggled with, and I confess it’s a side to blogging that I enjoy. The trouble is, the more I tinker the less I post. The more I craft the design, the less time I spend writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a battle, although one I’m sure I do not face alone. It’s not just the battle of a blogger, it’s a battle of a designer. Most of the tinkering I do is design related, little details and quirks in my theme which I notice but very few others will. I also know from experience, that I will get to the point where I’ve caught the little tweaks I need to and they will be fixed. Then it’s just a case of resisting the bigger things I’d like to do. Or at least knocking off the major ones first, like finding a way to post photos here and on Instagram, displaying them in a way I’m happy with. The key though, is to keep the posts flowing. Keep to my challenge of posting everyday, and getting through the tinkering stage until I get to the point where I’m just posting each day and all my published content originates here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or is it just a pipe dream? Should I just keep posting and ignore the little bits that nag?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I know I can’t just ignore the nagging. I’m a designer, I like details and its in my nature to keep refining bits until they’re gone. To keep crafting until they as close to perfect as can be, it’s just important to keep the perspective, to keep in mind that perfect doesn’t exist. It’s about getting things to good enough whilst keeping on posting each day and building momentum so that the writing takes over the tinkering and becomes a creative outlet in its own right.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Tinker
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My Blogroll in 2016</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Blogroll
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Back when I first started writing on the internet – ok it’s called blogging, ugh – I discovered a lot of blogs through the sidebars of those I was reading. The trend at the time, way back in 2006, was for each blog to feature a Blogroll. A collection of links to the blogs of other people that the author of each site either knew personally or who simply enjoyed those other sites. It was a great way of finding new blogs to follow and it’s sad that the practice seems to have pretty much disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be ten years since I started my first blog, and with it my first Blogroll, but I figured it was time to revive it. What follows, in no particular order, is a list of blogs which I read regularly on a wide range of topics. I hope there are some you haven’t come across and that you to will enjoy reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shawnblanc.net&quot; title=&quot;Shawn Blanc&quot;&gt;Shawn Blanc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisbowler.com&quot; title=&quot;Chris Bowler&quot;&gt;Chris Bowler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thenewsprint.co&quot; title=&quot;The Newsprint&quot;&gt;The Newsprint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.manton.org&quot; title=&quot;Manton Reece&quot;&gt;Manton Reece&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cjchilvers.com/blog/&quot; title=&quot;CJ Chilvers&quot;&gt;CJ Chilvers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://john.do&quot; title=&quot;John Saddington&quot;&gt;John Saddington&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.desiringgod.org&quot; title=&quot;Desiring God&quot;&gt;Desiring God&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thegospelcoalition.org&quot; title=&quot;The Gospel Coalition&quot;&gt;The Gospel Coalition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mbs-p-b.com&quot; title=&quot;Mike Bates&quot;&gt;Mike Bates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brooksreview.net&quot; title=&quot;The Brooks Review&quot;&gt;The Brooks Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://birchtree.me&quot; title=&quot;Birctree&quot;&gt;Birchtree&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://christianross.net&quot; title=&quot;Christian Ross&quot;&gt;Christian Ross&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://initialcharge.net&quot; title=&quot;Initial Charge&quot;&gt;Initial Charge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://paulstamatiou.com&quot; title=&quot;Paul Stamatiou&quot;&gt;Paul Stamatiou&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ugmonk.com/blog/&quot; title=&quot;The Ugmonk Journal&quot;&gt;The Ugmonk Journal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://oneofthethirsty.com&quot; title=&quot;My friend Nim&quot;&gt;One of the Thirsty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leaves2.wordpress.com&quot; title=&quot;My mum, Alison Bowell&quot;&gt;My mum!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Blogroll
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Permission</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Permission
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;At the start of last week I set myself the challenge to blog everyday between then and the end of the year. Yesterday I didn’t manage to post to this site, in some people’s eyes I’ve failed the challenge already. Maybe I have, but it’s not going to stop me carrying on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These types of challenges are great to do, they add an extra bit of impetus to get going on something you want to do. A little bit of healthy competition goes a long way. But yesterday life happened, two friends got married and the day was rightly taken up celebrating that. There simply wasn’t time in the day to sit down and write a post for this site, it was an exception to the norm and that’s ok. I realised this early on and gave myself permission to have a day off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years ago had I set myself this challenge I would’ve let it defeat me. The chain would’ve been broken and I would’ve let the day off turn into two, three or four days, before giving it one last effort and then stopping it. Over the last year and a half I’ve learnt that sometimes it’s ok to give myself permission to say, it’s just not going to happen today. As long as it doesn’t turn into a regular occurrence that’s perfectly OK, I just pick up where I left off the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been an important lesson for me to learn, perfect is unattainable and being somewhat of a perfectionist it’s a difficult thing to accept. Now in the context of this challenge, had I realised earlier in the week when I started it, I’d have written an extra post in the week so I had one in the bag and didn’t break the chain. In the context of real everyday life, it’s a far more important lesson to learn. I’ve had to learn how to give myself permission to say this is ok, this is good enough and I’m ok with putting it out there.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Permission
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Kill Your To Do List</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Kill-Your-To-do-List
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Here’s what’s always bothered me about task management systems: it’s not what Presidents use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never thought of &lt;a href=&quot;http://cjchilvers.com/blog/kill-your-to-do-list&quot; title=&quot;Kill Your To Do List&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; before. It’s never even crossed my mind about the methods of working for people in high powered positions, or national office. Yet it &lt;a href=&quot;https://uk.pinterest.com/pin/81416705736990410/&quot; title=&quot;Lincoln&#39;s Routine&quot;&gt;shouldn’t be&lt;/a&gt; a surprise when you think about.
After reading this excellent article from CJ Chilvers it struck me that in the last few months this is something I’ve started to do subconsciously.When I think back to how I’ve progressed some projects recently it’s all been down to clearly blocking out time on my calendar and then working during those times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course I’ve not entirely scrapped my to do list, and I think it would be wrong to scrap it completely. It’s a useful tool for keeping track of the client projects I’m working on. The important thing, I think, is to not let your to do list dictate your time and instead to let your calendar dictate your to do list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The calendar doesn’t lie. It’s brutal about how much time you actually have in a day to complete your projects. It’s honest. We need to stop wishing, determine what’s important enough to spend our very limited time on and get it scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Kill-Your-To-do-List
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>You’re Not Meant To Do What You Love. You’re Meant To Do What You’re Good At.</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Do-What-Youre-Good-At
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do what you love&lt;/em&gt; has been a bit of a mantra of late on the internet, at least on the blogs I seem to have been reading over the last couple of years. It’s something that I love the sentiment of, but at the same time something that has never quite sat properly with me. So when I saw the phrase &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/personal-growth/youre-not-meant-to-do-what-you-love-you-re-meant-to-do-what-you-re-good-at-4e8e6b8e929d#.a8cjyap2r&quot; title=&quot;You’re Not Meant To Do What You Love. You’re Meant To Do What You’re Good At&quot;&gt;You’re Not Meant To Do What You Love. You’re Meant To Do What You’re Good At&lt;/a&gt; in a tweet link to the matching article I instantly saved it to my Instapaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree entirely with this point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’re doing people an incredible disservice by telling them they should seek, and pursue, what they love. People usually can’t differentiate what they really love and what they love the idea of. But more importantly, you are not meant to do what you love. You are meant to do what you’re skilled at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trouble comes when the people who are espousing the mantra of do what you love are the fortunate few who’s skill also happen to be what they love. It gives them a distorted view that everyone should be doing this and it creates a worldview that doing work is a bad thing unless it’s something you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The husband of an old colleague of mine had a period of unemployment not long after they got married. It really impacted him as a person and I remember talking to my colleague about how her husband felt worthless because of it. He wanted to work because not working made him feel worthless. When he did get a job, it was not in something he loved, but it gave him meaning again. He was contributing to society, not reliant on it. He was giving something of himself to do it and what he was doing had value because of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Christian I believe we are designed to work, God even designed and modelled the week around it six days of work and one day of rest (Sabbath). The theologian Tim Keller in his book &lt;em&gt;Every Good Endeavour&lt;/em&gt; states&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Work is as much a basic human need as food, beauty, rest, friendship, prayer, and sexuality; it is not simply medicine but food for our soul. Without meaningful work we sense significant inner loss and emptiness. People who are cut off from work because of physical or other reasons quickly discover how much they need work to thrive emotionally, physically, and spiritually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is exactly what my colleague’s husband experienced. Without work he struggled in exactly the way Tim suggests we will. When we fall into the trap of telling people to only do what they love, we do a disservice to work. For some people their work involves doing what they love, whilst for others it involves doing what they are skilled at. For some, maybe even the majority, it involves doing a job because it gives them value and helps them serve people around them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article finishes with this quote which I think sums up the value of work, of any kind, superbly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The real joy of daily work is in what we have to give. We are not fulfilled by what we can seek to please us, but what we can build and offer. It is not fame, or money, or recognition that makes for a thoroughly meaningful life, it is how we put our gifts to use. It is how we give.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Do-What-Youre-Good-At
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>What Do You Write About?</title>
            <link>
                /2016/What-Do-You-Write-About
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I know what you’re thinking. It’s only the second day of the challenge I set myself, to post to my blog everyday from now until the end of the year, and already I’m asking the question of what do I write about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would imagine it’s a familiar story to anyone who’s decided to undertake such a challenge. Going from barely writing or posting to your blog to posting everyday it’s only natural to find yourself wondering what to write about. If I hadn’t been here before it would be a big worry, it might even be so discouraging that I would just abandon ship straight away. Whilst this morning when I decided it was time to write today’s post I didn’t have anything in particular I wanted to write about I know that if I keep going and posting each day I will eventually end up with too many subjects to write about. It’s the nature of the beast, the more you do it, the more ideas you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of different tactics that I’ve come across over the years that are aimed at helping you come up with subjects to write about. Unsurprisingly none of them have ever worked for me, but there is one thing that does. I know it works because I’ve demonstrated it in other parts of my life, be it reading my bible or doing the work for my freelance business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showing up every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I am, showing up. A new sheet in Ulysses, my headphones in and I’m writing. In fact through the course of writing this post I’ve already come up with the topic for tomorrow’s post. There it is in action. Showing up today has triggered the process. The more you do something the more idea’s you have, the first step is showing up.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/What-Do-You-Write-About
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The 2016 Blogging Challenge</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Blogging-Challenge
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve written 442 posts on this site. The first one was written on 17th January 2011, that’s five and half years ago. It equates to around 80 posts per year and about 1.5 posts per week. It’s not bad going, but it could be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During those times there’s been many spells of inactivity and many spells of multiple posts per day, this is what I would like to change most about my site, the inconsistent posting patterns. Last night I found myself browsing the web in a way that I’ve not done for a long time. I ended up on a rabbit trail of personal blogs, one that started with a site I subscribe to that I kicked off into safari on my iPad. It felt like rediscovering the internet again. This was what got me into the blogging scene way back in 2005 when I started my first blog. There was a line in one of the articles I read that resonated with me. It was feedback that the author received regularly,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Stopping blogging regularly was one of people’s biggest regrets. I certainly wish I hadn’t stopped. Or I should say, I wish I hadn’t let the habit slip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I started blogging way back in 2005 I’ve had two main sites. The first site, which sadly is no longer in existence, lasted from 2006 until this site started in 2011. It was my first proper foray into internet publishing and as a result I didn’t really think too much about what I would post. Topics were wide in range but naturally reflected my personal interests, something which I feel has been lost a bit on this site. Which is somewhat ironic given that this is the site which bears my full name in the url.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind it’s time to declare that this is the first post in a new challenge I’m setting myself. I want to recapture the joy that I had when I first started publishing on the web. It was something I enjoyed and did everyday, and so, that’s my new challenge. I want to post to this site everyday until the end of the year. Some will be links, some will be original writing, but all of it will reflect me and my interests. I’m going to try my utmost not to pick and choose too much of what I write, I will simply write and post each day from now until December 31st.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Blogging-Challenge
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>One Twelfth</title>
            <link>
                /2016/One-Twelfth
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;We’ve done it. All of us. Good job everyone. We’ve made it through January and we’re into February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always find January a bit of an odd month, it’s full of the initial hopes and dreams of the year ahead, yet it’s a hard slog. We spend the first week getting back into the swing of things, the second week doing our utmost to get new patterns of behaviour, thinking and habits off the ground. The third week pushing through the struggles of motivation, or lack there of; and the final week looking towards pay day to give us a glimpse that the slog has been worth while; and then before we know it, we’re into February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;February always feels like a month of transition. The weather and days start to show glimpses of spring, the evenings get noticeably lighter and we start to look forward to summer. Those new habits we tried to establish in January either live or die. We either stick by them and they become established, or they whither and die while we slip into our old established ways. Admitting defeat we move on convinced we’re never going to accomplish what we want to this year, resigning ourselves to another year of nearly but not quite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s make this year different. We’re a twelfth of the way through the year, and there’s 11 more months to go. It’s never too late to establish new habits, or find the focus we need to move on and make the year live up to the hopes we had at the start of January. Change doesn’t happen in 4 weeks, it takes work and turning up everyday to make things happen. The 21 days that it takes to establish a habit has only just passed, keep turning up and those days will turn into 42 and a well established pattern of behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write this post as encouragement to myself as much as to anyone who reads it. Don’t give up, focus and push through. Turn up and do the work, you never know what you can achieve, I’ll leave you with the words of Chef Gusteau from the Pixar film &lt;em&gt;Ratatouille&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you focus on what you left behind you will never see what lies ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/One-Twelfth
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Holocaust Rememberence Day</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Holocaust-Rememberence-Day
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Today marks the 71st anniversary of the liberation of Auschwitz-Birkenau, a place which is known world wide for the atrocities that our Jewish brothers and sisters faced during the Second World War. Atrocities that I didn’t know the depth of fully until I visited Yad Vashem in Jerusalem on my first visit to Israel a few years ago. Reading through the account of the holocaust in that place made me feel physically sick, I knew from my history lessons at school that it was a massive operation but I had no clue of the depth of it. No clue of how far it went in terms of the dehumanising treatment the Jews had to endure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly in today’s society we are again seeing the rise of anti-semitism. It takes different forms, whether it’s through the BDS movement or jihadi attacks in both Israel and Europe, this is what they are and to call them anything else forgets the beginnings of moments in history like the holocaust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is a day we must remember, especially in the current cultural climate, and stand side by side with our Jewish brothers and sisters. As a child of Christ I have an even greater responsibility to stand with Israel and show them the love their Messiah has for them.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Holocaust-Rememberence-Day
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Just Hit Command-N</title>
            <link>
                /2016/Just-Hit-Command-N
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Just hit Command-N. Those are the words I just read in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.manton.org/2016/01/tim-cook-swift-and-the-return-of-blogs.html&quot; title=&quot;Tim Coo, Swift and the Return of Blogs&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; from Manton Reece, and so that’s what I’m doing. I may not be a developer or someone who’s had much of an audience in my life on the Internet. However, for the last few weeks I’ve wanted to start posting to my site again but for whatever reason I’ve never known what to write. So here I am pressing the plus button in Ulysses on my iPad and writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember when I first got in to the whole blogging way of things. I wasn’t really selective about what I wrote about, I would just write whatever came to me. Of course there was a set of themes that would be covered, but they weren’t chosen with intention, there were just what my interests were. They were me. Since discovering Manton’s blog towards the end of last year I’ve been reminded of my early blog and the early blogs of those who I still follow. They were genuine and full of interesting things because they weren’t overly focused, they were just personal sites. Of course those sites, at least the ones that are still going, are still interesting but they’ve become more focused over time. Although that focus may have happened by a natural evolution as people found what really makes them tick, those sites are interesting in a different way now. Thankfully what I’m starting to see, and what I hope I continue to see, is more variety and new sites that are personal and reflect the whole of the person who writes them. That’s what drew me to this hobby we call blogging, and it’s what I hope will help me return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s to new beginnings, to starting to write more and to being less bothered about what I should write about and instead just posting what feels right.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2016/Just-Hit-Command-N
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Let me make a note of that</title>
            <link>
                /2015/Let-me-make-a-note-of-that
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Ever since I got my first iOS device, a 2nd generation iPod Touch, I’ve been on a quest to work out the best way to take notes. I’ve tried a shed load of different apps, Simplenote, Evernote, Notesy, the built in notes app, NVAlt… in fact if you can name it I’ve probably tried it. I’ve always read with interest articles on note taking setups, how people use them, how their go to app on their iPhone works so well for them, and I’ve always struggled to figure out how or why that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see I’ve tried so many times to get into the habit of using an app, or a suite of apps, to make my notes in. But for whatever reason I’ve never been able to stick with one. I’ll go through a spell of forcing myself to use them, to form a habit so that my first thought is to use my phone or the Mac app, but they never stick. I can never get to the point where I can declare, so and so is my goto note writing app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except, now that I think about it, I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goto for notes sits right beside me on my desk. In fact for the whole of my working life it’s sat right next to me on my desk, or in my back pocket. What’s it called?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well it’s called paper, or a notebook, and I make my notes on it with a pen. Try as I might I can not break the habit of using a physical notebook to make my notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The habit stretches back to my school days. I always had a notebook, or the back of my exercise books, which I would doodle and scribble in. Then when I was 16 I started a Saturday job in a family run hardware store which further ingrained the habit. I always needed a piece of paper and a pen in my pocket, to make a note of measurements, stock numbers, phone numbers, delivery addresses, you name it and it was on my note paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then when I started uni the habit continued, my sketch book was always with me. I’d use it to make note of ideas for projects, to record comments from crit sessions with my tutors and when I got the odd freelance job, to make notes from client meetings. The way I use my notebooks has barely changed since then. When I meet a client I take my notebook and my iPad, but it never feels natural to pull out my iPad to make notes (I use it to show work). It does however feel natural to pull out a pen and jot down some comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s something about the convenience of a notebook and pen that an app and my iPhone just can’t break. The technology, which on the surface presents a far more superior experience doesn’t seem to be able to break the hold a nice notebook and pen has over me. With my iPhone I can make a note, I can tag it, it’s automatically dated and I can search to easily find what I need. It should be the best way of making notes. Except it isn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tapping out a note on my iPhone, just doesn’t give me the mental connection that I need when making a note of something. It may be less efficient, in the sense that it might take me a little longer to find a note because I can’t search for it, but I do (generally) remember where on the page I wrote it and over time I’ve developed little quirks to help make things stand out. Tasks get a little box to the left of them, if I think it’s important when I write it, it’ll either get a star or often a box drawn around it. Information gets segregated on the page by lines, but more often than not, the simple act of writing it down is enough to commit it to my memory. It’s something which, in this digital world we now live, I fear we will lose. Processing something in an analogue manner can have a far more lasting effect than doing something digitally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also something rather nostalgic about using a notebook and pen. I have every single notebook from my professional life as a designer on a shelf. I can pick them up and look back to a certain moment in time and have an instant connection. I can remember where I was, who I was with and what was going on in my life at the time. Some of them are all neat and look like they’ve barely been used from the outside. Most of them are nicely worn, weathered with age they bulge in the middle. But I think most importantly, they present a physical instance of the work I’ve done in my life. The vast majority of it is created on my Mac, sure some of it’s printed, but the ideas and beginnings of it all are in my notebooks. You don’t get that with a list of files on a computer screen, you don’t get little sketches or doodles that seemed like nothing at the time but which turned into a substantial piece of branding. The throw away moments that are so commonly created in a notebook don’t even get considered in a notes app. Those are the very moments I can’t give up, the very moments I won’t give up. They’re the very moments that bring the best out of me and my pen and notebook are the most powerful tools I own.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2015/Let-me-make-a-note-of-that
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Archives</title>
            <link>
                /2015/Archives
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Back in October of 2014 I wiped this blog and started all over again in an attempt at a fresh start and the beginning of more regular posting. The lack of baggage was supposed to be the catalyst to help me post, to a degree it has worked and I’ve been posting here much more regularly since the turn of the year. The Week in Links has helped, and is approaching it’s six month anniversary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday evening I read a &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulstamatiou.com/10-years-blogging/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;post by Paul Stamatiou&lt;/a&gt; about his years of blogging. I was struck by a particular sentence half way through:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The era of the personal website is over. It’s now just a personal landing page with a photo, bio and link to a Twitter profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand exactly where he is coming from, but I also disagree, to a certain extent. It’s true a lot of websites have disappeared over the last few years, but over the last few months I’ve seen a resurgence in the personal site/blog. Something that I want to be a part of. It got me thinking about my own personal site, and the changes it’s been through over the last decade. I’ve never binned it to replace it with a personal site, but I did recently delete all my posts and before that I had another blog that has gone the way of the Dodo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It struck me how wrong that is. I put a lot of time and effort into writing those posts, and for them to be erased is just plain wrong. Fortunately I managed to locate a backup of this site from just before I wiped it, and I’ve now added all the posts back into the archive. There’s still a bit of tidying up to do but for the most part the archives now extend all the way back to January 2011. I’m also hoping to be able to locate an old backup of my very first blog, the one that existed prior to this one. I’ve been writing on the internet for nearly a decade now, it should be preserved and maintained in some form or another not consigned to oblivion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this to say, I’ve added the archives back to this place. If you’re interested and have the time, why not have a dig through and see what you can find.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2015/Archives
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Be Yourself</title>
            <link>
                /2015/Be-Yourself
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I can’’‘t remember how I came across the article &lt;a href=&quot;http://ift.tt/1E152hD&quot;&gt;Be Yourself&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Nahumck but I instanty saved it. I’’‘ve read twice since then. It resonated with me, in fact the tweets by Aaron Mahnke which triggered this article resonated with me. But most of all, this quote is what I connected with the most. Never have I been more aware of the true meaning of this quote than in the last six months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I think for most, being yourself is one of the hardest things to do as a human. It takes a lot to get out of your own way, remove the internal barriers, and open up your world to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2015/Be-Yourself
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Bored</title>
            <link>
                /2015/Bored
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I wonder how often the phrase &lt;em&gt;I’m bored…&lt;/em&gt; came out of your mouth as a child? I know it crossed my lips a fair few times, during my years at primary school. As I grew older the phrase appeared less and less, in fact I can’t remember the last time that phrase crossed my lips and I don’t recall it ever crossing them in my years since university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s troubling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does it mean I’m no longer getting bored? Do I get bored and no longer acknowledge it preferring to let myself while away the hours fiddling around on the internet or vedging out on the sofa?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I capable of getting bored or does the constant gratification provided by the various apps on my iPhone prevent it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in a world where constant gratification of boredom is readily available. A world where children are growing up with iPhones and iPads available to them as soon as they are talking, if not before. Will these children be able to get bored?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are worthy questions to consider, if people can no longer get bored, and I mean really bored. How will creativity flourish? Creativity out of boredom is a different kind of creativity to that which takes place at work. Boredom creativity is far stronger and more expressive than any other. When we are so bored that we decide to do something because it interests us, that’s when some of the most exciting creativity happens. A child who picks up a guitar and starts picking/strumming a song simply because they are bored isn’t playing that guitar for practise, they’re playing it with a desire to create. A desire to occupy their mind and to express themselves in a way they’ve perhaps never done before. The same goes for an artist who picks up a sketch book, and a writer who picks up a pen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is as much a challenge to myself as it is to anyone reading this. Do we allow ourselves to get bored? To get so bored we are compelled to do something productive out if it. Are we capable of letting creativity born out of boredom take place, or do we just occupy our minds with the latest free game on the appstore that’s taking Twitter by storm?&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2015/Bored
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Building</title>
            <link>
                /2015/Building
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’m great at making statements and promises about things that I want to do. It’s easy. I think of something I wish to do, decide there and then a means by which to do it, then post to my blog declaring it in the public domain.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
In principle it’s a good tactic. The public declaration should be enough of a motivation to make sure I stick to something, but the reality is that more often than not I fall short. I might stick to it for a couple of weeks, but then life will happen and that’s it, the idea slides out of existence. Why? Because of a lack of discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to discipline I’ve generally been quite good when it comes to doing something that really matters, or something that I have to do. The trouble was when it came to doing something I wanted to do, like writing for this site. So as part of getting back into it, I’ve been taking little steps, to build integrity, trust and discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Integrity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building integrity with myself is critical. The number of times I’ve set out with an aim to do something, then not succeeded to do it are countless, and this carries over into starting new things. Whilst the intention and desire can be strong, the belief that I can do it less so. It’s been erroded by years of unfulfilled promises to myself about starting to write on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trick, I’ve discovered is to start small. It’s not a new technique, but I testify that it’s starting to work. I started with The Week in Links, my weekly post sharing a few links to good articles or interesting things that I’ve seen around the internet over the week. As of the time of writing, I’ve now posted an edition of that post for nineteen weeks running. I’ve built integrity with myself that I can post to this site on a regular basis, on a schedule I decided and wanted to commit to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Trust&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I have built some integrity and belief that I can do something I want to do and not just something I have to do. I’m building trust in myself that I can actually do it. I trust that I can manage the rest of my day well enough, to be able to set aside time to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Discipline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trust in myself that I can do this, builds the discipline that I need to actually do it. Having established a pattern of turning up each week to post The Week in Links, I’m now disciplined enough to carve out that time each week to make sure I keep doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a knock on effect, or maybe more of a circular cycle. The more belief that I have in sticking by my stated intentions, builds the trust I need to be able to make those intentions in the first place. In turn, that builds the discipline I need to execute those intentions, thus giving myself more belief. It’s why this week I’ve added another step into my morning routine so that I can be sat here at my desk and do a half hour of writing before my work day begins. Not only am I building trust that I can work on writing for my site with regularity, I’m also building trust that I can get up and go through my morning routine with the time to do all that I both want and need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course there is another side to this. If I do miss one of my carved out writing slots, I must not give myself a hard time about it. Life happens and I won’t always get to do these things. When that’s the case I need to be able to say nevermind, reset and go again the next day remembering that for the past however many days I’ve been able to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2015/Building
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Barriers</title>
            <link>
                /2015/Barriers
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Barriers are a strange thing. In the real world they exist to form a separation, a physical division between two things. They can be permanent or temporary, but they exist for a specific reason. Their purpose though, is always the same, to prevent you from going somewhere you shouldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mental world things are slightly different. Barriers exist of course, but for different reasons, though their purpose is similar to their real world counterparts, they stop you going somewhere or doing something. The trouble is, they aren’t physical and that makes them immeasurably harder to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eighteen weeks ago I started posting a &lt;a href=&quot;http://philbowell.com/category/week-in-links/&quot;&gt;weekly article with a collection of links&lt;/a&gt; to interesting articles I’ve read during the week. I started it because I wanted to get back into writing for my blog. I thought having a regular post to commit to would remove the barrier that I seemed to have errected over the last couple of years. To a degree it’s worked, posting to my blog regularly has helped me to rebuild my interest in it, it’s helped me to establish a desire to post, but it hasn’t removed the barrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last few weeks I’ve started each week with the aim that this week would be the one that gets me writing a post a week. Several times I’ve drafted something, but each time I’ve failed to publish it. Fear seems to be the barrier preventing me from clicking that button. That little voice that says &lt;em&gt;No one will read it, no one really cares what you have to say&lt;/em&gt; squarks away as my mouse hovers over the publish button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve decided, this week &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; going to be the week that I breakdown that barrier. The little voice &lt;strong&gt;will&lt;/strong&gt; be silenced and I &lt;strong&gt;will&lt;/strong&gt; post an article every Wednesday from here on out. It is a challenge, but one I want. I have no idea what I will post about, but as Shawn Blanc says &lt;a href=&quot;http://shawnblanc.net/2015/06/you-have-ideas/&quot;&gt;I have ideas&lt;/a&gt; it’s just a case of letting them grow and taking a bit of action on some of them, regardless of whether they are good or bad, as well as having a bit of courage to press publish at the end of it.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2015/Barriers
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Rediscovering the Personal Site</title>
            <link>
                /2015/Rediscovering-the-Personal-Site
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;It’s been an interesting start to the year to say the least, but one positive from it has been the renewal of my interest in both my own blog and the blogs of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been reading blogs, or personal sites would probably be a more accurate term in 2015, since I came across them in my second year at university in 2006. Back then I loved the idea of people publishing something to the internet and quickly set my own blog up. I came across a number of great writers who like me were just finding their feet in the world of Web 2.0. In the 8 years that have passed since then, I’ve had a number of my own blogs and lost my motivation/desire to post to them all at various points in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early days of the blog, there was what felt like a strong community. A group of people writing about what interested them in a way which was new and exciting. It was inspiring to see others sharing in this way and it made me want to do the same. In the years since I left Uni in 2007 there seemed to be a change amongst the blogs I read. They became focused and somewhat same-y in their content, it felt like the blogs lost their personalities as their authors pursued a desire to be better writers. A few of them managed to maintain the personality that drew me to them in the first place, but, many didn’t and as a result the blogs either died off or my interest in them waned. It was sad and with that homogenising of content my own inspiration and desire to write also dried up.
Over the last few months I’ve started to notice something different. Perhaps it’s just that my own mindset has changed, or it could be that I’ve been finding a bunch of new sites, or a reaction to the likes of Facebook who seem to want to be the internet rather than part of it. But the personal site seems to be rising like a phoenix from the flames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the sites are specialised, with focused content, but they no longer seem to be of one voice talking about the same thing all the time. They have personality. The posts, whilst often being focused around a similar subject, are varied and seem to be a reflection of the people who write them. It’s both inspiring and a joy to read these sites. They might be writing about a pen, a notebook or a new Mac, but they are doing it in a way which is interesting and engaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These personal sites have the polish and high standard that the web in 2015 demands, but they seem to be returning to the personality and interest that was so apparent in the the rise of the blog back in the mid naughties. It’s refreshing and I’m thankful for it. I applaud those behind it and I hope it continues long into the future.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2015/Rediscovering-the-Personal-Site
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thirty Things I've Learned in Thirty Years</title>
            <link>
                /2014/Thirty-Things-I've-learned-in-thirty-years
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;When the year turned 2014 I began to reflect on my life, who I am, where I am and what I’m doing. Why should a simple year change cause such a mood to dawn on me? At the end of September I turned 30, it also happened to mark the 10 year anniversary since I left home and moved to university here in Cheltenham. These are two significant events in my life that mark the beginning and end of the last decade, one which has been full of happy times and inevitably it’s fair share of low times. Rather than this become a telling of the story that has been my twenties, I thought it more productive to look at, if I can, thirty things I’ve learned in the last thirty years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faith is important.&lt;/strong&gt;
Where you put it and in whom you put it has the biggest influence on your life and how you live it. Don’t waste it by putting it into things or people, they will only let you down. Instead, place it in Jesus, He is the only firm foundation that will never go away or let you down. My Faith has helped me through both the highs and lows of the last 10 years in a way which is incredibly hard to describe, but rest assured I will never place it in anything other than Christ.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Family matters.&lt;/strong&gt;
In just over the last 10 years (I know I’m breaking the rules slightly) I’ve lost 4 grandparents, they are all missed greatly and especially so when big events occur. If you have grandparents spend time with them. Find out about their life before you existed, who they were, what their dreams were when they were your age. Listen to them and invest in them as much as you do your parents and brothers and sisters. One of the things I treasure most is a letter my Granddad wrote when I was 11 telling me his experiences of the 2nd World War. When I read it I learn as much about my Granddad in that letter as I did when he was alive to speak to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friends.&lt;/strong&gt;
They will come and go, you will keep in touch with some, you will drift away from others, there’s often nothing you can do about this (although often there is). Make the most of them while you can, go out of your way to help them, support them in all they do and in any way you can. You may never know how much it means to them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s ok to be an introvert.&lt;/strong&gt;
I used to, in fact I sometimes still do, struggle with the fact that I am a naturally quiet person. At school, even at uni, I used to see people who can easily strike up a conversation with someone they’ve never met before and feel like there was something wrong with me because I find it so hard to do. It’s taken many years, a lot of reading and thinking, but the realisation that I get my energy from deeper friendships and not from a room full of strangers has been incredibly freeing. The trick is to not let this become a crutch when in a room full of strangers, I still need to work on stepping out my comfort zone, but at least I know what that zone is.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t be afraid to tell your friends what they don’t want to hear &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; don’t be offended if they don’t take it on board&lt;/strong&gt;
My best mate has never shied away from giving the kind of advice I don’t want to hear. I’ve not always acted on it, but on reflection months later I often find it was very good advice. I hope I’ve returned the favour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be vulnerable&lt;/strong&gt;
I don’t mean go spilling your heart out for all and sundry, but getting to know people properly means you have to be vulnerable. It sometimes means sharing elements of your life you may not be very proud of, but it means your friends will be able to support you in ways you really need, and it means you’ll find out who your friends really are.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smile&lt;/strong&gt;
Don’t be so wrapped up in your own world that if you randomly make eye contact with someone you panic and look away. Instead, smile. Not a forced one, a genuine one. It’ll make people feel like they matter and that they’re not a repulsive monster.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work isn’t the be all and end all that people make it out to be&lt;/strong&gt;
If you’re happy in it great, keep going. If you’re not, put your all into it no matter how down you feel about it. You will probably meet more people through work than through anything else in your life and people can tell if you don’t like your work, but people can tell more if you don’t like it and don’t care about it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Alone&lt;/strong&gt;
I’m not being anti-social when I disappear off to my room/office. Time alone is incredibly valuable, too much of it can be a bad thing, but not enough of it can be very dangerous. It’s ok to want to just spend time alone, doing my own thing. In fact I crave it sometimes, and when I don’t get it I can be touchy, cranky, less enthusiastic about things and just generally drained.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not Knowing is OK&lt;/strong&gt;
It’s ok to not know where you’re going. The world is full of people who give the impression they know exactly what they’re doing and where they’re going. Reality is they’re probably just as lost as you are and just bumbling along in a slightly more concealed way than you feel you are.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Having a Plan is OK&lt;/strong&gt;
Expecting that plan to work out exactly how you want it to and the world to be a nice fairy tale ending isn’t. That plan you had for your life at the age of 20 is very unlikely to work out, that’s ok. Recognising you are not as in control as you think you are is a good thing. Surrendering to God and his plan is even better. Often it will take a big event to make you realise this, but it will bring you out the other side in a better position.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t be too introspective&lt;/strong&gt;
I realise this one is somewhat ironic coming from a guy who is looking back at his life and inward at himself as he reaches what feels like a significant milestone. It is important to reflect on life, the universe and everything, but doing it too often is a bad thing. It sets you up for failure as you inevitably compare yourself to your friends, the plan you had when you were 20… we are broken people and we naturally look at the negative in these circumstances. For every introspective moment, take a minute to look at the now, you’re healthy, God has blessed you with another day on his beautiful creation, you have people you care about and who care about you. Dwell on that for a moment, then go and enjoy the day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust&lt;/strong&gt;
Trust people. This is, on some level, linked with point 6. You can not be vulnerable with people you don’t trust, but equally you can not get to the point of vulnerability without trusting someone first. So trust people. Don’t be naive, there are people out there who will abuse your trust to get something they want. In my experience, you’ll work out who they are before it’s too late and the ones you don’t, you’ll learn a lot from. In those cases it will be painful for a while after, but in the long run probably worth it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t let fear beat you&lt;/strong&gt;
That girl you’ve got your eye on, go speak to her. Don’t let the fear of what might happen, or the fear of failing stop you from doing things. Stop thinking of the negative what if’s and focus on the positives. Go, do and learn. This isn’t easy. In fact of all the things in this list it’s probably the thing I struggle with most and it’s also probably the thing I get most frustrated about because I have no clue how to beat it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be disciplined&lt;/strong&gt;
You’ll never get what you want done in life without being disciplined in some way. Without a bit of discipline you’ll spend most of your time doing what’s easy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read&lt;/strong&gt;
When I was growing up I used to read a lot. When I got to my twenties what I was reading changed from books to websites. The last couple of years I’ve been actively trying to reverse that change. I still read blogs, but I’m picky about which ones and I make a lot more effort to read books (and my bible). Books have more substance. They’ve taken hundreds of hours to write, been refined over and are written by people who are experts about the topic they’re on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think&lt;/strong&gt;
Think about things. Think about topics of importance, take time to dwell on them and to understand them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t apologise for who you are&lt;/strong&gt;
You’re who you are because God made you that way, don’t be ashamed of that. I’m thirty and have grey hair. I’ve never once, despite the recommendations of some of the youth I’ve worked with on beach mission in Wales, been tempted to dye it. God made me and He said I was “very good”. Why would I try and change that?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drink lots of water&lt;/strong&gt;
The last couple of months I’ve consciously been trying to drink more water. It’s had an interesting effect, I’ve felt more alert and able to concentrate much better. My skin has been clearer and I’ve lost weight as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop checking Facebook at every available opportunity&lt;/strong&gt;
Just don’t. Your life will be better off without the constant stream of people filtering their lives to make themselves feel better.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep a journal&lt;/strong&gt;
I wish someone had encouraged me at the age of 20 to keep a near daily journal. There have been several spells over the last few years where I’ve kept a journal. Most of those times have been to help me through difficult times. One day I might read them, but I’d much rather read them and be reminded of happy times and fun times that will help me when I’m going through the difficult times.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speak to your friends&lt;/strong&gt;
That might seem like something that goes without saying, but bare with me. We live in a world that relies on technology so much that it’s tempting to fall into the trap that it’s the best method of communication. My best mate lives 4 hours drive away, in fact for the 9 years that I’ve known him we’ve only lived in the same place for 2 years. Had we just relied on technology (Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and the odd text) to keep in touch we likely wouldn’t still be the friends we are. Friendships can only be maintained over a distance by putting in effort to speak regularly. Pick up the phone and give your friends a call. Speak to them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laugh&lt;/strong&gt;
Find people who make you laugh. Find people who will laugh with (at) you when you do something stupid. Find people who will do things stupid that you can laugh with (at).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise&lt;/strong&gt;
Don’t just sit on your backside all day, get the endorphins going. Get on your bike, go for a run, walk really quick, whatever, just exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pray&lt;/strong&gt;
You spend time with friends, so spend time with God.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have perspective&lt;/strong&gt;
Don’t just look down at your feet. If you’re so focussed on the now, you’ll forget what’s been and miss what’s to come. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Look up. Look back. Look forward.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; This was the phrase I ended the student bible study with last week. Look up at God because you belong to Him for He bought you at great cost. Look back at Christ and remember what He did for you on the cross. Look forward to the day when Christ will return in glory.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sleep&lt;/strong&gt;
Get enough sleep. If I don’t get enough sleep I get tired (well duh). I can’t concentrate on my work, I lose focus when talking to friends, it affects me in many other ways and I see it in others as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organise yourself&lt;/strong&gt;
Make lists or use a todo app, but do whatever it takes for you to be organised. You’ll never do all the things you want to do if you don’t know what you’ve got to do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shoulders back, head up&lt;/strong&gt;
It’s amazing how many people I see walking down the street looking at the ground or staring at their phones. Get your shoulders back and your head up, be confidant and move with purpose, the very least it will do is make you feel confidant. It also means those people with clipboards are less likely to bother you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen&lt;/strong&gt;
Be willing to listen to other people’s thoughts and opinions, especially if they are opposite to yours. Show respect to what they are saying and they will show respect to you when you share your opinion. Never shut people down with a blanket statement that dismisses their opinion as wrong and closes down any discussion, it is neither productive nor constructive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2014/Thirty-Things-I've-learned-in-thirty-years
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Fresh Start</title>
            <link>
                /2014/Fresh-Start
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;It dawned on me today that I’ve been writing a blog, in one form or another, for the last 8 years. Initially, I was full of the youthful enthusiasm of someone who had just discovered the medium, I could easily sit down at my Mac and within half an hour have published a new post. Within a few months I had found a number of other bloggers who wrote with a little more quality than I did and with a little more discernment when it came to topics they wrote about. They had built a bit of a larger audience than I had, but with some their encouragement I pushed on regardless. By the time I graduated university in 2007 I had built an audience of around 300 subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a decent number of subscribers, but bore an unfortunate consequence. The number of subscribers caused me to stop enjoying my blog. I wanted to provide value to my readers, say profound things. I felt I needed to bring a focus to my blog in order to do that and I began applying pressure to myself. Eventually falling into the beliefs that the posts I was writing weren’t good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things dried up and I stopped writing until my blog eventually died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then I’ve been trying to regain the blogging vigour I had when I first started. I just can’t seem to shake the pressure that what I write has to be amazing. I haven’t been able to break the fear of posting to my blog.
I’ve even made things more complicated. When I first started blogging, I would just write whatever came into my head. It would get a tag or two and then be posted. But when I started to struggle I began to seek out solutions to make posting easier. I added linked list posts, so I could just post a link and a little bit of commentary. Then I added quotes, and soon after photos. But it never really worked, rather than making things easier, I had really just added a level of complexity that I didn’t need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started working for myself, I thought I would quickly begin blogging again. I hoped I would be able to add another creative outlet, one that I had once found so valuable. The trouble was, I didn’t know what the blog was for. Was it for my business or was it personal. It had my name on the domain but I wanted it to grow so that awareness of my business would grow. Consequently nothing really changed and, despite a few spells of posting links, it’s largely sat dormant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;starting-again&quot;&gt;Starting again&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last two months I’ve finally started to use an app that’s been on my iPhone for most of the last two years. I’ve begun to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://dayoneapp.com&quot;&gt;Day One&lt;/a&gt; in a way that has bought me to a place that I want to write. Almost every evening for the last 2 months I’ve written an entry in Day One that has been tagged “3 Things”. Each post consists of 3 things that I’m thankful for from the day that has just passed. Occasionally the entries get an image, sometimes they get expanded on and I add some thoughts about whatever I’m thinking through at the time. One thing that it has helped me with, is finding that I’m starting to enjoy writing again. Starting to want to blog once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s with this in mind, that I find myself here. Starting again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve reset my blog. Gone is the archive of posts that are made up largely of links. Gone are the multiple categories and post types along with the complicated theme they needed to look different. Gone are any other bits of cruft that have built up over the years. Instead, posts are now posts, categories don’t exist and posts will likely be tagged. The site structure is simple, there’s the home page and the posts. An archive and an about page will follow at some point, but for now there are just posts. The theme is simple and clean, designed to be read and for any photos in the posts to look good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some ways it’s a sad and disappointing move. I’ve deleted an archive of work that has taken a few years to build up. But I needed to take away the burden of expectation, I didn’t want anything to feel like it didn’t fit what had come before it. I didn’t want a barrier to my blog and it felt like my blog itself had become that very thing.
So this is the new PhilBowell.com, it’s my blog and if you’ve made it to the end of this post I’d like to say thanks for your time hope to see you again soon.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2014/Fresh-Start
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Resolutions and Intentions</title>
            <link>
                /2013/Resolutions-and-Intentions
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;At the start of every year, I, along with millions of others around the world, make resolutions. We decide, often quite flippantly, to do certain things. It could be to change a habit, lose weight, or to get fitter and just “be healthier”. But 99% of the time they are lofty goals that last only a couple of weeks, a month or maybe six weeks if you really try hard, but they rarely last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I began thinking about my resolutions for the year, I made my usual trip to the dictionary for a definition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
res·o·lu·tion
noun
• a firm decision to do or not to do something.
• a formal expression of opinion or intention agreed on by a legislative body, committee, or other formal meeting, typically after taking a vote.
• the quality of being determined or resolute.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It struck me that a resolution is much more than the lofty ambitions we make at the start of each year. They are intentional. A committee will not vote a formal resolution into place without having a firm intention to follow through with it. Yet very often we determine what our new year’s resolutions will be simply by a fleeting desire or a momentary decision. We base them on nothing more than what we think is going to be a beneficial thing for us to do. We’re not intentional in our thoughts and often do not stand firmly behind our decisions, evidenced by the same resolutions recurring year after year. In stark contrast, a real resolution is intended, it has purpose, it is designed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
in·tent
noun
• something that is intended; &lt;em&gt;purpose; design;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A resolution is pointless if we have not considered why. Why do we want to get up earlier? Why do we want to use our time better? Why do we want to be fitter? All of these are good things but why do we want to do them? If we decide to do these things without thinking about the real purpose, they will never stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make them stick, we must go further than think about why we want to do them. Once we have a firm motivation in place, we must design that resolution using our motivation as a basis. As it says in Proverbs chapter 14 and verse 15:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&quot;A simple man believes anything, but a prudent man gives thought to his steps.&quot;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we resolve to just do something without thought we not only waste time, we waste our intentions and we waste energy. It’s hard enough to gain momentum when beginning a new thing that has a clear motivation, but gaining momentum on something without a clear aim or goal? That’s likely to end in a failure which has an impact on other plans we make. Once we are discouraged by something it’s very hard to recover the confidence and enthusiasm that we need to start something. The memory of failing at one thing lingers at the back of our minds and saps at what little confidence or belief we have about the new thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this as it approaches the second half of January, and you’re struggling to stick to the resolutions you made only a couple of weeks ago, I encourage you to stop for a moment and ask yourself why you wanted to do them in the first place. If you can’t find a concrete answer, maybe it’s time to reconsider. So many times I’ve heard someone declare they want to do something, but because of a lack of a defined destination they struggle, become discouraged and lose all motivation. A complete waste of that initially well placed intention. Don’t waste that limited supply of energy you have trying to build momentum behind something that’s just a shallow thought. Instead put it into a resolution that has a destination, something that has value.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2013/Resolutions-and-Intentions
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Do you like to shave?</title>
            <link>
                /2012/Do-you-like-to-shave
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I like to shave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask most men my age, their late twenties, that question and its usually met with a snort. An upturned lip. A look that says “are you serious?” without words passing their lips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact if you asked me that question a few years ago I would’ve responded in much the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what changed I hear you say? My approach changed. When I moved into a flat to live on my own for the first time I became much more aware of how I spent my money, every penny suddenly counted much more than it ever had. Spending several pounds on a can of shaving gel had to stop. So I bought a cheap shaving brush and a puck of soap that I knew would last far longer than the shaving gel ever had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That small change began something. Since it took me a bit longer to have a shave I started to relax, to take my time with it. I began to see shaving as a time to pamper myself and relax. I started to enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a couple of years, and although I’ve had an electric razor for quick shaves during the week, I’ve always enjoyed my Saturday morning wet shave. Once again an awareness of how I spend my money has prompted another change in my shaving set up. I ran out of cartridges for my Mach 3 and on going to buy some new ones, the cost floored me. I can’t spend £13 on 8 razor heads which will last me only a couple of months before threatening to pull the skin off my face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took to Amazon to find out if they were cheaper, they weren’t, but one of their handy suggestions based on other peoples purchasing habits was. I’m not talking slightly either, I’m talking £9 for 100 blades. A grand total of 9p per blade and according to the internet (means it’s true right?), each blade should last me 5 or 6 shaves. That’s about 2p per shave. So I took the next step in my shaving career and bought a double edged safety razor for £20. That means in just over 6 months I’ll be saving money and in 2 years time I’ll still be using the same pack of blades. Brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But do you know what’s even more brilliant?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy shaving even more now. I have to take even more time with it, making two or three passes over my face. I’ve had to relearn how to make a lather, turns out I was doing it wrong but the Mach 3 didn’t show it up. In fact I’ve had to relearn how to shave entirely, but it hasn’t been a chore. I now shave 3 times a week, using similar tools to my Granddad who I remember getting up early to shave in the kitchen sink. He used to take his time, I never understood why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shaving isn’t a chore. It’s a relaxing, soothing treat, and a great way to start the day, or finish it if you’ve had particularly stressful one. In fact it’s more than that. It’s a pause, a moment in time where I’m not thinking about anything else (I tried it once; blood everywhere), it’s an opportunity to give my mind a rest and just enjoy the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2012/Do-you-like-to-shave
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The One Where I Announce I'm Now Self Employed</title>
            <link>
                /2012/The-One-Where-I-Announce-I'm-Now-Self-Employed
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;There are some posts you dream about writing, posts you’d love to write but never think you actually will. This is one of those posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I wrote a post about change. Changing the way I approached something has lead to exciting guidance and a big change in my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started with a conversation with two very good friends of mine. One asked how work was, then followed it up with a query about what I really wanted to do. The other laughed, asked me a question, set me a challenge and then held me to it. That question lead me to writing the last post about a change of approach, a change which, thanks to Gods guidance is leading to a leap of faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the leap?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday 3rd August I worked my last day in full time employment and spent my last day living in sunny (!?) Slough. The following day I moved to Cheltenham, again. A place I attended university and a place that I love being in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that move came a change of employment. I am no longer a rat running a race, but instead a man working as a business owner. I’ve finally taken the leap into self employment. Relying on the Lord to supply me with enough work to put food in my stomach and to pay the bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time it’s been my ambition to work for myself, even while I was studying at Uni I knew ultimately I wanted to have my own design studio. It nearly happened straight after Uni after a little encouragement from my tutor, but I knew it wasn’t really the right time. There was a lot I still had to learn, well let’s face it there still is. I’ve now been in full time employment for 5 years. I’ve grown a lot, I’ve changed a lot and I’ve learnt a lot. I’ve experienced working for a small company and I’ve experienced working for a larger company. Both were good experiences that taught me many different things, but underneath there was always this desire to have my own company bubbling away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m delighted to say that has now happened. I’ve had a little holiday, moved to a new (old) place and am at the end of my first week of self employment. It’s exciting, a little daunting but feels like the best decision I’ve made. Except that I didn’t make it, God showed me the door and I pushed it. Now I’ve got to continue pushing doors, keep faithful to Him, and work as hard as I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next couple of weeks I’ll be able to introduce you to a new name and a new website. Of course this place will still exist and I hope to increase the level of writing, and hopefully build on some friendships that I’ve established through my blog over the years. It’s an exciting adventure, I hope you’ll join me on it!&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2012/The-One-Where-I-Announce-I'm-Now-Self-Employed
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Change</title>
            <link>
                /2012/Change
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;For the last few years I’ve been praying about something. I’m sure many of you have as well, but this particular &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; has occupied my prayers for several years. I’ve been praying about it in the same way for pretty much the entire time, asking for guidance and direction in relation to the &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt;. During that time the urge to do that &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; has grown. One could say its developed into something close to a permanent longing, something that left me unsettled because I’m not doing it and I’ve never really known why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent conversation with a very good friend left me feeling challenged. He asked me a question and laughed at my response because it’s been the same response I’ve given him for the last few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My response of course was to question why he was laughing at me, I guess feeling like he wasn’t taking me serious. His response was one which caught me off guard. Instead of answering why he was laughing, he simply asked me how I had been praying about this &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt;. I told him and after a moments pause he responded with a challenge. Why don’t you pray about it in a different way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He commented how that as I have been praying for guidance this &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; had grown in to a passion and longing, that is to say something more than momentary desire, then maybe I’d had that guidance and it was time to challenge it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for the last month I’ve been praying more earnestly and in a different manner. Instead of requesting guidance about the &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt;, I’ve been praying: Lord, I think you want me to do this, please show me if I’m wrong.
The results have been breath taking, surprising and exciting all at once. A change of events has begun that, I believe, God is using to lead me into doing this &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; I’ve been praying about for the last few years. I’m a little apprehensive, but the over riding feeling is one of excitement. This post is not an announcement, &lt;strong&gt;yet&lt;/strong&gt;, but maybe more of a watch this space…&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2012/Change
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>I Miss My Cave</title>
            <link>
                /2012/I-Miss-My-Cave
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;man cave&lt;/em&gt; 
  noun Informal .
  a room or other area in a home that is primarily a male sanctuary, designed and furnished to accommodate the man&#39;s recreational activities, hobbies, etc.
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.reference.com/browse/man+cave&quot;&gt;Dictionery.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my latter years at school while studying my GCSEs and A Levels I began to understand the need for a cave. Of course still being at school and living at home I had a ready made one - my bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a teenager in the early days of developing an interest in design, that cave allowed me to create the atmosphere I needed to work. I had a drawing table set up where I would work on creative pieces and study for my exams. It had a light that bent over me shining a focused beam on my work space and plunging the rest of the room into darkness. I had some of my most productive evenings at that table. In fact I have long standing memories of working on my graphics coursework close to a deadline with the masters snooker on my little tv and that light beaming a zone of creativity onto my table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving to uni I again had my own ready made cave. The room in my halls of residence quickly became the place for all my creative work. Angle poise shining on my desk, laptop on, a dark room and momentum building music on late in to the night. Then the bedroom in my shared house in the final two years at uni and the first year in employment had a similar feel, but replacing my laptop with my iMac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-miss-those-caves&quot;&gt;I miss those caves.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I’ve been living on my own I’ve not really had a cave. A flat with a living room, kitchen, bathroom and bedroom doesn’t really lend itself to creating one. The living room is a place for relaxing, eating and hosting visitors. The bedroom is for sleeping and relaxing, I need it to be purely for that else I’ll never shut down properly to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-quest-for-a-cave&quot;&gt;The quest for a cave&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I’ve no space for a desk and no closet I could convert into a cave I’ve been exploring ways to create an environment that can be quickly and easily set up, then easily removed when I have visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always tried to zone my living room so that I have a lounge area and a dining area. The dining area is the only bit of my flat that I can sit down and do work at and so it’s become the centre of my quest for a cave.
The table lamp which used to sit on my dining table has been removed and replaced with my angle poise. My laptop now has a home on the table and my wired Apple keyboard and Logitech mouse have come out of storage. All of them can be quickly packed away when visitors are around and for the first time in a few years I’ve been able to begin creating that cave like atmosphere as I work by the light of my angle poise. I can even do it with my iPad instead of the laptop should I wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst it’s not quite the same as a permanent cave, it’s a step in the right direction until I’m able to afford a place with room for a permanent cave. Most importantly it’s already having an impact on the way I’m working in the evenings on my own projects as well as on personal freelance clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the lesson that I’ve learnt, in this little exercise is that actually it’s not necessarily about having a physical space, it’s about atmosphere. In order to foster creativity I need the right atmosphere, a permanent place makes that easy to create but the quest for my cave isn’t really for a physical space at the moment. It’s about a way for me to recreate the atmosphere of my early and original caves. It’s about developing a method that allows me to quickly set up at my dining table and focus. Events over the last few weeks have caused me to realise specifically that by my very nature I’m a night owl and not an early bird. Maybe that has something to do with my atmosphere…&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2012/I-Miss-My-Cave
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Reading Stories, Food for the Imagination</title>
            <link>
                /2012/Reading-Stories-Food-for-the-Imagination
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I work as a graphic designer. Like many other folks in my profession I find it hard to turn off. I may not be thinking about projects from work all the time, but I’m always thinking about projects I’d like to do or reviewing the things I see all around me. I see every piece of design and mentally critic it, 99% of the time I’m not even aware I’m doing it, but it’s there, almost like a 6th sense wondering what questions the designer faced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve lost count of the number of times I’ve sat in a restaurant looking at the menu only to realise I’m not looking at what’s on offer but the way it’s been typeset. What font did they use? What does it make me think of the restaurant? Does it make the food I’m reading about sound even tastier or does it make me think I’ll be left wanting more? Does the menu fit the surroundings or does it just feel like a designer somewhere threw it together because he didn’t get a proper brief?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a pretty constant state of affairs. Right now I’m glancing at the empty can of San Miguel thats sitting on the dining table. Does it look like the taste? Does it make me want to lie on a hot beach in Spain? What the heck has a ship got to do with beer? Why did the designer pick gold as the main can colour and break away from the green and white that used to be there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t turn it off, and many a time I’ve amused good friends as I verbalise my critique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately relaxing is made all the more harder by it. I read to do my relaxing, mostly the blogs of a select few but they’re people who I’ve come to trust. I trust that the links they post are to interesting content, articles that can lead me on a chase around the internet looking at websites, new websites. Websites that start the inner critic on it’s familiar chain of questions. Questions that lead me to find another way of reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly made of paper that smell of ink and aren’t displayed on a screen. However, in this age of constant stream of information that feeds a thirst for knowledge, growth and understanding, I find I need a book that doesn’t make me think too much. There’s no point going to bed to read only to lie in bed for hours thinking about the chapter I just read and the challenges or knowledge it imparts. I need a good story. Something that will make me keep turning the pages, compelling me to read. So it is with great joy in the last year or so that I’ve discovered an author I enjoy, one that draws me to read rather than watch inane tv shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not the novels that I write this about though, it’s the impact they have on &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt;. As well as helping me relax, they force me to use my imagination. When reading about the unravelling story I’m forced to imagine the scene, what people look like and where they are. I’m forced to stop asking the questions I ask all day long as I review and work on the various projects I have on the go. That time away from questioning and evaluating can only have one impact as far as I’m concerned, that is, to make my work better. Having time to just imagine frees me from the constraints that are so often put in place when working. They may be imposed on me by the projects, or by the presssures I put on my self, but the more I read and use my imagination in a completely unattached manner. The more creative I feel, the more my imagination is fed the more easily I find work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a time when the people around me seem to read more than they ever did, I seem to be the only person among my friends who reads novels. I’d like to encourage you to start. Take a short story and read it. Start small and find something that feeds your imagination, a story which gives it new life and see what impact it has on your work.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2012/Reading-Stories-Food-for-the-Imagination
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Wecloming 2012 and Setting a Few Targets</title>
            <link>
                /2012/Wecloming-2012-and-Setting-a-Few-Targets
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;It’s that time once again when many people are posting reviews of the year just passed. I always enjoy reading these posts, seeing the people I follow who have achieved all that or more than they hoped to whilst hoping those who didn’t are able to in the coming year. I’m always drawn to writing something myself, and whilst my last year contains many highlights – my trip to Israel, a summer in North Wales and a deepening of friendships that have become increasingly valuable – I always feel somewhat hesitant to “review my year”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the heart of that hesitancy lies solely in my feeling of a lack of accomplishment. I never feel I’ve achieved anything worth writing about or highlighting. I call it the curse of the Internet. It’s so easy to spend time looking and comparing what I’ve done to all the people who have achieved a great deal, all the people who’ve had the guts to sit down work hard and put themselves out there. I’m always left reeling at, what feels like, my complete lack of gumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am learning though. Learning to not let that fear of failure or fear of no one noticing be the reason to stop myself from doing the things I want to. Thats why I’m writing this post, to set out three small targets to try and set me on my way this year. I think they are all achievable and am hoping they will set me on my way to accomplish something this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last year I’ve put weight on. Some people will argue that I needed to, I’ve always been a bit skinny, but in the last year I’ve put on a little too much. I weighed myself over the Christmas holidays and well the number at the start was too high. My first mission is to lose a stone in weight by exercising more regularly and cutting out those &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; treats which have snuck into my diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past couple of years has seen my blog fall in to decline, significantly. I’ve always enjoyed writing for my blog, but the past couple of years has seen a lot of things change in my life and it didn’t feel right to be writing about them here. Nor did it seem right to continue writing about things which on reflection are quite trivial when compared to the loss of loved ones. But time is moving on, and I feel that it is time to &lt;em&gt;pick up my pen&lt;/em&gt; once again and begin writing for my blog with more regularity. I realise I’ve said this before, and it’s gotten past January, February and into March before I’ve really realised I’ve not done anything I’d hoped to, so I’ve given myself a number to aim for. I’m going to try to write four posts a month. Not four link posts, but four &lt;em&gt;article&lt;/em&gt; posts, although I hesitate to call them articles. There’ll be no word count, just original content, content I create because I want to and enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third thing I want to do is a little more open ended and probably something that everyone hopes to do. &lt;strong&gt;I’d like to use my time to greater effect.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been a night owl, I like staying up late, the quiet cosiness of being up late with a small light on and my book, sketch book or Mac for company feels great. The problem is when you have a nine to five job that kind of behaviour is not really helpful. Hitting the sack in the early hours of the morning and then rising only a few hours later to go to work is a recipe for disaster. Burning the candle at both ends only really has one destination for me, running myself in to the ground and an onslaught of mouth ulcers. So in order to combat this tendency to waste my time, I’m resolving to give my self a bed time and get up earlier. My aim is to be up at six each morning in order to do a half hour of exercises, then spend time reading my bible, praying and whatever is left can be spent writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Re-reading that last paragraph makes it feel like a pretty big task, but I think knuckling down and doing it will help me to achieve the other two points. More than that though, having a set time to sit and read my bible without distraction will be the biggest benefit of all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always admired those who are able to get up early and spend some time each morning to do this. While I’m away in North Wales for two weeks every year, I spend time leading a children’s holiday club. When I’m there, life is so different to my everyday life that I’m able to easily get up early and spend time each morning reading from the word. I’ve become acutely aware in the last few weeks that it’s all down to a matter of attitude. I’m so aware of how important it is in those two weeks to devote my time in such a manner, that it’s time to change my attitude and devote that time every morning rather than in the evenings when I find it harder to concentrate and often run out of time. It’s something that I enjoy, but often feel a need to do out of duty, yet, when I set time aside I’ve seen the benefits in my life and my relationship with Jesus. I want to do it more and so this attempt to change my sleeping patterns is motivated by that desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so with that, please join me in raising my hot blackcurrent to 2012 and all it has in stall!&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2012/Wecloming-2012-and-Setting-a-Few-Targets
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>In Search Of Flow</title>
            <link>
                /2011/In-Search-Of-Flow
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Like most of the world, the arrival of an iPad in my life has meant a lot of my established routines and behaviours have changed. I’m no longer setting up camp on my sofa with my MacBook Pro to spend some time reading RSS feeds and going where the links take me, instead this time is being spent using my iPad. I find I’m using my MacBook Pro a lot less than I used too, that’s not necessarily a negative thing though, as the time that I do spend on my MacBook Pro is much more meaningful than it used to be. I’m finding myself going through a shift in mindset as I’m more focused when I sit down with my Mac and don’t find myself drawn to the likes of Twitter and Reeder. My productivity has increased, which can only be a good thing as I gradually pick up more freelancing work. The work that I am doing has become more meaningful, that is with one exception. Here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blog. It’s slipped and largely because of my shift in behaviour. Most of my blogging revolved around reading interesting articles and curating them on my site. This then drove me to write longer form content when I wanted and when something attracted me sufficiently. I now find myself both linking less and writing less. Not good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reading-a-ton-more&quot;&gt;Reading a Ton More&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I follow a lot of very good blogs, most of the things I read are on the internet and since getting my iPad Instapaper has really come in to it’s own. Shawn Blanc nailed it when he &lt;a href=&quot;http://shawnblanc.net/2011/01/best-software-of-2010/&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So in short, Instapaper is the best way to read the Internet. And the iPad app … is the best way to read your Instapaper articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trouble is, if a large portion of your reading material comes from the internet, the desire to share increases. It’s so easy in today’s world to share something to Twitter or Facebook, but if you want to add a little commentary to that link and share it on your blog, well it’s a little trickier. On the Mac I can hit Cmd-1 and MarsEdit will fire up with the link pre-populated and any selected text quoted. On the iPad, thats not so easy. Theres no MarsEdit for iPad and well, quite frankly, the iOS Wordpress app sucks and copy &amp;amp; pasting back and forth between apps isn’t the easiest or quickest way of doing things. Put quite simply the barrier to entry for posting on the iPad was too high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s the big deal? Well, like many people I like to write. I don’t consider myself a writer but one of the reasons I started blogging was to give myself another creative outlet; a place to stretch muscles that don’t necessarily get stretched all that much; a place to, should I need, release a little about topics that don’t necessarily interest my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I miss it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trouble is I don’t really know where to begin, and so in my usual manner I began to problem solve. The conclusion I reached? I find it easier to write when I have a reasonably steady flow of things going through the blog. Some momentum. The best and easiest way of creating that momentum, or generating flow, is by curating links and pointing people to other well written and interesting content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For once my thinking on this subject seemed to coincide with some other folk on the internet. Shawn Blanc and Benjamin Brooks touched on this recently in The B&amp;amp;B Podcast. When they visit a site they want to see articles before they will begin to measure if you are worth following. Something I agree with quite strongly, if there is a good article on a site I visit I will take note, if there are a couple in close succession, chances are you’ll end up in my feed reader. But if there are large gaps between articles and nothing else posted it makes a site feel stagnated, a stagnation I feel has begun to develop here. I want my site to feel alive and the best way to do that is to write regularly, and, because I’m out of practice the best way to break a cycle of not posting is to link to others. It’s not and nor should it be the sole purpose, but an active site is a cared for site and a cared for site usually brings good content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Beginnings of a Redesign&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeking out an easier way of building that flow led me down the path to the beginnings of a redesign. I needed an easy way to share links on the blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to help me begin to develop this flow I’ve made a few changes to the site. A slight facelift which aligns to a grid but really is a framework for the future and has allowed me to make a couple of adjustments to the behaviour of my links. For those of you who have noticed the titles of the links now point straight to the site I’m linking too, so rather than including the link in the text as I’ve done in the past I’m now free to just include my thoughts. It leads to a more streamlined way of posting from both the iPad and my Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Ben Brooks’ adjusted &lt;a href=&quot;http://brooksreview.net/2011/05/mobile-wp-blogging/&quot;&gt;bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; and the plugins that it requires I can now post more easily to the site. The pace isn’t quite what I’d like it to be but it’s developing and my hope is that I can pay more attention in the long run and begin to write my own articles with a little more regularity than the sporadic posting that I seem to have settled into.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2011/In-Search-Of-Flow
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My First Conference (Part Two)</title>
            <link>
                /2011/My-First-Conference-(Part-Two)
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to work a seemingly random collection of thoughts into a follow up post about New Adventures conference. It’s not really happened so I’ve chosen to just throw them out there to anyone who is interested.
Overall I enjoyed the day, it was fun, informative and pushed me out of my comfort zone, teaching me things about design and myself that are valuable and I am processing in order to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most enjoyable was Brendan’s talk. He was  the most entertaining in delivery and engaged the audience excellently. His passion for design is infectious, but something I felt myself identifying with straight away. I don’t obsess over using the right pencil, but my friends can attest that I do obsess over other seemingly pointless items.
Most disappointing was Veerle Pieter’s talk about inspiration. I really enjoy Veerle’s blog, and so was looking forward to hearing her talk but, for me, it had too much example and not enough insight. I was hoping for some processes which people could adopt or adapt to make their own and use as triggers in the creative process. I know we all work differently, but hearing how someone goes about finding inspiration when all they are hitting is brick wall after brick wall can be inspiring in itself. Veerle also seemed to contradict some of the talks from the morning, with a theme of doing something  a certain way because you like it rather than for a particular reason. Whilst design is subjective and sometimes we go with our gut, there’s usually reason for doing it beyond “I like it”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most thought provoking was Dan Rubin’s talk on maturing the industry by developing a language that has meaning and that everyone can understand. Having moved to a new job around 3 months ago and having had the opportunity to work on a couple of web jobs, this struck a cord. The things I mean when I refer to something and the things they mean when my new colleagues refer to something are easily confused on these jobs, however, when it comes to a print job everyone knows exactly what the other person means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elliot’s talk, Andy Clarke’s, Jon Tan’s and Mark Boulton’s were also some of the most informative, interesting and thought provoking talks that left me feeling inspired and motivated. Good stuff that I have already noticed is informing the way I work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Adventures was a really good day, which I thoroughly enjoyed, hopefully I’ll get to a few more in the future and I’m certainly hoping that I can make it to New Adventures 2.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2011/My-First-Conference-(Part-Two)
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My First Conference (Part One)</title>
            <link>
                /2011/My-First-Conference-(Part-One)
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;This week I’m heading to my first design conference in the form of &lt;a href=&quot;http://newadventuresconf.com/&quot;&gt;New Adventures&lt;/a&gt; in my home town ((Well 25 minutes outside of the city is technically my home town, but I was born in Nottingham so close enough.)). In the past I’ve always looked in on conferences from the outside, so when I heard about &lt;a href=&quot;http://mrqwest.co.uk/naconf/&quot;&gt;naconf&lt;/a&gt; I figured it was time to take the leap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who works primarily in print but has a real fascination with the web I’m hoping to learn a lot and figure out where my layout skills can cross over to the screen. I’ve heard it said many a time that print designers shouldn’t switch to the web, but equally I’ve seen many high profile designers achieve great things in both formats.
I’m most looking forward to hearing some of the best in the business share some valuable insights into the various topics. In particular I’m looking forward to hearing &lt;a href=&quot;http://veerle.duoh.com/&quot;&gt;Veerle Pieters&lt;/a&gt; share some thoughts on triggering inspiration and how we can break through the block we all suffer from time to time. One of the things I find hardest when I’m designing for the web is inspiration. When you use the web so regularly it’s very easy to let yourself fall in to a pattern of “this goes here, that there…” and before you know it you have a very insipid run of the mill website. I’m hoping I may pick up a few techniques to help me use my experience in designing for print be the inspiration for designing for the web. (I was going to go on here highlighting all the things I’m looking forward to, but, as I began writing I realised I’d be highlighting all the talks in the schedule. It seems, unsurprisingly, that they all compliment one another nicely.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it’s my first conference I know I won’t be able to soak everything up all in one go, but I’m going armed with a brand new Moleskine and I’m hoping the notes I make will compliment the slides when they are released. The whole day will be a learning experience, but the learning doesn’t just stop once I’ve left the venue. It continues in the follow up and, most importantly, in my efforts to put what’s been said into practise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the talks, I’m looking forward to hopefully meeting a few of the people I’ve come across on the web. Be it via blogs, twitter or some other means it’d be great to meet some new faces in the industry. So if you read this, or follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/#!/philbowell&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; do come and say Hi!&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2011/My-First-Conference-(Part-One)
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Leaving Tumblr</title>
            <link>
                /2011/Leaving-Tumblr
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;It’s been just under a year since I began trialling &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; as the basis of my blog. At the time I was writing from &lt;a href=&quot;http://phil.electricweekend.com/&quot;&gt;Electric Weekend&lt;/a&gt; but had been struggling thanks to several events that happened at the end of 2009. In an attempt to get back in to the swing of blogging I’d decided to make a clean break from my first blog and start again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a while I posted regularly but I soon fell in to a trap of consuming rather than writing. Tumblr makes it very easy to find new blogs to follow, not a bad thing, but I found it all too easy to consume rather than create. However, in the last month or so I’ve begun to feel that desire to create again, to write on a more regular basis. Not only that but I wanted more control, and this is the driving force behind my move back to a Wordpress based site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;control&quot;&gt;Control?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I used to enjoy most about my old site was the ability to change things up should I feel they’ve become stale. I could more easily try out new features should I come across something I liked the look of. But it goes beyond this, I wanted more control of the fundamentals of the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that has frustrated me most, not necessarily with my site, but with the sites of bloggers who use Tumblr, is the poor archives. It’s frustrated me that I’ve not been able to find a link or an article on someone’s site. It’s such a bad experience that I began to think people, or at least some people, will have the same trouble finding things on my site as I’m having here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all boils down to the fact that I’d like to design the overall experience people have on my site and the only way I can do that is to move to a self-hosted platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;theme&quot;&gt;Theme?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So having admitted I’d like to have more control over my site, here I am using a default theme. Well the answer to that is simple. I wanted to make the move while I had the desire to write more. I’ve already wasted a month knowing I wanted to leave Tumblr, and so rather than wait until I’d got a fully designed blog I decided to make the move now and begin tailoring my site as I settle in to my new surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not everything is running without some customisation. I’ve already begun my design process with the URL’s (Thanks to a little inspiration from &lt;a href=&quot;http://ianhin.es/wrote-about/designing-urls-for-humans/&quot;&gt;Ian Hines&lt;/a&gt;.) which feature a more friendly sentence like structure that I hope will grow as I develop the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll also notice that comments are available on this post. Having not had comments on my site for a long time I’ve begun to feel that on certain posts it might be quite nice to try and foster a bit of conversation, they won’t be on by default but I hope to be able to turn them on from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also hoping to find a way to bring most of the content from my Tumblr site into this one so that everything from PBcom can be archived here. But whilst all this is going on, I now feel I have a website where I can start to be myself again. Somewhere I’m hopeful I can get back into the flow of blogging regularly, with a mixture of long form articles and links. A place where I’m happy to create is far more important to me than discovering even more content. This year I’m hoping to use my time more wisely, and hopefully this move is the first step in using my online time in a more productive manner.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2011/Leaving-Tumblr
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Introducing PBcom</title>
            <link>
                /2010/Introducing-PBcom
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;The last few months have been very quiet here at Electric Weekend, there’s been lots going on behind the scenes which have made it hard to write here. I covered some of those in the last post, but now I’m beginning to feel the desire to write again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I also feel as a person I’ve begun to out grow Electric Weekend, particularly as I look to present myself to be available for hire on a freelance basis. With that said, I’d like to introduce you to my new site &lt;a href=&quot;http://philbowell.com&quot;&gt;philbowell.com&lt;/a&gt; or PBcom as it’s affectionally known by me. Phase one, the log, has just gone live and phase two, the portfolio, will follow suit in the next couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean for Electric Weekend? It means I’ll no longer be posting here, the site will remain as an archive but from now on I’ll be posting on the log at PBcom. Please head over there, change your feed reader to point to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/philbowell&quot;&gt;new RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; or give me a follow. Oh, and enjoy the new site.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2010/Introducing-PBcom
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Summer 2009</title>
            <link>
                /2009/Summer-2009
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Well, it’s been a while. In fact it’s been the longest gap between posts there’s ever been on Electric Weekend. I’m not going to apologise, the simple fact is that in the last 2/3 months a lot of stuff has happened, a mixture of ends of chapters, beginnings of new ones and a good bye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest end to a chapter has meant I’m now living in a flat on my tod instead of in a shared house with two very good friends. One of whom had to move away for unfortunate circumstances, the other, well he got married. It was sad to know I’ll no longer be living with these two guys, we’ve lived together since the beginning of uni almost 5 years ago and enjoyed a lot of good times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beginning of my busy summer began with the wedding of one of my housemates. A guy who has become a very good friend got married to a girl who I can also call a very good friend. The chance to share their big day was very special and, hopefully, by now they are settling in to married life&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#78265&quot; id=&quot;fn1&quot; title=&quot;see footnote 1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step in the summer involved moving into a 1 bed flat. I’ve never lived on my own, and well, it’s been eventful so far but I’m settling in. Having only been in the flat for less than a week I was due to go away for 2 weeks. Every summer, well for the last 3, my girl friend and I have gone to server on a beach mission in North Wales and like always the night before we go was very busy. The complication this year was that I got locked out my flat late at night the day before I was due to drive for 5 hours early in the morning. Looking back it was funny, but at the time a little stressful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully a very enjoyable 2 weeks followed. A time to serve God and enjoy spending time with a bunch of awesome people. A chance to share the gospel with a group of kids, whom it is obvious God is working in. A privilege to be involved in such a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My return to the flat signalled another eventful night. Having come home tired and ready for a good sleep in my own bed I was rudely awakened at 4am by a roof tile. Odd you might think, but I’d call it scary. It’s not pleasant being woken up by something crashing through your bedroom window and a sleepless night followed. Fortunately it was fixed quickly the next morning, and things have been fairly plain sailing since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final part of my eventful summer followed the week after beach mission, and it’s partly why there has been such a gap in posting here on the blog. It’s prompted a lot of thoughts, memories and reflections and is the main reason this post has sat in my drafts for most of September. I knew I had to write it and it felt like I couldn’t really post trivial links before I wrote about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several months ago my Granny was diagnosed with cancer. At the end of August and after several weeks of pain, where she was being looked after by my Mum, my Uncle and my Aunt, my Granny passed away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last photo I have of myself and Granny is sat in front of me now. It brings back memories of playing games on the carpet, cricket in the back garden with Grandad bowling and Granny catching, of softmints and of cheeky pound coins slipped into my hand as we left to go home. But, most of all it brings back memories of a lady who is loved and missed. A lady who always had a smile, who cared for her family and who was, most importantly, my Granny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;78265&quot;&gt;In fact I know they are. Last weekend I celebrated my 25th birthday, with a group of friends, including the happy couple. A very good time was had, and it was brilliant to see them enjoying life as Mr &amp;amp; mrs. &lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; title=&quot;return to article&quot;&gt;?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2009/Summer-2009
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Experiencing A Fever</title>
            <link>
                /2009/Experiencing-A-Fever
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I’ve done something tonight I’ve not done for a a while. I’ve sat at my desk with a glass of wine and read. I’ve read feeds. Some of which contained posts that stretched back a few weeks, others posts written today and I’ve come out the other side feeling like I’ve enjoyed a relaxed evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world where we get busier and busier, where more and more things are going on, times where we can just relax seem to be more and more precious. Those moment where you can focus on something and forget about all that’s going on around you, forget about the ToDo’s stacking up in Things, the emails needing to be read and those things that otherwise cause distractions. Of course I’m not talking about the times spent with people, those times are important and to be relished, in fact there’s nothing nicer than spending the evening sharing a pizza and a bottle of wine with my girlfriend. Those times are treasured &amp;amp; important and anything but a distraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead I’m talking about things that, at least for me, seem to come under a group banner called the internet. Yes, the internet is invaluable, in fact I use it for work and play, but it can get to a point where you feel like you are always clamouring to stay on top of things. Stay on top of the inbox, stay on top of the ever growing unread feed count whilst dipping in and out of the stream of consciousness otherwise known as Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judging by the, lack of, frequency of posts on my blog in the last few months its been apparent I’ve been looking for away to not tone back on the amount of things I read on the web, but rather to implement some form of control. That control seems to have been to add a bit of distance between the constant barrage of the internet and me. I’ve begun reading books again, shock horror, and I’ve been enjoying it. Enjoying it in a way I’ve not been enjoying reading on the web for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been clear some habits had to change and the main issue lay with my feed reader. So much goes into it that if I don’t stay on top of it and achieve RSS ZERO everyday I soon lose enthusiasm for it, hit the mark all as read and start again. The trouble with this is I miss things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t like missing things, and I end up in the repeating process of aiming to achieve RSS ZERO everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people may say it’s a little sad I felt the need to stay on top of my RSS feeds everyday, and I’d agree. But working in an industry that is constantly changing, evolving, growing and releasing new things everyday it’s difficult not to want to try and stay at the peak. Seeing the things others are creating helps me draw inspiration and develop new ways of thinking, something very important in the world of design. Rather than zeroing out I wanted a way of keeping my finger “on the pulse” whilst removing the pressure of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often wanted my feed reader to tell me what’s going on, to give me the most important bits and then let me catch the rest when I’m ready. I’d flitted back and forth for a few months between NetNewsWire, Google Reader and NewsFire but nothing really differentiates one from the other. They all handle feeds in the same way and they all made me feel like I needed to achieve RSS ZERO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then almost exactly a month ago there was an interesting development. No not the release of a new version of the iPhone OS, but instead the unleashing on the internet of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://feedafever.com/&quot;&gt;Fever&lt;/a&gt;.
Now it would be a little naive of me to claim that Fever has fixed things and allowed me to reclaim lots of time, no that has to come with a change of mindset, but it has helped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fever brings a new approach to RSS feeds and I’m &lt;a href=&quot;http://patdryburgh.com/blog/ninety-eight-degrees/&quot;&gt;not the only one&lt;/a&gt; who has noticed. Some enjoy the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tightwind.net/2009/07/fever-revealing-communities/&quot;&gt;new aspect of community&lt;/a&gt; it brings, connections with readers are good things, but others like me enjoy the control it brings. I’ve enjoyed the last couple of weeks and noticed I’m less distracted when it comes to work. No longer am I opening NNW regularly to see what’s new and keep the unread count down. I’m popping into Fever for a quick break, read an article while I drink my coffee &lt;strong&gt;that it tells me&lt;/strong&gt; I might be interested in and then back to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overall feeling is one of being informed without feeling overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can be updated on what’s happening without having to discover it for myself. It’s then up to me how much time I spend seeking out more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-how-does-it-work&quot;&gt;But How Does It Work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a little trepidation I’d purchased Fever and within minutes I had my RSS subscriptions imported. A little sifting allowed me to move some of the feeds which provide the odd interesting article into a section called Sparks which I also populated with some blogs I’d removed in a cull because the good to bad ratio was swinging the wrong way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This left me with a bunch of feeds I knew I would like reading otherwise known as Kindling. Some of these were moved into a folder called favourites because as a general rule of thumb I enjoy reading every post and look forward to their pithy comments. This bit is usually my first port of call when I’ve got a bit more time on my hands, it works just like the “old skool” feed readers. I can go through feeds individually and sift through the articles selecting things to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there’s The Hot List, the gem that tells me what I might like, that keeps me up to date and lets me enjoy reading the Kindling. If a feed in my Kindling combines with some in my Sparks, the article gains a higher temperature and thus becomes more likely to be read. It’s a clever trick that works on the understanding that blog posts link to each other. It knows that the internet is a large community with many little ones inside, so it knows that when lots of blogs are linking to something then heck it must be good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-the-out-come&quot;&gt;What’s The Out Come?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, for me at least, it makes for a more enjoyable and more relaxed reading experience. No longer is there the pressure to keep up to date by checking the feeds and looking at each one individually, now I can be &lt;em&gt;kept&lt;/em&gt; up to date and all I have to do is visit the first page of Fever. A quick glance shows me all the headlines, I can pick one to read and then if I’m interested look at the list of blogs I’m subscribed to and see what they’ve got to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for me how feeds should behave. They’re there to tell you a site has been updated, so it makes sense for you’re feed reader to prioritise things for you. Now if only someone would do the same for my email…&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2009/Experiencing-A-Fever
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Motivation</title>
            <link>
                /2009/Motivation
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;These days, I’m sure like many, my primary source of reading material is via the internet, or more specifically my feed reader. There’s a lot of great content out on the web and filtering out the cruft to get to it can be a bit of a mission. We are bombarded with information clamouring for our attention the moment we open our web browser, so finding a way of weeding out the crap to reveal the good stuff is imperative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trouble is once you’ve found a few choice blogs which provide you with quality and fairly regular content, doors are opened. Opened to a world of inspiration. Inspiration to create for yourself, be it design, writing or whatever floats your boat. This in itself is fantastic. The more good stuff out there the more everyone benefits and the more people are inspired to go out and create. Let’s face it at the heart of everything that’s created there’s an inspiration that’s been harnessed to produce something unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other side of this there’s a negative. Once you’re up and running creating content that &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; are pleased with, the distractions appear. There’s traffic stats, how many people are visiting? How many people are staying? How many people like what you’ve done enough to subscribe and be notified when you create more? Then there are the comparisons. How come they get more than me? What’s so different about their writing than mine? Why can’t I execute my designs like that? It has an impact. It stops you creating, you lose your focus and the things you do create don’t bring the enjoyment they used to. Creating becomes a chore as you try to find the break through that will bring you the traffic, or is it the recognition, of the people you look up to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a nasty spiral and something we all go through. For whatever reason, it seems to be human nature to compare what you create to those around you. It starts early in school. There’s the competition with grades, that feeling you’ve put your heart and soul into something yet you only get a B but your mate gets an A and did it all the night before. Every time you go home your parents remind you, there’s no proof they did it the night before. Chances are they worked on it just as much as you did, if not more, and therein lies the reason for their higher grades.
Similarly the same applies to the blogs and designers you come across on the internet. They’ve worked at it, and they’ve worked damn hard. It doesn’t just come over night, for some it comes quicker than others, but every time it’s deserved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trick is to make it enjoyable. Find that thing that makes you smile. That gives you the satisfied feeling up on pressing publish which can only come when you’ve worked at something. Remove those barriers, get rid of the nagging questions. Push them aside and concentrate on making what you create the best it can be. When you have those crises of confidence. Take a step back, review the situation, look at what you’ve done in the past that has satisfied you and know that you can do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly check your motivation. If you’re creating to try and satisfy others what you create won’t be the best it can. You can’t satisfy others because you don’t know exactly what their requirements and needs are. You only know what will satisfy you, and you’ll only know it when it’s been achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what satisfies me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing that I’ve done my best to bring to glory to God in all I do. As a Christian my priority is my relationship with Jesus. I try and begin each day with spending some time with my Lord, reading His word, listening and speaking with Him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I go to work in the knowledge that I’m not going alone. That He is with me, my source of inspiration, my motivation. I try to work in a way that demonstrates this to my colleagues through my behaviours and the way I approach my work. All in the hope that they will see something different with in me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s the reason for this post?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s somewhat of a reminder. That if that’s the way I approach my work, why is it that the figures in my Mint installation matter so much? They shouldn’t. The reason I like to create is the same as the reason I apply myself to my work in the manner I do. I want to use my gifts to bring glory to Him. I want to create quality content, not because it might increase the numbers, but because I want people to see that I’ve something in my life that matters far more. Something that drives me to do that best I can in everything I do, not just in certain areas of my life, but in &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2009/Motivation
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Talent Crutch</title>
            <link>
                /2009/The-Talent-Crutch
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Micaheal Mistretta has been at it again. Another excellent post this time about &lt;a href=&quot;http://michaelmistretta.com/2009/the-myth-of-talent/&quot;&gt;The Myth of Talent&lt;/a&gt; which brought to mind a lesson I learned back when I was 16 doing my GCSE’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a talent, you have a talent, everyone has a talent. A lot of people don’t believe they have one, or simply haven’t found it yet, but we all have a talent. I’m fortunate in that from an early age it was apparent I could draw, that I had a natural creative flair. I used to draw a lot, but my drawings weren’t always observational, the majority of them were designs. I’d design football kits, cars, robots and machines, whatever came to mind I’d design it. It’s what I did, it was how I was known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s not always been a good thing, and nearly led to a big, big slip up when I was doing my GCSE’s. Having gone through most of school, particularly early senior school, being told I was very talented and just needed to be kept interested in art I developed a reliance on my natural abilities. I’d look around, see I was doing better than those in my class and think I was ok. That was until a phone call from my Mum to my art teacher revealed I wasn’t doing enough. Yes I was doing more than a lot of others, but it still wasn’t enough. I was using my talent as a crutch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;People use talent as a crutch — an excuse: “I couldn’t possibly do such and such because I’m nowhere near as talented as so and so.” Sure, it’s easy to believe that it’s not your fault you aren’t good at something, simply because you weren’t granted that ‘talent’ at birth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a  similar way I was using my talent as a crutch. Not as an excuse to not try something, but as an excuse to say “I’m naturally good at this, I don’t need to work as hard as everyone else”. My awareness of my natural ability, or talent if you will, was my crutch. It caused me to be too relaxed and too confident. Knowing you can do something doesn’t mean you don’t have to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Talent is potential. It is worth nothing if you don’t do anything with it. Telling me that you have talent is absolutely worthless unless you’re the kind of person that’s going to do something about it… Becoming good at something takes a lot more than just talent. It takes hard work — pure, unbiased, hard work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I learnt that day when I came home to be told I was failing. I still remember that feeling. At first an incredulous disbelief, “I can’t be, it’s what I’m good at.” Then a horrible sinking feeling as the realisation set in. I needed that GCSE to do what I’m doing now, if I didn’t get it I had no idea what I would do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being told that I was failing at something I was naturally gifted at was crushing, but I needed to be told. It started a process which I’ve been doing ever since, working at improving my talent. In 6 months I turned my GCSE around, I passed and it meant I could move on to eventually work as a professional creative. It’s been hard, and sometimes I’ve not been as good at it as I have at others, but that lesson has stayed with me and doubtless will never leave. It may be partially to blame why I don’t always believe I’m as good as I am, something I’m often told, but it’s something that makes me strive to be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have three people to thank for helping me learn that lesson. My Mum for making that phone call then coupled with my Dad for encouraging me, and God for giving me parents who want the best for me. After all He gave me my natural gifting and I was squandering it, not using it for the purpose He intended. Resting on my laurels wasn’t going to glorify Him, so He prompted them to make me realise what was happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this day I believe I’m very fortunate to have known I was naturally good at something from such a young age, many people after almost an entire lifetime still don’t know what they are naturally good at. I am forever thankful that I knew, but I’m even more thankful that I have a God on my side who wants the best for me. For that reason I try my hardest to ensure all I do is for His glory, without Him I wouldn’t be doing something I love for a living.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2009/The-Talent-Crutch
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Two Mac Nightmare - Email & Contacts</title>
            <link>
                /2009/Two-Mac-Nightmare-Email-Contacts
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;If you’ve only just found this series of posts exploring how I keep my two Macs in sync you might want to look at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://phil.electricweekend.com/2008/12/mac-sync-series/&quot;&gt;introduction&lt;/a&gt; of the series to help set the scene. In this post I want to explore the issue of keeping emails and contacts in sync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m sure the majority of you are aware of the a well known protocol to help with this issue. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Message_Access_Protocol&quot;&gt;Internet Message Access Protocol or IMAP&lt;/a&gt;, as it’s more commonly known, allows you to access your email through a web interface or a desktop email client and have the data appear identically in all places. Deleting an email on your desktop will mean the email is deleted on your laptop as well as on the web interface. In essence it provides everything you need to keep your mail in sync across multiple devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my email I use the same Google Apps account that I use for my &lt;a href=&quot;http://phil.electricweekend.com/2008/12/mac-sync-series-calendar/&quot;&gt;calendar syncing&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve found gMail to be extremely effective in solving the problem many people deal with regarding email. It enables me to have a central hub for all my email addresses. I currently have 3 emails addresses forwarding to my gApps account meaning that I effectively have a desktop client on the web, I’m able to view incoming mail and reply/send using which ever address I want. This setup mirrors my Mail.app on both my Macs adding the consistency I require. Any rules that I want to apply to me email are applied in gMail and so are the same in all locations, meaning I don’t have to set up the same rules on my Macs, it’s all done for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now initially gMail’s IMAP implementation was not very well thought through, fortunately that was fixed with the addition of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://gmailblog.blogspot.com/2008/06/introducing-gmail-labs.html&quot;&gt;gMail Labs&lt;/a&gt; item called &lt;a href=&quot;http://gmailblog.blogspot.com/2008/10/new-in-labs-advanced-imap-controls.html&quot;&gt;Advanced IMAP&lt;/a&gt;. This allows very useful fine grained control of which labels appear as folders in Mail.app, you can turn off all mail boxes with the exception of the inbox if you so wish. Most importantly it means I can turn off gMail’s “All Mail” folder and in the process eliminate all the duplicate emails that appear in Spotlight searches within Mail.app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point I’d like to take the opportunity to explain why MobileMe is not suitable for me&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#49843&quot; id=&quot;fn1&quot; title=&quot;see footnote 1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I have many email addresses which I send mail from, on the Mac using Mail.app this works perfectly I can send email using any of the addresses I’ve set up. Unfortunately this is not the case for MobileMe. Whilst you can use email aliases they always end with @me.com and you can not use a custom domain. This is pretty much a deal breaker for me. I can’t justify paying for a service in which I won’t use one of the key features and whilst I could use gMail for my email needs and MobileMe for my other items it just doesn’t work in my mind. Integration of Web Apps is just as important to me as integration of desktop apps. The whole reason I use Mail/Address Book/iCal is because of their integration, and the idea of having to go to separate sites for different services would in my mind be like using other non-standard software on my Macs. I like everything to be as connected as it can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now unfortunately this leads me to the bane of my synchronisation nightmares. Contacts. For a while I had some syncing of my contacts between Macs using the Yahoo sync built into Leopard’s Address Book, but this didn’t fit with my integrated Web Apps and excluded some fields that I put to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need a sync with gMail. So when Apple added the ability to sync Address Book with gMail I was pleasantly surprised. That was until I discovered I needed to sync my iPod touch through iTunes. I don’t plug my iPod into my iMac very often so this presented another unsatisfactory “solution”. I went in search of other methods and found &lt;a href=&quot;http://wateree.net/syncman/&quot;&gt;Syncman&lt;/a&gt; a small app being developed to provide syncing of Address Book with gMail. Sadly it too lacked the control I wanted, and on closer inspection I found it hasn’t been updated for several months. Again another unsatisfactory solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this seems rather odd. We have a very good, widely used protocol for keeping our email in sync across multiple clients but no way of keeping our contacts in sync. I find it hard to understand why there is not a protocol that works hand in hand with IMAP to provide this. Both sets of data are so heavily reliant on the other it seems illogical that there isn’t a widely available method of keeping everything in sync. Whilst I could get a working solution in MobileMe, because of it’s email shortfalls I wouldn’t be in better position than I am now. I’m left frustrated, along with many others, with my hopes resting on the guys at BusyMac to provide a solution. I’m told they are developing a new version of BusySync which brings Address Book sync, hopefully it will come soon and be just as effective as their calendar sync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;49843&quot;&gt;In my opening post a &lt;a href=&quot;http://phil.electricweekend.com/2008/12/mac-sync-series/#71617&quot;&gt;footnote&lt;/a&gt; highlighted that MobileMe wasn&#39;t suitable for me so I&#39;d like to answer that here.&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; title=&quot;return to article&quot;&gt;?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2009/Two-Mac-Nightmare-Email-Contacts
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Two Mac Nightmare – Calendars</title>
            <link>
                /2008/The-Two-Mac-Nightmare-Calendars
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;When I &lt;a href=&quot;http://phil.electricweekend.com/2008/12/mac-sync-series/&quot;&gt;introduced&lt;/a&gt; this series of posts, I highlighted the main areas I wanted to keep in sync between my Macs and a web interface for use at work. This post aims to introduce you to the method I use to keep my calendar in sync across the three areas.
On both my Macs I use iCal to keep things organised. On the web I have a Google Apps For Your Domain (GAFYD) account setup which includes a very nice calendar that mirrors iCal nicely.  In my quest to find a syncing method I’ve tried many different routes but always felt that the combination of iCal and gCal was the way forward and there are quite a few tools available to enable this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first tool that came available was of course the first tool I tried.  It’s also probably the most well known, and goes by the name of &lt;a href=&quot;http://spanningsync.com/&quot;&gt;Spanning Sync&lt;/a&gt;. It installs via a preference pane which enables you to configure it with your Google account and enable fully fledged bi-directional sync. I used it when it was in beta and for the free trial period once it was fully released, but something about it didn’t quite feel right to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m already trusting a 3rd party with my calendar information by enabling this sync, what I didn’t like about Spanning Sync was the fact it didn’t speak directly to Google.  Everything was passed through the Spanning sync servers. I didn’t want yet another 3rd party server holding my information, and adding an extra step in the sync meant, at least in my eyes, adding another thing that could break. However, this wasn’t the only reason I didn’t like Spanning Sync. I didn’t like the pricing method they were using. A subscription basis didn’t sit right with me, especially at the price they were asking. $65 for a lifetime or $25 for a year. That felt expensive and turned me away in the search of another solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for me this was at a time when a second option was just entering the market in a beta. gSync&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#73872&quot; id=&quot;fn1&quot; title=&quot;see footnote 1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; had become available and unlike Spanning Sync it spoke directly with Google and was not subscription based.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with Spanning sync I tested it for the beta period and the free trial, but again I was left wanting. Whilst the utility seemed to work there were always a few hiccoughs with the sync. It didn’t always work and a couple of times I was left to restore from backups and spend time on Google sorting out broken calendars with surplus events. Not really the ideal solution. I quickly grew tired of this and gave up for several months, relying on one copy of iCal and my memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as I was beginning to get fed up and have ago at the all elusive sync, a new utility arrived on the market in the form of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.busymac.com/index.html&quot;&gt;BusySync&lt;/a&gt;. At the time it was only able to sync between 2 Macs on a local network (LAN), but I still gave it ago. It worked very well. I was able to set my iMac up as my “server” and have it sync my iBook flawlessly. I was very impressed, but still a little reluctant to commit as the web interface I needed was still eluding me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully only a few months after launch BusySync 2.0 was released and with it the ability to sync with a Google Calendar. I tried it again, and once again I was impressed. The same ease of use that was in version 1.0’s sync over LAN was present with 2.0’s sync to Google. A simple case of checking the right boxes after inputting my login details. Still I wasn’t sold instantly but after the 30 day trial ended I coughed up for a license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially I had my iMac setup, as before, as my “server”. It was publishing my calendars for my iBook to subscribe to as well as publishing them to my Google calendar. For a while this seemed to be working, but then I hit a few roadblocks. I wasn’t turning my iMac on as often as I needed, as a result I wasn’t getting identical sets of information on Google and my iBook. Things were getting a bit out of sync. I changed the way I was handling things so that my iBook was subscribed to my Google calendar which was in turn subscribed to my iMacs calendars.
This worked, everything was staying in sync and identical. But it didn’t feel right to me. It didn’t feel like I had a central point which acted as the “master” so I changed things again. This time exporting my calendars from my iMac and importing them into my Google Calendar. Then using BusySync I subscribed to the calendars from Google on my iMac and on my iBook. This was it. It felt right. It felt like a “cloud” and my calendars remained in sync no matter what I did. Whether I was at work adding an event on my iBook adding an event or on my iMac adding an event. Everything came and went very nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stunningly, but that’s not what you want to know. BusySync uses technology built into Mac OS X called Sync Services. As I understand it that technology presents BusySync with the calendar data the moment you complete entering it, and BusySync pushes it to Google. That means usually within a minute of making a change in iCal it is reflected on Google. Unfortunately the other direction doesn’t quite work the same way. Getting events from Google is still a pull system, checking at a specified intervals for new events and changes. However, setting it to check every minute pretty much enables the same feeling, and events feel like they appear almost instantly&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#74227&quot; id=&quot;fn2&quot; title=&quot;see footnote 2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It can’t get much better than that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please stay tuned for the next two installments of my series on keeping two Macs in sync. I’ll be tackling emails and contacts as well as those few important files you need in multiple places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;73872&quot;&gt;After I&#39;d written the main body of this post I couldn&#39;t find a link to gSync. It was created by a company called Macness but their website no longer seems to be alive. I guess the project died.&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; title=&quot;return to article&quot;&gt;?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;74227&quot;&gt;I have this setup on both my iMac and iBook. As the battery on my iBook is foobar&#39;d and I have it permanently plugged in I don&#39;t know how this would impact battery life. Having spoken with John, one of BusySync&#39;s developers, I thought I would pass on this piece of information regarding battery life.
&lt;blockquote&gt;If you have BusySync set to sync every minute with Google Calendar, it could very well be keeping your Mac from going to sleep, and will run down your battery. I recommend that you change the Google Sync interval to be greater than your sleep interval.
Setting Google to sync every minute doesn&#39;t buy you much. Any changes you make locally will sync immediately, and if you&#39;re concerned that something has changed on Google since the last pull, you can select the Sync Now menu command from the BusySync Menu bar icon.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; title=&quot;return to article&quot;&gt;?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2008/The-Two-Mac-Nightmare-Calendars
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Two Mac Nightmare – Synchronisation</title>
            <link>
                /2008/The-Two-Mac-Nightmare-Synchronisation
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;For the last couple of years I’ve been wrestling with the age old problem of having two Macs, a desktop and a laptop. Whilst it’s nice to have the luxury of two Macs it’s always presented an issue that I’m only now beginning to find a solution for. The age old problem of keeping the two machines in sync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many people I’ve gone down the route of pursuing that &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; solution and come up short. I’ve always been left with that feeling that my Macs are kind of there, they’re kind of synced but not quite. It’s always felt a little skew-whiff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there’s probably many answers to why, most likely beginning with my lack of desire to commit to any one method. I’m sure many of you who are in the same boat have gone down the same stream I did. Trying every new “solution” that presented itself, not to mention numerous attempts at finding a quick manual sync workflow. I tried many different services or apps, but each time they felt clunky and came up short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until I started working&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#70077&quot; id=&quot;fn1&quot; title=&quot;see footnote 1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that the true problem came to light. I had always been pursuing this nirvana of my two Macs in perfect sync without nailing down just what it was that needed syncing. When I started work it was made instantly clear what it was that I needed syncing, for the first time I was able to nail down just what I needed to be the same on my two machines.&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://phil.electricweekend.com/2008/12/mac-sync-series-calendar/&quot;&gt;Calendars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; — In this case iCal on my iMac and iBook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://phil.electricweekend.com/2009/01/mac-sync-series-email-contacts/&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; — This one was pretty easy, there&#39;s a rather well known protocol that deals with this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://phil.electricweekend.com/2009/01/mac-sync-series-email-contacts/&quot;&gt;Contacts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; — Address Book on my two Macs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some files&lt;/strong&gt; — Not everything but a select group that changes on a regular basis as well as a few constants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I also had a new problem. It wasn’t just the two machines that I needed to keep in harmony. I now had a third access point, my work Mac, that I wanted to be able to access my data on but didn’t really want to have synchronised in the same way. The ideal solution was a web interface that stayed in sync with my two Macs at home&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#71617&quot; id=&quot;fn2&quot; title=&quot;see footnote 2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. An added twist that seems to complicate the issue a little further. Or does it? Since the sync has to involve a “cloud” of some sort, it makes a lot of sense to seek out a solution that involved a web interface as a natural solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, now I’ve explained the issue I’ve been faced with I guess it’s time to introduce the series this post is beginning.  I’m aiming to go through the tools I now use to “solve” the problem I’ve just outlined.  I”ll tackle each individual item in a post of their own, with email and contacts in a combined post&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#74951&quot; id=&quot;fn3&quot; title=&quot;see footnote 3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, that will hopefully provide people in a similar position with an effective solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;70077&quot;&gt;I was a student at the beginning of this issue so it was never imperative that the two Macs were &quot;in sync&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; title=&quot;return to article&quot;&gt;?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;71617&quot;&gt;At this point people usually suggest Apple&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.me.com&quot;&gt;MobileMe&lt;/a&gt; but for various reasons, largely with email it&#39;s not suitable for me.  I&#39;ll tackle this more in the email post that&#39;s to come.&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; title=&quot;return to article&quot;&gt;?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;74951&quot;&gt;The two go so well together it&#39;s hard separate as well as to understand why there is no open protocol for contact sync in the same style as IMAP. &lt;a href=&quot;#fn3&quot; title=&quot;return to article&quot;&gt;?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2008/The-Two-Mac-Nightmare-Synchronisation
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Faceless</title>
            <link>
                /2008/Faceless
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Yesterday I encountered something at the bank which made me really think about the way some services are provided. More specifically it’s made me think about how technology is being introduced and taking the place of humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’m sure many of you know, I like technology. It fascinates me and I believe used correctly it can help us do many tasks. In fact I’d say pretty much everyone is helped by technology at some point in their day. It can save time for many tasks and add convenience of access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many cases technology and machines are being used to replace people, making the experience faceless. In fact there are many things which can now be done facelessly. I can pay for my shopping at the supermarket on the self-service aisles, I can pay for my petrol at the pump and not the kiosk and I can withdraw money from my bank at a “hole in the wall”. All great implementations which make the experience painless and quick. These implementations are popping up all over the place all aiming to speed up the process and provide greater efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is it always necessary?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These implementations often speed processes up. Withdrawing money from the bank is great, I don’t have to go into the building and I can do it when I need it. Similar with the petrol. I can buy it from the pump, I don’t have to walk to the kiosk and leave my car. Yet why is it I prefer to pay at the kiosk?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all honesty that’s just a personal preference. A lot of the time I want something other than petrol like a newspaper, which means I don’t have a lot of choice. I’m also limited to paying on my card and not by cash. But some times I want to be served by a person. Deal with something face to face. Somethings just don’t feel right unless you deal with a person, somethings don’t need to be faceless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really I’m talking about the event that I was faced with yesterday. I’m talking about banking. Hold on. Didn’t I just say I like the convenience of using a cash machine? Well yes I did. But I’m talking about banking in the terms of going to the bank to pay money into my account. Yesterday I was met with queues of people all waiting to do some form of banking. Now on a saturday this is probably pretty expected. Except the queues weren’t for the counter, they were for machines, the counters were all closed. I promptly turned round and walked out. I’ll go to the bank in my lunch hour when I can pay my money into my account with a person at the counter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess my point is this. There are somethings which shouldn’t be faceless, paying in money to the bank being one of them. Why? Because this kind of thing revolves around trust. I like to see the person I hand over my paying in book to type in the digits and stamp my book, I then know my money has been paid in. A machine means I have to do it blind. I don’t get to watch my money being paid in to my account. If anything goes wrong there’s no physical feedback, no proof. There’s no smile and opportunity to ask a question on a whim, and I’m pretty sure it would take longer or the same amount of time to use the machine as it would to see a person. Sometimes it feels like companies are saying lets do this by machine because we can, let’s ignore the interaction that occurs between our customers and employees, it’s all the same end product. Ultimately this can put customers off. I know I won’t be going back to that bank on saturday unless I have too. I’d rather go at a slightly more awkward time to do it face to face, gaining the reassurance of seeing something happen in front of me and not when the machine is emptied and it’s content processed.&lt;/p&gt;

            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid>
                /2008/Faceless
            </guid>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
	</rss>
